<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>NEAR Foundation Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/category/near-foundation/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/category/near-foundation/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 12:38:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>NEAR Foundation Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/category/near-foundation/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Pyth Price Feeds Launch on NEAR Protocol Bringing Equity, Commodities, and Market Data On Chain </title>
		<link>/blog/pyth-price-feeds-launch-on-near-protocol-bringing-equity-commodities-and-market-data-on-chain/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oracles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pyth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pyth Price Feeds]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21126</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Pyth, the largest first-party provider of real-time market data for crypto, equities, FX, and commodities to more than 40 blockchains, …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/pyth-price-feeds-launch-on-near-protocol-bringing-equity-commodities-and-market-data-on-chain/">Pyth Price Feeds Launch on NEAR Protocol Bringing Equity, Commodities, and Market Data On Chain </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Pyth, the largest first-party provider of real-time market data for crypto, equities, FX, and commodities to more than 40 blockchains, has launched on NEAR protocol. Pyth, whose services are used by more than 80 market participants — including Jane Street, CBOE, Binance, OKX, and Bybit — brings high-fidelity, high frequency financial market data to the NEAR blockchain natively for the first time.</p>



<p>Previously, Pyth had deployed its feeds to Aurora, the EVM chain built on NEAR. But today Pyth data feeds are fully compatible with NEAR Protocol.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The announcement is a boon to the burgeoning DeFi ecosystem built on top of NEAR, which stands to benefit from data feeds that update every 300 milliseconds.</p>



<p>While other oracle providers use third-party data providers or relayers, Pyth’s data comes from institutions directly. Additionally, Pyth does not use price triggers to prevent certain prices from being pushed. Pyth uses <a href="https://pyth.network/blog/what-is-confidence">Confidence Intervals </a>to ensure continuous price availability. This new metric allows projects to consume Pyth’s price feeds during the most volatile market conditions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-importance-of-oracles">The Importance of Oracles&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Oracles are an important part of any DeFi ecosystem, since they are the information bridges between blockchains and databases. Although oracles could be built by the developers of DeFi projects, out-of-box, decentralized oracles are helpful for builders to start quickly without losing time and effort creating their own oracles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&#8220;Celebrating a new era of data reliability and trust, Douro Labs is thrilled to announce the seamless integration of Pyth Network with the NEAR blockchain,&#8221; says Abhimanyu Bansal, Head of Partnerships at Douro Labs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&#8220;This strategic partnership empowers developers on NEAR with real-time, accurate data feeds, and as we bridge the gap between the physical and digital worlds this integration propels us towards a future of decentralized applications that are not only secure but also truly informed.&#8221;</p>



<p>Pyth has a robust network that is able to deliver price data even during sizable events. During the LUNA/UST incident in May ‘22, Pyth managed to track the LUNA price very accurately during the UST de-peg, while other networks stopped updating the price, causing inaccurate price data.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In less than a year since Pyth’s launch, the network secured more than $2.0B in total value. Pyth has facilitated over $70 billion in trading volume and received over a million client downloads from passionate developers. Pyth supports 350+ low-latency price feeds across digital assets, equities, ETFs, forex pairs, and commodities.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/pyth-price-feeds-launch-on-near-protocol-bringing-equity-commodities-and-market-data-on-chain/">Pyth Price Feeds Launch on NEAR Protocol Bringing Equity, Commodities, and Market Data On Chain </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meet the 2023 NEARCON IRL Hackathon Winners</title>
		<link>/blog/meet-the-2023-nearcon-irl-hackathon-winners/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON IRL Hackathon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21104</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The wait is over! After a week of intense, dedicated work from the NEARCON hackathon judges, the winners of the …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/meet-the-2023-nearcon-irl-hackathon-winners/">Meet the 2023 NEARCON IRL Hackathon Winners</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The wait is over! After a week of intense, dedicated work from the NEARCON hackathon judges, the winners of the 2023 NEARCON IRL Hackathon have been chosen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For the NEARCON IRL Hackathon, DevHub issued travel stipends to the most experienced hackers from all around the world. From Brazil and Canada to Spain, the UK, and beyond, the best builders traveled to NEARCON to celebrate NEAR’s global ecosystem. Those hackers who choose to stick around and keep building on NEAR will be eligible to apply to NEAR Horizon&#8217;s pre-acceleration program or the accelerator itself.</p>



<p>Without further ado, let’s take a look at the amazing projects that were built on NEAR. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-developers-track-winner-quex">Developers Track Winner: Quex</h2>



<p>Quex is an AI-powered NEAR Grant program treasury. A smart contract can automatically fund a project if a pre-configured ChatGPT concludes that it will satisfy the grant program criteria.</p>



<p>“The idea of a fully autonomous AI-controlled treasury captivated our imagination. We envisioned a system where AI, not humans, would have the sole discretion over the allocation of funds, paving the way for an unbiased and efficient distribution of resources,” wrote Quex developers Dmitry Meshkov (3x) and Alejandro V. Betancourt (Biz Dev, Metapool / Co-founder NEAR Misfits).&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We aim to achieve the fully autonomous and secure DAO — even being the developers of this DAO, we should not be able to fund our own project until we get a ‘funded’ response from AI, and we&#8217;re not able to censor transactions to fund projects good enough from the chosen AI point of view.”</p>



<p><a href="https://devpost.com/software/quex">More details on Quex</a>. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-entrepreneurs-track-winner-clickdapp">Entrepreneurs Track Winner: ClickDapp</h2>



<p>ClickDapp, a B.O.S-powered no-code tool to easily create, customize, and deploy dApps, was the winning project for the NEARCON IRL Hackathon’s Entrepreneurs Track.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“ClickDapp was inspired by how easy it is to start a Web 2 company,” said developers João Veiga, Pedro Destri, and Rafaeldkb Borges. “No-code tooling empowers a set of different players, from devs to PMs, to entrepreneurs, allowing them to create and iterate on their products with zero to no difficulty, low cost, and faster development speeds.”</p>



<p>“ClickDapp is a no-code builder connected to the Near BOS library, giving devs, PMs and entrepreneurs the superpower of building entire blockchain applications and products without writing a single line of code.”</p>



<p><a href="https://devpost.com/software/click-dapp">More details on ClickDapp</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-creators-track-winner-b4b">Creators Track Winner: B4B&nbsp;</h2>



<p>An influencer-marketing protocol for Near Social Graph, B4B collects on-chain data about channel activity and enables the amplification of new and existing projects in certain NEAR communities.</p>



<p>“We have built a protocol that simplifies searching, analyzing, and managing influencer marketing through Near Social Graph,” said developers Anton Pecherkin, Ann Chuhnina, Gregory Melnikov, and Aleksandr Sokolov. “Additionally, it provides new monetization opportunities for content creators and influencers in the ecosystem.”</p>



<p>“B4B is a Web3-native influencer ad network that connects advertisers with influencers willing to create and publish ads on their channels. The B4B protocol protects advertisers and influencers by escrowing the budget and maintaining a transparent history of ad orders owned by users. During the NEARHACK, we connected the protocol with the Near Social Graph.”</p>



<p><a href="https://devpost.com/software/near-social-b4b">More details on B4B</a></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-regulators-track-winner-proof-of-reputation">Regulators Track Winner: Proof-of-Reputation</h2>



<p>Proof-of-Reputation is a mechanism that enables any user to get a loan using their on-chain activity as collateral and accomplishing the regulator&#8217;s requirement. In other words, it’s a simple, on-chain, and transparent loan protocol for underbanked regions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Small and medium-sized businesses (SMBs) are the backbone of many economies. Still, they often face challenges in accessing loans — this is especially true in underbanked regions, where people may not have access to traditional banking services,” said the developers Luis Daniel Mendez Castellanos, Irving Yair Nava Hernández, and Alan Estrada.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Avoid complicated, bureaucratic, and lengthy loan application processes. All tracking is done on-chain using a Soul Bond Token,” explain the developers. “If necessary, complete anti-money laundering (AML) procedures by completing quests for proof of identity, proof of citizenship, and other requirements provided by third parties. Allow anyone in regions with limited access to banking services to get a loan.”</p>



<p><a href="https://devpost.com/software/proof-of-reputation-score-and-loan-system">More details on Proof-of-Reputation</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Pitch Competition Winner: DeFi Builder</h2>



<p>Using AI, DeFi Builder allows users to effortlessly launch powerful DeFi projects without coding. Its intuitive code-less tools unlock the doors to the next DeFi entrepreneurs on NEAR and Aurora.</p>



<p>“For the NEAR hackathon, we introduced an innovative feature: the AI Smart Contract Generator,” said its developers&nbsp; Ravi Rasadiya, Alexe Spataru, Lorenzo Castagnone, and Daniel Morosan. “Utilizing the latest AI technology —&nbsp;which has been trained and fine-tuned on NEAR Rust smart contracts, JavaScript smart contracts, and Aurora EVM smart contracts —&nbsp;NEARAI can generate a variety of smart contracts tailored to the user&#8217;s specific requests.”</p>



<p>“The platform&#8217;s design focuses on automating complex processes like smart contract deployment, while offering integration across various blockchain networks, thus streamlining the journey from concept to market-ready DeFi project.”</p>



<p><a href="https://devpost.com/software/defi-builder">More details on DeFi Builder</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-main-track-winners">Main Track Winners</h2>



<p>Three winners took home prizes for the NEARCON IRL Hackathon Main Track.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-1st-prize-obrigado">1st Prize — Obrigado</h3>



<p>Obrigado allows seamless execution of heavy computational tasks, distributed across multiple computational resource providers.</p>



<p>“NEAR is aiming to be the OS for an open web with the on-chain frontend (B.O.S) and backend (WASM/zkWASM),” said the developers William S, João Vasco Pestana, Igor Perić, Souheila Sidennas, and Hojay Lee. “The missing piece is a way to process heavy computes such as training a LLM or analyzing DNA data.”</p>



<p>“Obrigado will allow seamless execution of heavy computational tasks, distributed across multiple computational resource providers (Task Runners), ensuring efficient processing and integrity of results, all within NEAR. Computing happens off-chain and book-keeping like job queue handling, result validation, node reputation, slashing and balances happen on-chain.”</p>



<p><a href="https://devpost.com/software/obrigado">More details on Obrigado</a>. </p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-2nd-prize-magic-build">2nd Prize — Magic Build</h3>



<p>Magic Build is a powerful tool designed to streamline the process of generating front-end interfaces for smart contracts on the B.O.S. It will help developers on B.O.S to deploy products faster without coding.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Our B.O.S Composer is a tool that helps create widget connections within the BOS ecosystem. It enables infinite scalability of nested widgets, increasing the depth and resource utilization of a website,” said the developers Hai N and Kuro Denjiro. “With B.O.S Composer, you can create multiple pages, export them as widgets, and then select and link these widgets together.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Magic Build also supports horizontal widget connections through the &#8220;self customize&#8221; section, where you can input the URL of a widget, export it, and import it to establish connections with other widgets. B.O.S Composer simplifies the process of creating widget connections, enabling the creation of intricate and resource-rich web experiences within the B.O.S ecosystem.</p>



<p><a href="https://devpost.com/software/magic-build">More details on Magic Build</a>.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-3rd-prize-web3-plugin">3rd Prize — Web3 Plugin</h3>



<p>A web3.jd plugin for NEAR Protocol and its ecosystem, Web3 Plugin provides the functionality of near-api-js but in the web3.js style.</p>



<p>“Developers who already use web3.js can quickly start working with NEAR technology  with fewer things to read and learn,” said the developer, Muhammad Altabba. “All they need to do is provide the web3.js library with a link to a NEAR provider, add it with the plugin, then they can start working just like they are used to. Even though there will be slight differences that they&#8217;ll have to adjust for, we do our best to reduce them to the minimum.”</p>



<p><a href="https://devpost.com/software/web3-plugin-near">More details on Web3 Plugin</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-thanks-for-joining-the-nearcon-irl-hackathon">Thanks for joining the NEARCON IRL Hackathon</h2>



<p>Thanks to all of the participants who joined the NEARCON ‘23 hackathon! As you can see from the winners, there was no shortage of great, cutting edge projects built on NEAR. The NEAR community and ecosystem are strong and creative because of each and every project like yours.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A big thank you as well to the NEARCON IRL Hackathon judges: Max Zavershynskyi (Leader, NEAR DevHub), Eric Winer (CTO, Pagoda), Alex Shevchenko (CEO, Aurora), Nate Geier (CEO, Mintbase), Laura Cunningham (General Manager, NEAR Horizon), Samantha Bohbot (Chief Growth Officer, RockawayX), Oleg Fomenko (Co-founder, Sweat Economy), Bowen Wang(Head of Protocol, Pagoda), Sandi Fatic (Co-founder, Calimero Network), Joe Spano (Co-Founder, ShardDog), MJ (Head of Product, Proximity Labs), and Diogo Monica (Founder, Anchorage Digital). </p>



<p>The NEAR Foundation and the entire NEAR community looks forward to you participating in the hackathon at NEARCON ‘24! </p>



<p>Keep hacking and building on NEAR.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/meet-the-2023-nearcon-irl-hackathon-winners/">Meet the 2023 NEARCON IRL Hackathon Winners</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Tasks Launches AI Marketplace on NEAR to Revolutionize the Future of Work</title>
		<link>/blog/near-tasks-launches-ai-marketplace-on-near-to-revolutionize-the-future-of-work/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21096</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The convergence of AI and Web3 captured the tech industry’s imagination in 2023 — but few ideas have actually become …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-tasks-launches-ai-marketplace-on-near-to-revolutionize-the-future-of-work/">NEAR Tasks Launches AI Marketplace on NEAR to Revolutionize the Future of Work</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The convergence of AI and Web3 captured the tech industry’s imagination in 2023 — but few ideas have actually become a working reality. An exciting exception is NEAR Tasks, a global gigs marketplace poised to reshape AI training while leveraging the power of NEAR blockchain. Officially launched at NEARCON 2023 with its first product beta launching this week, NEAR Tasks is a self-service platform where anyone can easily list and complete AI requests, setting a new standard for quality data labeling.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-unlocking-the-power-of-ai-and-web3"><strong>Unlocking the Power of AI and Web3</strong></h2>



<p>NEAR Tasks envisions a future where AI and Web3 technologies complement each other, fostering an ecosystem driven by transparency and efficiency. This symbiotic relationship aims to streamline task matching, review processes, and manage data quality more effectively at scale.</p>



<p>Implemented on the NEAR Protocol, NEAR Tasks utilizes on-chain tasker IDs, smart contracts for automated payments, and $NEAR transactions for global payments with minimal fees. This ensures accountability, motivates high-quality outcomes, and addresses the challenge of underpaid workers in the AI sector.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>NEAR Tasks in a Nutshell</strong></h2>



<p>In the age of AI, despite popular narratives about LLMs replacing a range of human jobs, human intelligence actually becomes even more important: as models get more complex, they need human expertise for fine-tuning models and increasing subject matter specialization. This user-friendly platform seamlessly connects task listing, work review, and crypto rewards, propelling AI model training into a new era through direct human feedback loops and a flexible self-service marketplace.</p>



<p>For business clients and AI builders, NEAR Tasks provides a self-service, plug-and-play solution, liberating users from the constraints of costly managed service options. Blockchain integration on NEAR facilitates efficient data labeling by verified human experts, who can build reputation and get paid in real time for contributing quality work to the platform.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For taskers, the NEAR Tasks marketplace offers a transparent path to monetizing their skills and knowledge, unlocking new revenue streams in the ever-evolving AI labor frontier, and changing the future of digital work. There are more than a billion participants in the global on-demand gig economy today, showing the need for more opportunities as well as greater specialization for those with particular training or expertise. With more reliable identity verification for accounts, faster work review, and the ability to pay taskers with crypto, taskers can get paid more reliably and work at the pace they wish — making the gig economy more supportive to specialized workers. </p>



<p>In his introduction to NEAR Tasks at NEARCON in Lisbon, Senior Engineer Momo Araki pointed out: “There’s an interdependence for the system to work properly. You have to reform the central inspection principle wielded by task providers, and maintain sybil-resistance so workers can’t spoof the platform. It’s loosely analogous to a ‘proof-of-work’ model, where work performed well also translates to earning reputation, which leads to accessing further opportunities.&#8221; Incorporating more trust into a tasks marketplace in this way also produces better results for the AI builders and businesses trying to refine their models. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>A Fair and Transparent Platform for AI Training</strong></h2>



<p>In an AI landscape where autonomy often overshadows human involvement, NEAR Tasks recognizes the vital role of a global workforce responsible for data labeling and validation. The platform introduces on-chain digital IDs for taskers, ensuring transparency and accountability.</p>



<p>Transactions exclusively conducted in $NEAR guarantee rapid global payments with minimal fees, directly confronting the issue of underpaid AI workers in what is known in the industry as “AI sweatshops.”</p>



<p>&#8220;Human intelligence forms the base of artificial intelligence, and it&#8217;s time we give AI tasks the recognition they deserve as legitimate jobs in the AI economy,&#8221; says Catherine Yushina, Head of Operations at NEAR Tasks.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>AI Is NEAR</strong></h2>



<p>At NEARCON 2023, NEAR Co-Founder Illia Polosukhin — an AI researcher himself and co-creator of transformers, the architecture powering today’s major LLMs like ChatGPT — named AI as one of the core verticals for the NEAR ecosystem heading into 2024. From transforming governance and business operations with AI agents to provable provenance for data and content, as well as novel marketplaces like NEAR Tasks and hybrid human-AI working environments, we’re at the very beginning of an exciting revolution that will change the ways we work, collaborate, transact, research, and govern ourselves. More news is coming before the end of 2023 to position NEAR as the leader at the intersection of AI and Web3. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Join the AI + Blockchain Movement</strong></h2>



<p>If you want to be part of this transformative AI and blockchain convergence shaping the human intelligence market, sign up for the NEAR Tasks <a href="https://neartasks.ai/neartasks-waitlist">waitlist</a> — currently at more than 48,000 applicants. The marketplace opens for public access in Q1 of 2024. You can also reach out to the team directly to request entry into the current Beta. Drop them an email at <a href="mailto:info@neartasks.ai">info@neartasks.ai</a> to express your interest by Monday, November 20.</p>



<p>For more information about NEAR Tasks, please visit <a href="https://neartasks.ai/">https://neartasks.ai/</a>.</p>



<p>Follow along on social media:</p>



<ul>
<li>Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/near_tasks">https://twitter.com/near_tasks</a>&nbsp;</li>



<li>LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/98907399">https://www.linkedin.com/company/98907399</a>&nbsp;</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-tasks-launches-ai-marketplace-on-near-to-revolutionize-the-future-of-work/">NEAR Tasks Launches AI Marketplace on NEAR to Revolutionize the Future of Work</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEARCON &#8217;23 Unwrapped: Lisbon Steps into the Open Web in Iconic Fashion</title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-23-unwrapped-lisbon-steps-into-the-open-web-in-iconic-fashion/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI is NEAR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EigenLayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR DA Layer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON ‘23]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21092</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Over the course of three epic days, the NEAR ecosystem showed up and showed out to make NEARCON ‘23 the …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-unwrapped-lisbon-steps-into-the-open-web-in-iconic-fashion/">NEARCON &#8217;23 Unwrapped: Lisbon Steps into the Open Web in Iconic Fashion</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Over the course of three epic days, the NEAR ecosystem showed up and showed out to make NEARCON ‘23 the most iconic edition yet. Groundbreaking partnerships were announced, new bonds forged, and a new vision for AI and the open web was unveiled by some of the brightest minds in the blockchain business.</p>



<p>“The open web is an internet where all people control their own assets, data, and power of governance,” remarked NEAR co-founder and newly minted CEO of NEAR Foundation, Illia Polosukhin, on Day One of NEARCON ‘23. “And that vision extends beyond NEAR to the entire space, with the B.O.S. acting as the single entry point to an open web.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Illia’s remarks truly encapsulated the spirit of NEARCON ‘23, as innovative collaborations with the likes of Polygon and <a href="https://near.org/blog/near-foundation-and-eigen-labs-partner-to-enable-faster-cheaper-web3-transactions-for-ethereum-rollups-via-eigenlayer/">EigenLayer</a> highlighted a cross-chain, multi-ecosystem future with NEAR enabling multiple key facets of tomorrow’s truly open web.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So ICYMI, here’s all the key happenings, hubbub, and highpoints of an iconic NEARCON ‘23.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-partnerships-irl-hackathon-and-ncon-make-a-splash">Partnerships, IRL Hackathon, and NCON make a splash</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/jog58Foi9eK8yb0kt8LNLgFBKjQo_cXMxmxeUn3ZDPFEgvNaQ3RjVnw-i9AOrKpa3Q3sv70HDA9Lzn2vAUWN6A-tq6S3obNwg_Z9f2B1VciUCWNlOXK3rCbWJWWvJ34ZYED5WJoRY0-jqiwdYVoFvw4TqHGsmsGHgU_7zO3Z0mLfjeS8dQmWII645drzXw" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Things started off with a bang before the doors of the Convento Do Beato in Lisbon even opened, with the debut of the NCON token. The first ever native NEARCON token, attendees could download the NEARCON app and collect NCON tokens by completing tasks, bounties, and viewing sessions throughout the event.</p>



<p>NEARCON-goers could then redeem NCON tokens for swag or a bite from the various food trucks, or even send NCON to other attendees via a slick native wallet on the NEARCON app. All told, <a href="https://twitter.com/openwebdata/status/1723463055542300696">over 110,000 NCON tokens</a> were distributed during the event, making it a smash hit amongst attendees.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/WvxgD6nadaErgWpYzZLpHKMJmLXrxWA9r4riyOV_wywtPrBLCKEjhiCASWjAGFVk2C0twfjs8macMcr029Hawm0N7ftUrsbkZdJVC6QGF5L-IIottIQlp3Bcgtmrbkk5LBknm0cqxwUVfkhSA-sG8D5ptvFsZWqC-tC8Ava6daCzCYDQdhS1X3JdniIBCA" alt=""/></figure>



<p>This year’s NEARCON also took place across three cool and contrasting venues: NEARCON HQ, Hacker HQ, and Community HQ, each providing a unique experience for those of varying interests. HackerHQ was popping in particular due to the three day IRL Hackathon. Held in a stunning seaview venue, the winners will be announced next week, so stay tuned.</p>



<p>Once everyone settled in for Day One, the ecosystem was treated to a few major game-changing partnership announcements. Here’s a roundup of the major collabs that are already making an impact for NEAR builders, developers, and the community at large:</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-releases-the-data-availability-layer-for-eth-rollups-and-ethereum-developers">NEAR releases the Data Availability Layer for ETH Rollups and Ethereum developers</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Introducing the NEAR Data Availability Layer" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/U1IfP435Aow?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>By far the biggest news of Day One was NEAR <a href="/blog/near-foundation-launches-near-da-to-offer-secure-cost-effective-data-availability-for-eth-rollups-and-ethereum-developers/?_gl=1%2Ak9zc45%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTA3NDE2NTgxOS4xNzAwMDM4OTU2%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTcwMDAzODk1Mi4xLjAuMTcwMDAzODk1Mi4wLjAuMA..">unveiling the NEAR Data Availability Layer (NEAR DA)</a>, offering robust, low-cost blockchain data to developers for modular open web development. NEAR DA will help developers reduce costs and enhance the reliability of rollups, while keeping the security of Ethereum. NEAR DA is a key part of tomorrow&#8217;s open web development stack, with early users including StarkNet, Caldera, Movement Labs, and others.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-x-eigenlayer-streamline-ethereum">NEAR x EigenLayer streamline Ethereum</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/4Ir5U6Ej7UgAKATGtl2k3GEBZxcx9Ijetal173PU1eM2MQpV9C_wCj5DBt6rhWx_rSg4JqZiTXTnQq2RiEECZ8USbNkOtFoHifoVPn4xB6_-71Mb5mALQD6BXhP30NLTWR6hEBziROAg3v8hNnAU_1-Hpfk5TSJZz2kqhxDgMJLq2uYTOVDzML8G5MIKzQ" alt=""/></figure>



<p>NEAR Foundation announced its <a href="/blog/near-foundation-and-eigen-labs-partner-to-enable-faster-cheaper-web3-transactions-for-ethereum-rollups-via-eigenlayer/?_gl=1%2Abb1vlz%2A_up%2AMQ..%2A_ga%2AMTA3NDE2NTgxOS4xNzAwMDM4OTU2%2A_ga_9GWCXQJ62J%2AMTcwMDAzODk1Mi4xLjAuMTcwMDAzODk1Mi4wLjAuMA..">partnership with EigenLayer</a>, which will speed&nbsp; up transaction times and slashing costs on the Ethereum blockchain. The collaboration will introduce a fast finality layer to Ethereum rollups, boosting their efficiency and scalability. The fast finality layer showcases the strengths of NEAR’s technology while making the open web more usable.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-layerzero-brings-interoperability-to-near">LayerZero brings interoperability to NEAR</h3>



<p>In other big news, <a href="https://x.com/NEARProtocol/status/1722936951358034312?s=20">LayerZero integrated with NEAR</a>, bringing over 40 blockchain networks into the open web. Layer brings trustless cross-chain messaging into the fold, making NEAR a more versatile ecosystem. The announcement highlighted NEAR&#8217;s commitment to seamless communication across various blockchain networks.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-day-one-highlights-bringing-the-open-web-vision-to-life">Day One highlights: bringing the open web vision to life</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/5fAa-iF11u_bBT0EJBugPswSRTK_DHm7ECm7cLCVfEtmDtoBIKN52uxtmdhoe_GQWmkP_-C--T3SEtp73OayIz1dZSIvSDAxHDNc7A0K7dDW4PgJvug3KvDxbqfJYvTig2bTg8vOTiEQPClSJnYvUzBugacwlUJR3dqVTxWSNeymjYjJORlvPHGfL7s1ZA" alt=""/></figure>



<p>While there were a ton of amazing sessions and panels on the first day — from open web gaming and sports to crypto economics — one of the major themes was how Illia would realize his vision for a truly open internet in his new role as CEO of the NEAR Foundation. With a renewed focus on developers in the ecosystem, it only makes sense for him to steer the ship.</p>



<p>Piggybacking on Illia’s “NEAR: The Open Web Vision” keynote, new NEAR COO Chris Donovan made a case for the open web, while also sitting down to discuss Web3 regulatory issues with Coindesk’s Michael Casey. And in other developer tooling news, NEAR Data Availability (DA) was announced, giving developers low-cost access to modular, scalable blockchain data.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-day-two-highlights-the-ai-is-near-track-takes-flight">Day Two highlights: the AI is NEAR track takes flight</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/Fliv3gNu9eojFeS2QCYlbxHaSRLWEofADptXojnQOVMHb-JBTXZ1Euxfz-QByKYir75UtWSqIzzfAmYBVCz8SJzl1r4_iZIjsbIyKdlMAayDnzJeRmDv9_8vSDsp7oEdKXy81iSLX9w60C_9o6dPWOz7barT9gxfu1I1w5_tGkAJz-kHi132RK710vzz-w" alt=""/></figure>



<p>The second day of NEARCON ‘23 was perhaps the boldest to date, with an epic “AI is NEAR” speaker and programming track that was simply mind blowing. Things kicked off with sessions featuring thought leaders from the likes of Pantera Capital and NEAR Tasks, and heated up even more with NEAR co-founder Alex Skidanov’s talk on generative AI and the open web.</p>



<p>Illia returned in the afternoon to discuss “AI on NEAR: The Future of Work and Governance,” painting a picture of how AI will impact the future of governance, work, asset ownership, and beyond. He was then joined by Mike Butcher of TechCrunch, with the two unpacking the intersection of AI, blockchain, and global policy.</p>



<p>“AI has the potential to be a huge driver for productivity,” Illia explained. “AI agents, for example,&nbsp; are redefining the future of work. They have the unique ability to manage transactions and resources on blockchain platforms, communicate with secure cryptographic verification, and act as autonomous entities on people’s behalf — and directly for their benefit.”</p>



<p>The AI is NEAR track was capped off when Illia then joined Michael Casey for a Coindesk podcast, where the two dove as deep as one can imagine down the AI rabbit hole. In particular, Illia shared his experience, views, and predictions regarding AI, blockchain, and the open web – simply a must listen. (Stay tuned for the release of this Coindesk podcast with Illia and Michael.)</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-day-three-highlights-governance-and-hackathon-on-stage">Day Three highlights: governance and hackathon on stage</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/YMVF0QoG2ZetU2RDLt_nolNdY7zpPh8xeNNvkvPtQ6I1Nzu_H2G_d0Chx1KTM0lcq2jMJZ3QFkLJDtQccpLP63nyyQBSKBhZ-WX-eED61NbYupTHjHQLk-CxriCdqBFG-cznfPVFtr48Avga7qSbfUgup1_CnSW5EWGSwldn59un6pvdD3rsLgwZv1SnsQ" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Governance and current happenings with the NEAR Digital Collective (NDC) were front and center in a spirited Day Three. One of the most unique panels was the NEAR Governance Forum, featuring AVB from the Transparency Committee, Cameron Dennis from Banyan, and Blaze of Cheddar.</p>



<p>All three gave their takes on what’s gone right — and wrong — with the NDC since its inception at last year’s NEARCON. And in a “Round Robin” format, the three fielded a variety of questions from the audience, some of whom were NDC members themselves. Blaze and AVB then joined NEAR’s Yadira Blocker in an afternoon session discussing Decentralized Democracy in 2024.</p>



<p>The final season of NEARCON ‘23 featured presentations from the IRL Hackathon, where builders unveiled their work and ideas. Judges and panelists included Oleg Fomenko, CEO of Sweat Economy, with talented NEAR builders putting their best foot forward. They showcased some truly amazing ideas and tech, so you’ll want to keep your eyes peeled for the winners.</p>



<p>And what’s Day Three of any NEARCON without a party? This year’s bash was held at the LX Factory, an enormous space where all attendees got their final chance to network, share ideas, and have a blast. The Littles sponsored the party, bringing an added element of excitement by setting up carnival games at the venue along with The Fun Pass to reward anyone who played.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-nearcon-23-as-iconic-as-it-gets">NEARCON ‘23: as iconic as it gets</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/yYY2_yr7Zg7pzkHX3fpfsykRtcnXSlKZR-RcTXw4pTzfPnkfR2PH3_xaIqGFPjDkpcm3bN5fG4LVBV9qP20QVuu63SlCyQnZynqNuCq8uNwY7CNGhb4d8bld1DPMvw6XibIBsHe0dYz9MuQSj7_m5ZEmgAPe_Wu5hWpGxg5M2j0ohXt96G9c-j2smCf55w" alt=""/></figure>



<p>If you joined us in Lisbon, a huge thanks for making this year’s edition so fun, spectacular, and rewarding. If you weren’t able to attend, we sincerely hope to see you next year. From transformative partnerships to leading the Web3 pack in AI, NEARCON ‘23 showcased the passion, momentum, and ingenuity of the entire NEAR ecosystem.<br><br>If you weren’t able to make it to Lisbon for NEARCON, don’t worry —&nbsp;you can still check out all of the talks. Visit <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@NEARProtocol/videos">NEAR Protocol’s YouTube page</a> for the full livestreams from the Layer 1 and Layer 2 stages, or click the links below.&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>NEARCON Day One Livestream</strong>&nbsp; – <a href="https://youtu.be/Cj2PpoZW47g?feature=shared">Layer 1 Stage</a>, <a href="https://youtu.be/6vMidjsnXjM?feature=shared">Layer 2 Stage</a></li>



<li><strong>NEARCON Day Two Livestream</strong> – <a href="https://youtu.be/gYhNjSQ1uVs?feature=shared">Layer 1 Stage</a>, <a href="https://youtu.be/uIMWHcMuzj8?feature=shared">Layer 2 Stage</a></li>



<li><strong>NEARCON Day Three Livestream</strong>&nbsp; – <a href="https://youtu.be/nsnit6wKIUU?feature=shared">Layer 1 Stage</a>, <a href="https://youtu.be/ghb5mxFQoOs?feature=shared">Layer 2 Stage</a></li>
</ul>



<p>Anyone who built furiously at the HackerHQ or clinked a cocktail at the Glass Movers &amp; Shakers Happy Hour will likely tell you something similar: that NEARCON ‘23 showed the importance of a truly open web — and how together we can all achieve it.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-unwrapped-lisbon-steps-into-the-open-web-in-iconic-fashion/">NEARCON &#8217;23 Unwrapped: Lisbon Steps into the Open Web in Iconic Fashion</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEARCON ‘23 Day Three: Governance and Multi-Chain in the Spotlight</title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-23-day-three-governance-and-multi-chain-in-the-spotlight/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 16:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21089</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As NEARCON &#8217;23 drew to a close, the vibrant energy of innovation and unity in the open web was palpable. …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-day-three-governance-and-multi-chain-in-the-spotlight/">NEARCON ‘23 Day Three: Governance and Multi-Chain in the Spotlight</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As NEARCON &#8217;23 drew to a close, the vibrant energy of innovation and unity in the open web was palpable. Attendees reflected on a journey filled with groundbreaking discussions and pivotal connections, marking the final day as a celebration of collective progress and shared visions for the future.</p>



<p>The conference&#8217;s last act spotlighted transformative dialogues and educational strides, with a keen focus on empowering the next wave of builders. Governance talks, innovative partnerships, and technical milestones underscored NEAR&#8217;s commitment to nurturing talent and fostering a future where the open web thrives.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-major-eigenlayer-and-layerzero-announcements">Major EigenLayer and LayerZero announcements</h2>



<p>Day Three was headlined by two major announcements that will impact the NEAR Protocol and ecosystem in a variety of ways moving forward.</p>



<p><strong>NEAR and EigenLayer enable fast finality on Ethereum&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>NEAR Foundation <a href="https://near.org/blog/near-foundation-and-eigen-labs-partner-to-enable-faster-cheaper-web3-transactions-for-ethereum-rollups-via-eigenlayer/">partners with Eigen Labs</a> to develop a &#8220;fast finality layer&#8221; for Ethereum rollups, promising swift and economical transactions. This initiative, set for a 2024 testnet launch, aims to quicken cross-rollup communication and minimize costs, streamlining the developer experience and enhancing Web3 interoperability.</p>



<p><strong>LayerZero integrates with NEAR for cross-chain messaging</strong></p>



<p>A second big announcement was the integration with LayerZero Labs on NEAR’s EVM layer, Aurora, enabling NEAR to connect with over 40 blockchain networks. LayerZero&#8217;s endpoint paves the way for trustless cross-chain messaging, expanding NEAR&#8217;s interoperability and user experience. For further details, visit LayerZero&#8217;s documentation <a href="https://layerzero.gitbook.io/docs/">here</a><strong>.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-day-three-ecosystem-news-and-announcements">Day Three ecosystem news and announcements</h2>



<p>EigenLayer and LayerZero were just the tip of the iceberg for the ecosystem on Day Three. Here’s a rundown of other key happenings.</p>



<p><strong>​​Activelink boosted by NEAR grant</strong></p>



<p>Activelink, enhancing sports and media engagement, has received a NEAR Foundation grant to facilitate on-chain transactions, fostering direct fan connections and monetization on the NEAR protocol.</p>



<p><strong>Ample kicks off Horizon program</strong></p>



<p>Ample, readying to disrupt media distribution, leverages the Horizon Programme to launch a unique platform for artists. It aims to democratize entertainment by tokenizing content, ensuring creators&#8217; ownership, and optimizing monetization without requiring open web expertise.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Encode: Kickstarting NEAR Innovations</strong></p>



<p>Encode teams up with NEAR Horizon for an eight-week online accelerator, starting November 23rd including workshops, mentorship, and global networking opportunities. Open to unfunded hackathon and startup projects, it’s a launchpad to growth without full-time commitment. Check out the <a href="https://www.encode.club/encode-near-horizon-accelerator">Encode accelerator website</a> to learn more and <a href="https://encodeclub.typeform.com/near2023acc#source=ncn">fill out an application</a> today.</p>



<p><strong>QSTN: NFT Success and Testnet Launch</strong></p>



<p>QSTN announced a full sell-out of their NFT collection on NEAR, gearing up for their public incentivized testnet on November 13th. QSTN is calling on the open community to engage and earn NEAR rewards for survey participation and feedback with Telegram integration plans.</p>



<p><strong>World of Rogues brings mobile adventure to NEAR</strong></p>



<p>World of Rogues is set to conquer mobile gaming, with Rogues Studio announcing a forthcoming release for iOS and Android. Emphasizing a seamless, frictionless blockchain gaming experience on NEAR, the studio focuses on easy onboarding for non-crypto gamers.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Lava Network bolsters NEAR with modular APIs</strong></p>



<p>The Lava Network is boosting the NEAR ecosystem through a partnership aimed at enhancing developer tools with modular APIs and incentivized public RPCs. By integrating NEAR support, Lava provides developers with a robust node network, ensuring speed and efficiency.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Encore Network empowers NEAR with user-centric data</strong></p>



<p>Encore, a leading data collection platform, announced a huge step in data control. NEAR users now control their data along with terms of sharing. The goal is to slash customer acquisition costs for projects and spur revenue, marking a new chapter in data-driven user empowerment.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-key-sessions-and-panels">Key sessions and panels</h2>



<p>The final day of NEARCON ‘23 highlighted governance, along with a special session between NEAR co-founder and CEO Illia Polosukhin and Polygon co-founder Jordy Baylina.</p>



<p><strong>NEAR Governance Forum: shaping decentralized democracy</strong></p>



<p>At the NEAR Governance Forum, leaders like Blaze from Cheddar and Alejandro Betancourt of the Transparency Commission discussed challenges in the NDC, emphasizing the need for high standards and community-driven progress. Topics included efficient governance models, the balance between autonomy and collaboration, and advancing NEAR&#8217;s decentralized democracy.</p>



<p><strong>Illia dives deeper into Polygon and ZK with Jordi Baylina</strong></p>



<p>NEAR&#8217;s Illia Polosukhin, alongside Polygon co-founder Jordi Baylina, dove into the collaboration between the two ecosystems. The two focused on zero-knowledge proofs for enhancing cross-chain interactions and unifying blockchain security. They talked about streamlining Layer 1 and Layer 2 operations, promoting a cohesive and interoperable blockchain network, and more.</p>



<p><strong>Envisioning the future of decentralized democracy&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>During &#8220;What 2024 Looks Like for Decentralized Democracy&#8221; Blaze and Alejandro returned along with Yadira Blocker from the NEAR Foundation to break down cultural and operational shifts needed for effective governance, touching on the role of AI in streamlining decision-making processes. They also discussed the NDC’s past, present, and future.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-littles-bash-at-lx-factory-closes-out-nearcon-23">The Littles bash at LX Factory closes out NEARCON ‘23</h2>



<p>Day Three will culminate in a huge bash at <a href="https://lxfactory.com/en/map/">LX Factory</a>, sponsored by The Littles. Unwind and network against the backdrop of one of Lisbon&#8217;s most vibrant and hip nightlife districts. The closing party not only marks the end of an iconic NEARCON ‘23, but will be fertile ground for future collaborations and community bonding.</p>



<p>Not to mention a chance to win rewards and NFTs just by playing carnival games via The Littles Fun Pass app on NEAR. Win or lose, you’ll walk away with some cool blockchain-based swag.</p>



<p>As NEARCON &#8217;23 wraps up, the collaborative spirit of the open web community is clear. The convergence of thought leaders, innovators, and enthusiasts in Lisbon made this year’s edition incredibly special. Thanks to every attendee, hacker, sponsor, and NEAR enthusiast for making NEARCON ‘23 so memorable, and see you at the LX Factory at 9 PM for the grand finale!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-day-three-governance-and-multi-chain-in-the-spotlight/">NEARCON ‘23 Day Three: Governance and Multi-Chain in the Spotlight</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Foundation and Eigen Labs Partner to Enable Faster, Cheaper Web3 Transactions for Ethereum Rollups via EigenLayer</title>
		<link>/blog/near-foundation-and-eigen-labs-partner-to-enable-faster-cheaper-web3-transactions-for-ethereum-rollups-via-eigenlayer/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eigen Labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[EigenLayer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21085</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>EigenLabs, one of the leaders in building scaling solutions on Ethereum, is partnering with the NEAR Foundation to create an …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-and-eigen-labs-partner-to-enable-faster-cheaper-web3-transactions-for-ethereum-rollups-via-eigenlayer/">NEAR Foundation and Eigen Labs Partner to Enable Faster, Cheaper Web3 Transactions for Ethereum Rollups via EigenLayer</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://www.eigenlayer.xyz/about">EigenLabs</a>, one of the leaders in building scaling solutions on Ethereum, is partnering with the NEAR Foundation to create an industry first partnership designed to foster faster, cheaper transactions for Layer 2 projects building on Ethereum.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ethereum rollups, projects that perform transaction execution outside of the main Ethereum blockchain, have been one of the fastest growing sectors on the world’s largest blockchain. However, they have consistently faced challenges around finality and cost, making them an expensive option for developers looking to build on Ethereum. With the partnership with the NEAR Blockchain and NEAR Foundation, those roadblocks disappear.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-world-s-first-fast-finality-layer-for-ethereum-layer-2s">The world’s first ‘fast finality layer’ for Ethereum layer 2s</h2>



<p>The partnership, which will have the two teams build the world’s first “fast finality layer” for Ethereum layer 2s, will see transaction times shrink from minutes and hours to 3-4 seconds. The cost of transacting on this new finality layer will become 4,000 times cheaper than it is currently, creating the perfect conditions for teams looking to scale on Ethereum.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This advancement will reduce liquidity fragmentation between Layer-2s through increased efficiency while also allowing them to make individual decisions around the sequencers they use to process those transactions, either on-chain or off-chain. The fast finality layer retains all Ethereum security guarantees while adding both NEAR and EigenLayer guarantees, making it an attractive option for any team building on Ethereum L2s.</p>



<p>“We are thrilled to partner with the highly innovative team behind the NEAR protocol,” says Sreeram Kannan, founder of EigenLabs. “This is a mutually beneficial partnership that will leverage both NEAR and EigenLayer’s technologies to make it easier, faster, and cheaper for developers to build on Ethereum.”</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-making-the-open-web-more-usable">Making the Open Web more usable&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The collaboration, spearheaded by <a href="https://www.pagoda.co/">Pagoda</a>, the NEAR ecosystem development team, will help transition the NEAR-Ethereum Rainbow Bridge to an actively validated service (AVS).&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Pagoda is proud to work with Eigen Labs, a world-class team, to cobuild the fast finality layer. This solution improves the composability with Ethereum L2s and reduces liquidity fragmentation within the rollup ecosystem,&#8221; says Bowen Wang, Director of Protocol at Pagoda.</p>



<p>The partnership will not only help projects building on Ethereum, but NEAR too, create a better bridging experience between NEAR and Ethereum, allowing transactions to reach finality faster, with stronger security guarantees and decentralization.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“NEAR Foundation is proud to partner with such an excellent team as Eigen Labs to offer a fast finality layer for ETH rollups,” says Illia Polosukhin, co-founder of NEAR Protocol.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The fast finality layer showcases the strengths of NEAR’s technology while making the Open Web more usable, which has always been the core goal for NEAR. It will also help defragment liquidity for Ethereum rollups and make all of Web3 more interoperable as a result.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The NEAR Foundation’s mission is to help usher in the dawn of the open web, a radically new form of Web3 where infrastructure, application protocols, and access is open to anyone, anywhere. Facilitating the development of Ethereum by creating a pathway to fast, low-cost, and scalable infrastructure is one the many ways NEAR is helping bring about this radical shift in how the internet works.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A testnet is expected to launch in Q1 2024, and more details will be shared around that time.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-foundation-and-eigen-labs-partner-to-enable-faster-cheaper-web3-transactions-for-ethereum-rollups-via-eigenlayer/">NEAR Foundation and Eigen Labs Partner to Enable Faster, Cheaper Web3 Transactions for Ethereum Rollups via EigenLayer</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEARCON ‘23 Day Three: Shaping the Future of Decentralized Governance </title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-23-day-three-shaping-the-future-of-decentralized-governance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 08:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 23]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21078</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEARCON &#8217;23&#8217;s grand finale is here, packed with groundbreaking sessions you won&#8217;t want to miss. It&#8217;s been a great ride …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-day-three-shaping-the-future-of-decentralized-governance/">NEARCON ‘23 Day Three: Shaping the Future of Decentralized Governance </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEARCON &#8217;23&#8217;s grand finale is here, packed with groundbreaking sessions you won&#8217;t want to miss. It&#8217;s been a great ride so far, with engaging sessions, a mind-blowing hackathon, and the chance to network in person with open web experts from all over the globe. Today’s agenda has some of the most impactful talks yet, so get ready to send NEARCON ‘23 out with a bang!</p>



<p>Start with a coffee at 9:00 AM and enjoy breakfast at the venue with other attendees before diving into our final day of immersive sessions. By 10:45 AM, the curtain will lift on the main stage for NEARCON 23’s final foray into Web3 — including a special, surprise announcement from NEAR CEO Illia Polosukhin.<br>Remember, you can stay connected throughout the day on Calimero Chat  — a private, decentralized comms built on the NEAR blockchain.<br><em>*Note: There is no bag check or cloak room at any NEARCON venue</em>. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-can-t-miss-sessions-on-day-three">Can’t miss sessions on Day Three</h2>



<p><strong>What 2024 Looks Like for Decentralized Democracy</strong> (1:00 PM &#8211; 1:30 PM, Layer 1 Stage).</p>



<p>Join us for a deep dive into the future of governance on NEAR, where the visionaries behind NEAR&#8217;s political framework dissect past triumphs and unfold the master plan for 2024. Hear from our panelists, including Joe Spano of ShardDog and Blaze from Cheddar.</p>



<p><strong>Special Announcement </strong>(12:00 PM &#8211; 12:30 PM, Layer 1 Stage). Don’t miss NEAR Co-founder and NEAR Foundation CEO Illia Polosukhin’s major announcement. When Illia speaks, the entire Web3 world listens, so grab a quick bite and head on over to the main stage for what’s sure to be Illia’s mic-drop moment of NEARCON ‘23.</p>



<p><strong>NEAR Governance Forum</strong> (11:05 AM &#8211; 12:00 PM, Layer 2 Stage). Curious about NEAR’s decentralized governance model? Get your questions answered by Alejandro Betancourt of the Transparency Commission and Cameron Dennis of Banyan Collective, with the conversation facilitated by Gus Friis of NEARWEEK.</p>



<p><strong>NEAR Campus: Unleashing the Potential of University Partnerships for DevHub </strong>(11:00 AM &#8211; 11:20 AM). NEAR DevHub’s Boris Polania will showcase the NEAR Campus&#8217;s role in revolutionizing developer engagement. Explore the relationship between NEAR and academia, and how NEAR Campus will serve as a touchpoint for global campuses in the future.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-sensational-speaker-highlights">Sensational speaker highlights</h2>



<p><strong>Unveiling the Web3 BUILD Incubator Fellowship</strong> (11:20 AM &#8211; 11:30 AM, Block Zero Stage)</p>



<p>Max Mizzi from Major League Hacking will introduce the BUILD Incubator Fellowship, an innovative collaboration with NEAR Horizon. Discover the inception, operation, and success stories of the program&#8217;s trailblazing summer cohort.</p>



<p><strong>It&#8217;s Honest Work: How DeFi Is Growing Up </strong>(11:30 AM &#8211; 12:00 PM, Layer 1 Stage),</p>



<p>From ‘DeFi Summer’ to today, decentralized finance remains one of the most promising areas of crypto — and it’s inevitably maturing. Drop by as an incredible panel included Arjun Arora from Orderly Network, Mike Cahill of Douro Labs, and more chart recent developments that are reshaping DeFi&#8217;s landscape on NEAR and beyond.</p>



<p><strong>Aurora Unleashed: Igniting NEAR&#8217;s Potential </strong>(11:15 AM &#8211; 11:30 AM, Layer 1 Stage).</p>



<p>Alex Shevchenko of Aurora Labs takes the spotlight to discuss Aurora&#8217;s impactful innovations within the NEAR ecosystem. Expect insights into Aurora’s network developments, Borealis infrastructure, and their cross-contract call SDK, all of which amplify NEAR&#8217;s technological prowess.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-irl-hackathon-grand-finale-and-lx-factory-party">IRL Hackathon grand finale and LX Factory party</h2>



<p>Judgment day is finally here, as winners of the IRL Hackathon will claim their awards on the Main Stage from 2:35 PM &#8211; 3:50 PM. Huge thanks to all who participated and submitted projects. Every hacker, coder, builder, and developer is what makes the NEAR ecosystem special and the NEAR Foundation looks forward to engaging each and every one in the future.</p>



<p>Finally, NEARCON ‘23 is going out with a major bang at one of the most iconic Lisbon party venues — LX Factory. An epic bash brought to you by The Littles, it’s a going away soiree that every NEARCON ‘23 attendee simply can’t miss. Grab a drink, do some networking, and groove your night away as NEARCON ‘23 sails off into the Portuguese sunset. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A few important reminders </h2>



<p>Here are today&#8217;s venue hours:</p>



<ul>
<li>Armazem (Hacker HQ) closes at 12:30 PM. </li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li>Garagem (Community HQ) closes at 5:30 immediately after the happy hour. </li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li>Convento Do Beato Layer 2 Stage closes at 12:00 PM. The Layer 1 Stage and venue closes at 4:00 PM. </li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li>Closing party at LX Factory (Fábrica) from 9:00 PM &#8211; 4:00 AM. Open to badge holders. </li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-shoutout-to-day-three-sponsors">Shoutout to Day Three sponsors</h2>



<p>Of course, this epic Day Three wouldn’t be possible without the support of todays’ generous and amazing sponsors:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>The Littles</strong></li>



<li><strong>SailGP</strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Day Three will be all about forging connections, gaining insights, and celebrating all that you and the collective NEAR ecosystem has accomplished not only over the past three days – but the entirety of 2023. So grab a coffee, head on over to the venue, and let’s make the final day of NEARCON ‘23 count towards making this the most iconic edition ever.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-day-three-shaping-the-future-of-decentralized-governance/">NEARCON ‘23 Day Three: Shaping the Future of Decentralized Governance </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEARCON ‘23 Day 2 Roundup: Web3&#8217;s Women Shine and Innovations Unfold</title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-23-day-2-roundup-web3s-women-shine-and-innovations-unfold/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 17:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEARCON 23]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21075</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As the Lisbon sun dipped below the horizon, NEARCON ‘23&#8217;s second day came to a vibrant conclusion. The day was …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-day-2-roundup-web3s-women-shine-and-innovations-unfold/">NEARCON ‘23 Day 2 Roundup: Web3&#8217;s Women Shine and Innovations Unfold</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As the Lisbon sun dipped below the horizon, NEARCON ‘23&#8217;s second day came to a vibrant conclusion. The day was marked by a rich tapestry of dialogue and discovery, highlighting the profound impact of women in Web3 and the AI is NEAR track. The energy was palpable as attendees navigated through a day steeped in collaborative exploration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Key announcements from Pyth Network and breakthroughs in identity solutions with idOS and Tangem Wallet underscored a day where the future of blockchain was not just imagined, but actively constructed.</p>



<p>Remember, you can stay connected with other attendees through Calimero Chat — a private, decentralized comms built on the NEAR blockchain.</p>



<p><em>*Note: There is no bag check or cloak room at any NEARCON venue</em>. </p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-female-open-web-trailblazers-kick-start-day-two">Female open web trailblazers kick start Day Two</h2>



<p>Day 2 of NEARCON ‘23’s celebrated diversity and technical milestones, highlighting transformative initiatives and strategic expansions within the ecosystem.</p>



<p>The &#8220;Women in Web3&#8221; brunch at NEARCON ‘23 spotlighted the vital contributions of women in blockchain, focusing on fostering inclusivity. Leaders in the space convened to discuss strategies for empowering women, emphasizing the NEAR Foundation’s commitment to diversity with initiatives like the Women in Web3 Changemakers list.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ecosystem-highlights-take-center-stage">Ecosystem highlights take center stage</h2>



<p><strong>FractalID unveils idOS on NEAR</strong></p>



<p>FractalID is redefining Web3 identity with the launch of idOS on NEAR, providing users with unparalleled control over their digital identity. This pivotal development promises to enhance user sovereignty and compliance in dApp interactions, bolstering NEAR&#8217;s position as a leader in decentralized identity solutions.</p>



<p><strong>Pyth Network</strong></p>



<p>NEAR&#8217;s integration with the Pyth Network brings a wealth of real-time price feeds to its testnet, significantly enhancing the toolkit available to developers. This move, a year after Pyth&#8217;s Aurora integration, demonstrates NEAR&#8217;s dedication to equipping its platform with the data and tools required for leading-edge dApp development.</p>



<p><strong>Octopus Network restaking and IBC bridge</strong></p>



<p>As part of its Octopus 2.0 program, Octopus Network —&nbsp;built on NEAR Protocol —&nbsp;unveils $NEAR restaking for Ottochain launch in December. This initiative enhances validators&#8217; rewards and bolsters appchain security, incentivizing $NEAR&#8217;s wider use and fostering equilibrium in the NEAR ecosystem.</p>



<p>Octopus Network also introduced Adaptive IBC, bridging Cosmos and NEAR ecosystems for enhanced interoperability with Secret Network poised to be the first adopter.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Tangem Cold Wallet integrates NEAR Protocol</strong></p>



<p>The Tangem Wallet, renowned for its Swiss-made security and simplicity, now fully supports the NEAR Protocol, ensuring effortless self-custody for NEAR holders. This collaboration embodies NEAR&#8217;s commitment to making Web3 accessible, offering users a secure and straightforward way to manage their digital assets with confidence.</p>



<p><strong>Jump DeFi broadens DeFi accessibility on NEAR</strong></p>



<p>Jump DeFi has extended its decentralized finance platform to Telos, making strides toward widespread DeFi adoption. By integrating with NEAR Protocol, Jump DeFi simplifies user and developer engagement, streamlining access to a previously fragmented DeFi ecosystem with its all-in-one solution for core financial activities.</p>



<p><strong>MotoDEX accelerates on NEAR Blockchain</strong></p>



<p>MotoDEX, integrating with the NEAR blockchain, offers a thrilling motorcycle racing game directly on app stores. It caters to 13,000 daily players, blending the thrill of racing with the perks of blockchain tech. The game&#8217;s seamless Web3 integration ensures accessibility for all, fueling a new era of blockchain gaming.</p>



<p><strong>GeekPay rides high on NEAR Blockchain</strong></p>



<p>GeekPay also announced impressive growth with a $1M turnover, a quarter of which was on NEAR. GeekPay simplifies payroll for businesses like theirs. Its recent accolade includes a nod from the Tenity Incubation Program, affirming GeekPay&#8217;s pivotal role in the gig economy and future of work.</p>



<p><strong>DevHub&#8217;s bold new rebrand</strong></p>



<p>DevHub unveiled a fresh brand identity to resonate with its evolution into a thriving NEAR developer ecosystem. This rebranding is more than a visual facelift — it represents DevHub&#8217;s commitment to fostering innovation and supporting builders at every stage. Dive into the enhanced experience at <a href="https://neardevhub.org/">neardevhub.org</a> and join the ranks shaping the Open Web with NEAR.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-key-sessions-and-panels">Key sessions and panels</h2>



<p><strong>SK Telecom ports into the metaverse</strong></p>



<p>Sehyeon Oh from SK Telecom detailed the Korean company’s strategic foray into the open web, highlighting their collaboration with NEAR Foundation and plans for a Web3 wallet and NFT marketplace. SKT&#8217;s approach aims to fuse digital and tangible realms, from art NFTs to metaverse developments while community building with education and blockchain integration.</p>



<p><strong>FractalID unveils idOS on NEAR&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Julian Leitloff from Fractal ID and Johan Salaï Bondioli of Pagoda introduced the idOS at NEARCON ‘23, a leap forward in Web3 identity, granting users control over their digital presence. This initiative is set to redefine the interaction landscape for dApp users, solidifying NEAR&#8217;s leadership in decentralized identity solutions.</p>



<p><strong>NEAR’s evolution from Nightshade to Starsight</strong></p>



<p>Bowen Wang from Pagoda offered a compelling overview of NEAR Protocol&#8217;s evolution, highlighting the advances in stateless validation and zero-knowledge technologies. Wang teased the upcoming Starsight project, promising a leap forward in blockchain&#8217;s usability, scalability, and decentralization in 2024.</p>



<p><strong>Illia Polosukhin on AI&#8217;s Role in NEAR&#8217;s Future</strong></p>



<p>NEAR co-founder and CEO Illia Polosukhin dove into the future of AI and its integration with blockchain. He emphasized AI&#8217;s potential to drive work and governance on NEAR, forecasting AI agents that execute tasks autonomously, enhancing efficiency within decentralized systems and contributing to the evolution of DAOs into truly autonomous organizations.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-side-events-and-networking">Side events and networking</h2>



<p>As Day Two winds down, don’t forget to head on over to the Community HQ for the Movers and Shakers Happy Hour, sponsored by Glass and Moonbounce. Just a few steps down the cobbled Lisbon streets from HackerHQ, Movers and Shakers will be a great chance to sip some cocktails and learn about Glass, an innovative app bringing the adult beverage closer to brand enthusiasts on the NEAR blockchain.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-looking-ahead-to-day-three">Looking ahead to Day Three</h2>



<p>Day Three of NEARCON ‘23 is your final opportunity to dive into immersive open web sessions starting at 10:45 AM, after doors open at 9 AM. The day will highlight the Hackathon&#8217;s brightest innovations with judging from 12:00 PM and the NEAR Pitch Competition and Hackathon Awards Ceremony from 2:35 PM to 3:50 PM on the Main Stage, showcasing top project pitches.</p>



<p>NEARCON ‘23 then goes out with a massive bang at the Closing Party at the LX Factory, sponsored by The Littles. The bash begins at 9:00 PM, and will be a chance for attendees to unwind, network, and reflect on everything that was NEARCON ‘23. Not to mention dancing the night away in one of Lisbon’s most happening party venues.</p>



<p>We hope you had a fantastic Day Two at NEARCON ‘23, with the best yet to come. Enjoy another buzzing evening in Lisbon and see you on Day Three!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-day-2-roundup-web3s-women-shine-and-innovations-unfold/">NEARCON ‘23 Day 2 Roundup: Web3&#8217;s Women Shine and Innovations Unfold</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unlocking the Future of DeFi with the idOS on NEAR: A Developer&#8217;s Guide</title>
		<link>/blog/unlocking-the-future-of-defi-with-the-idos-on-near-a-developers-guide/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[DJ Pangburn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idOS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21069</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the ever-evolving landscape of web3, DeFi has stood apart as a driver of innovation, promising a decentralized financial future. …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/unlocking-the-future-of-defi-with-the-idos-on-near-a-developers-guide/">Unlocking the Future of DeFi with the idOS on NEAR: A Developer&#8217;s Guide</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the ever-evolving landscape of web3, DeFi has stood apart as a driver of innovation, promising a decentralized financial future. But for developers and founders, the challenge has always been integrating real-world applications with the decentralized world, ensuring compliance, and providing a seamless user experience. Enter the idOS on NEAR, a solution — built with Fractal — that bridges this gap and brings the Open Web closer to mainstream adoption.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Why the idOS Matters&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>For developers diving into DeFi, the idOS (Identity Operating System) on NEAR offers a robust framework. It&#8217;s not just about creating decentralized financial applications; it&#8217;s about crafting solutions that can interact with real-world systems, regulations, and meet user expectations.</p>



<p>1. <strong>Composable &amp; Permissionless Integration</strong>: With the idOS, developers can effortlessly combine different protocols that require identity verification, leveraging the &#8220;money legos&#8221; concept. This composability ensures that your DeFi applications can scale and evolve with the ecosystem.</p>



<p>2. <strong>Enhanced User Experience &amp; Identity Verification</strong>: One of the major pain points in the decentralized world is the repetitive identity verification processes, often known as KYC. With the idOS, this process is streamlined. Users verify their identity once, and then, by simply signing with their wallet, they can reuse their verified credentials across any NEAR dApp without undergoing KYC again. This not only enhances user experience but also ensures faster onboarding and interaction with dApps.</p>



<p>3. <strong>Seamless On/Off Ramps</strong>: The idOS facilitates smoother crypto-fiat transactions, a significant pain point in web3 adoption. By integrating the idOS, developers can offer users the ability to easily transition between the decentralized and traditional financial worlds, unlocking use cases like remittances or DeCommerce payments.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Beyond DeFi: Proof-of-Personhood Use Cases</strong></h2>



<p>While DeFi is the cornerstone, the idOS’s potential extends beyond. For founders looking to innovate in areas like decentralized governance or community voting, the idOS provides the tools to ensure proof-of-personhood:</p>



<p>1. <strong>Decentralized Voting</strong>: Governance is a critical aspect of any decentralized protocol. With the idOS, developers can integrate systems where users prove their unique human status, ensuring one person, one vote. This minimizes the influence of bots and whales, leading to fairer governance outcomes.</p>



<p><strong>2. Portable user profiles across Web3</strong>: For platforms that require user profiles like Near.org, the idOS offers a decentralized solution. Users can create and manage their profiles, ensuring data privacy and control. This is especially crucial for platforms that want to offer personalized experiences without compromising on user data sovereignty.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading"><strong>Privacy-Preserving KYC &amp; Compliance</strong></h2>



<p>No developer wants to compromise on user privacy. With the idOS, KYC processes become more user-centric. Users can obtain KYC credentials from multiple providers, with the assurance that their data remains encrypted and under their control. For founders, this means complying with global financial regulations without sacrificing user trust.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Join the revolution with idOS</h2>



<p>For developers and founders ready to shape the future of DeFi and decentralized applications, the idOS on NEAR offers the tools, scalability, and compliance required for success. As we venture into a world where decentralized finance and real-world applications converge, solutions like the idOS will be at the forefront, ensuring that innovation remains uncompromised.</p>



<p>Join the revolution and explore how the <a href="https://idos.network/">idOS</a> can redefine your DeFi applications and enhance user identity verification on NEAR.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/unlocking-the-future-of-defi-with-the-idos-on-near-a-developers-guide/">Unlocking the Future of DeFi with the idOS on NEAR: A Developer&#8217;s Guide</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEARCON ‘23 Day Two Begins: Expand Your Open Web Horizons</title>
		<link>/blog/nearcon-23-day-two-begins-expand-your-open-web-horizons/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The second day of NEARCON 23 is kicking off with an awesome agenda, carrying over the massive momentum from Day …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-day-two-begins-expand-your-open-web-horizons/">NEARCON ‘23 Day Two Begins: Expand Your Open Web Horizons</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The second day of NEARCON 23 is kicking off with an awesome agenda, carrying over the massive momentum from Day One. Doors fling wide open at 9:00 AM for all attendees, so make sure to grab a coffee and a quick breakfast bite before the sessions really get ramped up at 10:45 AM all the way through 5:30 PM.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You won’t want to miss a moment of Day Two, so read on for a complete rundown.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-join-the-morning-brunch-at-community-hq">Join the morning brunch at Community HQ</h2>



<p>This year, we&#8217;re paying tribute to the dynamic women shaping the Web3 ecosystem, and leading a discussion on how to nurture the next generation of top talent. Join us for the Women in Web3 Changemakers breakfast at Community HQ at 8:30 AM. It’s a must attend event for anyone wishing to learn about the challenges and career opportunities available to women — and how to make the World of Web3 brighter for all.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-can-t-miss-sessions-on-day-two">Can’t miss sessions on Day Two</h2>



<p>Day Two at NEARCON ‘23 will dive into the intersection of the open web and traditional industries and explore new developments in digital identity, including a must see fireside chat with NEAR CEO Illia Polosukhin and TechCrunch.</p>



<p><strong>SK Telecom&#8217;s Leap Into Web3</strong> (11:25 AM &#8211; 11:40 AM, Layer 1 Stage): Sehyeon Oh, EVP at SK Telecom, unveils the telecom giant’s Web3 strategy, including an open web wallet and NFT marketplace initiative. Learn about how a traditional industry is collaborating with NEAR to expand the reach of the open web..</p>



<p><strong>AI x Blockchain: Illia Polosukhin and Mike Butcher in Conversation</strong> (3:50 PM &#8211; 4:15 PM, Layer 1 Stage): Join Illia Polosukhin, NEAR co-founder, and Mike Butcher of TechCrunch as they dissect the interplay between AI and Web3, and what the future holds for their convergence.</p>



<p><strong>From Nightshade to Starsight: The Evolution of NEAR Protocol Design</strong> (2:40 PM &#8211; 3:00 PM, Layer 2 Stage): Pagoda&#8217;s Bowen Wang provides insights into NEAR Protocol’s recent advancements and teases upcoming developments regarding protocol design and the next evolution of sharding.</p>



<p><strong>Introducing Decentralized Identity Solutions With the idOS</strong> (1:45 PM &#8211; 2:15 PM, Block Zero Stage): Julian Leitloff explains how the Identity Operating System (idOS) is transforming digital identity, offering users sovereign control over their personal data with their pioneering open-source DID solution.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-more-speaker-highlights">More Speaker Highlights</h2>



<p><strong>Hiring Wisdom for Web3</strong> (11:00 AM &#8211; 11:15 AM, Layer 2 Stage): Dan Eskow, open web recruiter at Up Top, shares invaluable hiring tactics tailored for the dynamic Web3 sector, where finding the right fit is as challenging as it is critical.</p>



<p><strong>Economic Design in Protocols </strong>(11:45 AM &#8211; 12:00 PM, Layer 2 Stage): Lisa JY Tan from Economics Design guides us through the intricacies of creating economically sound and sustainable protocols, offering vital insights for VCs and entrepreneurs.</p>



<p><strong>Bug Bounties and Web3 Security</strong> (3:30 PM &#8211; 3:45 PM, Layer 2 Stage): Mitchell Amador, founder and CEO of Immunefi, narrates the journey to establishing the most substantial bug bounties in the open web.</p>



<p><strong>Strategizing DAO Resource Allocation</strong> (4:25 PM &#8211; 4:40 PM, Layer 2 Stage): Andre Geest of Safe discusses optimizing resource distribution within DAOs, presenting a balanced approach to boost both governance and community engagement.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-founders-forum-and-irl-hackathon">Founders Forum and IRL Hackathon</h2>



<p>For entrepreneurs forging the next wave of open innovation, the Founders Forum at Community HQ is the place to be. Dive into sessions from 11:30 AM to 5:00 PM that dissect critical legal and regulatory aspects for startups, explore the equilibrium between decentralization and compliance, and uncover strategies for assembling a stellar team in the Web3 domain.</p>



<p>Also, a reminder for all Hackathon participants. Finalize your projects by the 5:00 PM deadline and prepare to showcase your open web ingenuity.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-sunset-socializing-and-networking">Sunset socializing and networking</h2>



<p>After the jam-packed sessions all morning and afternoon, get ready to wind down and relax before calling it a day — or getting revved up for a late Lisbon night.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Movers and Shakers Happy Hour</strong> (5pm &#8211; 7pm, Community HQ): Mingle with your newest NEARCON friends and connections at an epic happy hour sponsored by Glass and Moonbounce.</li>



<li><strong>SailGP Happy Hour</strong> (5:45 pm &#8211; 7pm, NEARCON HQ): Swap stories and fresh insights right outside the Layer 2 Stage as the final session ends. Who knows, you might even score a collab or two while you’re at it.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-shout-out-to-the-day-two-sponsors">Shout out to the Day Two sponsors</h2>



<p>A heartfelt thank you to today’s sponsors, without whose all-out support such an event would not have been possible.</p>



<ul>
<li>Glass</li>



<li>Moonbounce</li>



<li>SailGP</li>
</ul>



<p>Get ready for a day brimming with Web3 wisdom, open web masterminds, and the chance to engage with the brightest and bravest of the NEAR ecosystem. It&#8217;s a unique concoction of insight, education, and fun that only NEARCON ‘23 can cook up. So seize the day, connect at the happy hours, and let’s make Day Two a milestone for the entire open web.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nearcon-23-day-two-begins-expand-your-open-web-horizons/">NEARCON ‘23 Day Two Begins: Expand Your Open Web Horizons</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
