<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Community Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/category/community/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/category/community/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 14:09:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.5</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Community Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/category/community/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">234542837</site>	<item>
		<title>[REDACTED] Speakers Announced, Hackathon Registration Is Live</title>
		<link>/blog/redacted-speakers-announced-hackathon-registration-is-live/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 14:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer relations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redacted]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21462</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It’s getting really real: [REDACTED] is just around the corner, and we have some major updates. You may recall that …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/redacted-speakers-announced-hackathon-registration-is-live/">[REDACTED] Speakers Announced, Hackathon Registration Is Live</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>It’s getting really real: [REDACTED] is just around the corner, and we have some major updates.</p>



<p>You may recall that <a href="https://redactedbangkok.ai/">[REDACTED]</a> is a global convergence to shape the future of User-Owned AI and Chain Abstraction—a future where technology belongs to the people, not corporations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s an IRL movement gathering November 9-11 in Bangkok. It’s a worldwide hackathon kicking off September 5. It’s a defining moment to unify the collective working on these technologies to reclaim our sovereignty.</p>



<p><em>Are you in?</em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The IRL movement: speakers announced, apply to attend</h2>



<p>[REDACTED] is a whole IRL movement: 1,500+ devs, builders, founders, funders, researchers, regulators, and more gathering in person, November 9-11, at the Avani+ Riverside Hotel Bangkok.</p>



<p>Some things can only happen IRL, and some are just way better. Like:</p>



<ul>
<li>Gaining insights from the teams defining the intersection of AI and Web3</li>



<li>Upskilling and learning how to develop AI x Web3 products and apps</li>



<li>Forming deep connections to build the user-owned future together</li>
</ul>



<p>[REDACTED] will feature a wide range of curated sessions, workshops, and discussions led by the people driving AI x Web3 and Chain Abstraction. We can finally share that this includes:</p>



<ul>
<li>Illia Polosukhin (NEAR)</li>



<li>Curtis Spencer (Electric Capital)</li>



<li>Anand Iyer (Canonical)</li>



<li>Maartje Bus (Messari)</li>



<li>Matt Stephenson (Pantera)</li>



<li>Calanthia Mei (Masa)</li>



<li>Evrard-Nil Daillet (Google)</li>
</ul>



<p>And more to come as we get closer to Bangkok.</p>



<p>Tickets to the [REDACTED] IRL movement are totally free—you just have to <a href="https://redactedbangkok.ai/">apply</a> to attend, either as a participant or as a hacker (about which, see below). Visa letters are available to support visa applications.</p>



<p>For the absolute latest on the movement, <a href="https://t.me/redactedbangkok">join the official [REDACTED] Telegram channel</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">[REDACTED] Hackathon Registration Is Live</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="[REDACTED] Hackathon Registration Is LIVE" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QrciN2vJ3gY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>Registration for the [REDACTED] hackathon is <a href="https://redacted.devpost.com/">OPEN</a>.</p>



<p>The [REDACTED] hackathon sets top problem-solvers to collaborating on the biggest issues in AI x Web3 and Chain Abstraction. Kicking off September 5, it’s eight weeks remote so teams can go deep, and it culminates at the IRL movement in Bangkok, November 9-11.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hackers accepted into the hackathon can expect workshops and tutorials on industry-leading tools, interactive discussion and support from category/ecosystem experts, and, oh yeah, a chance at over $500k+ in bounties and prizes.</p>



<p>There will also be travel scholarships so qualifying hackers can be IRL in Bangkok for the awards ceremony—and to participate in the IRL movement.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Get Involved with [REDACTED]</h2>



<p>There are a lot of ways [for partners?] to get involved with [REDACTED], from digital marketing exposure and exclusive access to side events to major visibility at the IRL movement. <a href="https://airtable.com/appdLXQkwmt4rqtW0/pag8inbcwhbrWjXW9/form">Find what’s right for you.</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/redacted-speakers-announced-hackathon-registration-is-live/">[REDACTED] Speakers Announced, Hackathon Registration Is Live</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21462</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>EthCC 2024: User-Owned AI Takes Center Stage</title>
		<link>/blog/ethcc-2024-user-owned-ai-takes-center-stage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 18:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21447</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Last week, the Ethereum community gathered in Brussels for EthCC, the largest annual European Ethereum event focused on technology and …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/ethcc-2024-user-owned-ai-takes-center-stage/">EthCC 2024: User-Owned AI Takes Center Stage</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Last week, the Ethereum community gathered in Brussels for EthCC, the largest annual European Ethereum event focused on technology and community. Usually held in Paris, this year&#8217;s event moved to Brussels due to the Summer Olympics. Despite initial mixed reactions to the change in location, the Web3 community descended on the Belgian capital for an intense week of conferences, networking, and learning. The NEAR ecosystem was front and center, touting the same vision it has held since its inception: building a world where all people control their own assets, data, and power of governance.</p>



<p>The week kicked off with NEAR co-founder Illia Polosukhin delivering a keynote at the Open Source AI Summit titled &#8220;Why the World Needs User-Owned AI.&#8221; Illia presented the case for investing in open-source, User-Owned AI, emphasizing the importance of collaboration in proactively managing risk, improving user safety, and formally verifying code. He stressed that all data used in training AI models must be open-source to ensure transparency, unpack potential biases, and debug issues effectively.</p>



<p>Later in the week, Illia delivered a keynote presentation on the NEAR AI Hub and AI Developer concept. His talk sparked considerable interest, particularly regarding the transformative potential of Developer AI. The audience was captivated by the vision of a system where individuals, regardless of their technical expertise or financial resources, could transform their ideas into fully-fledged, decentralized, and scalable applications simply by interacting with an AI-driven development platform. This lower barrier to entry for app creation promises to accelerate innovation across the blockchain ecosystem and even in Web2.</p>



<p>NEAR&#8217;s presence at EthCC extended beyond AI discussions. Altan Tutar, CEO of Nuffle Labs, showcased Nuffle&#8217;s pioneering work on data availability, demonstrating how NEAR technology is scaling Ethereum L2s. This presentation highlighted NEAR Protocol&#8217;s versatility beyond its L1 capabilities and its potential to defragment Web3.</p>



<p>Alex Shevchenko from Aurora Labs introduced Forwarder, a personal bridge designed for seamless token transfers between centralized exchanges and various chains, addressing the rapid growth of new blockchains in the ecosystem.</p>



<p>A significant highlight of NEAR&#8217;s participation was the Chain Abstraction Day Brussels on July 10th. Co-hosted with Agoric Systems, this event marked the culmination of NEAR&#8217;s year-long series on interoperability and the future of multi-chain apps and transactions. The day-long program covered different methodologies to achieve chain abstraction to intents, data availability, and infrastructure, including a talk from Illia on what&#8217;s next in the NEAR ecosystem&#8217;s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=saCoQE39Cvo">contributions to Chain Abstraction</a>. A special fireside chat between Agoric&#8217;s Dean Tribble and Illia delved into architecting next-gen Web3 apps.</p>



<p>The NEAR AI Tech Showcase on July 11th further demonstrated NEAR&#8217;s commitment to innovation. The event featured live demonstrations of AI-powered blockchain applications, giving attendees hands-on experience with the latest developments from the NEAR ecosystem. Underpinning these developments was the NEAR Horizon AI Incubation Program, a strategic initiative designed to kickstart NEAR&#8217;s AI ecosystem by collaborating with top-tier Web3 x AI projects.</p>



<p>NEAR&#8217;s presence at EthCC 2024 offered the rest of the Web3 ecosystem a tangible vision of a User-Owned AI future with real technologies already taking shape. By championing the transfer of power and ownership to users, NEAR aims to unlock a myriad of benefits: enhanced productivity, improved search results, personalized experiences, and novel economic opportunities, all while maintaining a steadfast commitment to privacy and security. The ecosystem&#8217;s overarching goal remained clear: to onboard 1 billion users to a new open internet. NEAR&#8217;s unique position at the intersection of blockchain and AI showcased its readiness to address the growing demand for decentralized artificial intelligence, leveraging Web3&#8217;s inherent strengths to forge a truly user-owned digital landscape. As the event concluded, it was evident that EthCC 2024 marked a defining moment for NEAR Protocol, highlighting its visionary approach, technological prowess, and unwavering commitment to a decentralized, user-centric future.</p>



<p>Interested in learning more about User-Owned AI and the teams building the ecosystem? Check out the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL9tzQn_TEuFWMuPiQOXhaE5lpOTnxLPZY">NEAR AI Office Hours</a> series.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/ethcc-2024-user-owned-ai-takes-center-stage/">EthCC 2024: User-Owned AI Takes Center Stage</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21447</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR at EthCC 2024: Pioneering AI x Web3 </title>
		<link>/blog/near-at-ethcc-2024/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21437</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As EthCC 2024 descends upon Brussels, the city&#8217;s historic charm provides a captivating backdrop for one of the crypto industry&#8217;s …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethcc-2024/">NEAR at EthCC 2024: Pioneering AI x Web3 </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As EthCC 2024 descends upon Brussels, the city&#8217;s historic charm provides a captivating backdrop for one of the crypto industry&#8217;s most anticipated events. Amidst cobblestone streets and Gothic architecture, NEAR Foundation is set to make waves with its pioneering approach to AI x Web3. This year&#8217;s conference promises to be a melting pot of ideas, where NEAR&#8217;s forward-thinking vision will take center stage.</p>



<p>The week-long extravaganza kicks off on July 6th with the Open Source AI Summit. Here, NEAR is positioning itself as the home for User-Owned AI. Championing a User-Owned AI future means building a New Internet that democratizes AI development and access, ensuring users, not centralized companies, control AI. By championing this concept, NEAR is set to ignite discussions on how blockchain can revolutionize the AI landscape, putting power back into the hands of individuals and fostering a new era of technological autonomy.<br></p>



<p>Building on the momentum of the Open Source AI Summit, the spotlight shifts on July 7th to the next-generation modular infrastructure for all layers at Contextualised Connect Brussels by YAP Global. Altan Tutar, CEO of Nuffle Labs, will take center stage before a room packed with media representatives, showcasing Nuffle&#8217;s pioneering work on data availability. By leveraging NEAR technology to scale Ethereum L2s, Nuffle demonstrates NEAR Protocol&#8217;s versatility beyond its L1 capabilities, blurring ecosystem boundaries and fostering collaboration with tier-1 projects like EigenLayer. This strategic expansion and technological validation position NEAR as a crucial player in the broader blockchain landscape, attracting more developers, users, and collaborations with major projects, thereby extending NEAR&#8217;s relevance and utility in the evolving decentralized technology space.</p>



<p><br>Without missing a beat, on July 9th, EthCC&#8217;s main event showcases two game-changing presentations. Illia Polosukhin, CEO of NEAR Foundation, will dive into &#8220;Build Your Next Web3 App with AI,&#8221; offering a practical roadmap for integrating AI into blockchain development. Following this, Alex Shevchenko, CEO of Aurora Labs, will address &#8220;Simplifying Access Across Blockchain and Exchanges,&#8221; highlighting NEAR&#8217;s innovative approach to interoperability. These talks will demonstrate NEAR&#8217;s commitment to advancing AI integration and cross-chain accessibility, positioning the ecosystem at the forefront of Web3 innovation.</p>



<p><br>Chain Abstraction Day Brussels on July 10th marks the culmination of NEAR&#8217;s year-long series, solidifying its place as a cornerstone event at EthCC. Co-hosted with Agoric Systems, this gathering positions Chain Abstraction at the forefront of discussions on interoperability and the future of multi-chain environments. Expect deep dives into the technical aspects of defragmenting and unifying Web3, including infrastructure, data availability, and the role of venture capital. Get hands-on with the latest tools, learn from cutting-edge research, and see real-world applications in action through developer success stories. Live lightning demos will bring the power of chain abstraction to life. This event offers invaluable insights and practical knowledge for everyone, from seasoned blockchain developers to Web3 newcomers, helping you streamline and scale your projects.<br><br>Capping off the week, Illia Polosukhin delivers a keynote at Agents Unleashed, where he deep dives into the potential of AI-powered blockchain applications. This summit is designed to unite developers and innovators in the Web3 autonomous AI agent space, offering a comprehensive look at the current use case landscape. Following this, NEAR HZN presents the NEAR AI Tech Showcase on July 11th. This event promises to be a testament to NEAR&#8217;s innovative spirit, featuring live demonstrations of AI-powered blockchain applications. Attendees will get hands-on experience with the latest developments from the NEAR ecosystem, seeing firsthand how AI is reshaping the blockchain landscape. Underpinning these developments is the NEAR Horizon AI Incubation Program, a strategic initiative designed to kickstart NEAR&#8217;s AI ecosystem. By collaborating with top-tier decentralized AI projects, this program aims to co-design crucial infrastructure that will enable sophisticated AI applications on NEAR. Collectively, these events and initiatives demonstrate NEAR&#8217;s commitment to advancing user-owned AI, where intelligence tooling optimizes for individual users and communities rather than corporate profit, unlocking benefits like higher productivity, personalized experiences, and novel economic opportunities.<br><br>As attendees move between historic venues and modern conference spaces, they&#8217;ll witness firsthand how NEAR is pioneering AI x Web3. NEAR&#8217;s presence at EthCC 2024 is more than just a series of presentations &#8211; it&#8217;s a demonstration of a User-Owned AI future. Putting the power and ownership in the hands of the user unlocks benefits such as higher productivity, better search results, more personalized experiences, and novel economic opportunities that are all privacy-first.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethcc-2024/">NEAR at EthCC 2024: Pioneering AI x Web3 </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21437</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shape the User-Owned Future at [REDACTED] in Bangkok</title>
		<link>/blog/redacted/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 15:54:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEARCON 2022 was epic. NEARCON 2023 was iconic. NEARCON 2024? Not this year. Gm to [REDACTED]. [REDACTED] is a global …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/redacted/">Shape the User-Owned Future at [REDACTED] in Bangkok</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEARCON 2022 was epic. NEARCON 2023 was iconic.</p>



<p>NEARCON 2024? <em>Not this year.</em></p>



<p>Gm to [REDACTED].</p>



<p>[REDACTED] is a global convergence to shape the future of User-Owned AI and Chain Abstraction—a future where technology belongs to the people, not corporations. Imagine stepping into a ‘Sovereign Paradise’ where the air buzzes with inspiration and opportunities to learn about AI and Web3. At [REDACTED], you&#8217;re not just attending another tech conference: you are contributing to a pivotal moment in the digital revolution. This IRL movement unifies the AI x Web3 collective as we embark on a transformative future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>[REDACTED] is November 9-11, in Bangkok, Thailand. Be a part of the learnings and insights shared at [REDACTED] by joining Keynotes, Firesides, Workshops, or Hacking.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">[REDACTED] is an IRL movement, and the application to attend is LIVE at <a href="http://redactedbangkok.ai/">redactedbangkok.ai</a>.</h2>



<p>AI is transforming the internet and the way we interact with computing. AI and Web3 can work together to ensure the power of intelligence is where it belongs: in the hands of users. NEAR is leading at this intersection of AI x Web3, and the NEAR Foundation is gathering the global AI x Web3 community in Bangkok to share key innovations and insights, form deep connections that can only happen IRL, and build the user-owned future together.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">[REDACTED] is free, but attendance is by application only.</h2>



<p><a href="http://redactedbangkok.ai/">Apply now</a> to claim your spot among 1,500+ devs, founders, researchers, regulators, creatives, and leaders. Here’s what to expect as you journey through [REDACTED]</p>



<ul>
<li>Upskill your AI knowledge in essential workshops and deep-dive discussions led by the teams defining the intersection of AI x Web3.</li>



<li>Gain insights on how to develop AI x Web3 products and applications. </li>



<li>Connect with collaborators on building the tools, driving adoption, empowering users and communities, and taking back sovereignty.</li>



<li>Interact with projects from NEAR and other Ecosystems, solving problems with AI x Web3 technical solutions. </li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">And stay tuned to participate in the [REDACTED] hybrid hackathon for a chance to win over $500k in prizes.</h2>



<p>The [REDACTED] hackathon is an opportunity to collaborate over eight weeks—both online and IRL in Bangkok—with top problem-solvers on the biggest issues in Chain Abstraction and AI x Web3, with category experts from NEAR and beyond providing interactive discussion and support.</p>



<p>The future of AI, decentralized ecosystems, and community-driven innovation is taking shape live at [REDACTED]. Apply to attend at <a href="http://redactedbangkok.ai/">redactedbangkok.ai</a>.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/redacted/">Shape the User-Owned Future at [REDACTED] in Bangkok</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21428</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Modular Spins Out to Become Nuffle Labs with $13M in Funding</title>
		<link>/blog/nuffle-labs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21409</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The NEAR Foundation announces the launch of Nuffle Labs, a new venture spinning out from Pagoda and the NEAR Foundation. …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nuffle-labs/">NEAR Modular Spins Out to Become Nuffle Labs with $13M in Funding</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The NEAR Foundation announces the launch of Nuffle Labs, a new venture spinning out from Pagoda and the NEAR Foundation. Founded by the core contributors to the NEAR Data Availability Layer (NEAR DA) and the NEAR Fast Finality Layer (NFFL), the NEAR Modular product suite is now spinning out into an independent entity dedicated to improving and amplifying NEAR’s modularity offerings. The new entity has secured $13 million in funding, including a strategic grant from NEAR Foundation and external investment led by Electric Capital.</p>



<p>The spinout of Nuffle Labs reflects not only the strength of the core team and the products they are building, but also illustrates the Foundation’s commitment to decentralization by turning core functions over to proven teams in the ecosystem. As an independent team, Nuffle Labs will be better positioned to operate at the forefront of modular blockchain design, nurture its own decentralized community, and forge more partnerships across the Web3 ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Nuffle Labs will leverage NEAR Protocol’s cost-effective, fast, and proven technology to offer rollups enhanced modularity. It is responsible for two key products in NEAR’s modular suite: NEAR Data Availability (NEAR DA) and NEAR Fast Finality Layer, now Nuffle Fast Finality Layer (NFFL).</p>



<p><strong>Nuffle Labs secures $13M in funding to support their growth</strong></p>



<p>Nuffle Labs’ spinout comes with substantial investment, including a strategic grant from the NEAR Foundation as well as funding from external investors including Electric Capital, Canonical Crypto, Fabric Ventures, Robot Ventures, Caladan, and Lyrik Ventures. Notable angel investors include Jordi Alexander (Selini), Blackdragon VC, Bowen Wang (NEAR), Sreeram Kannan (EigenLayer), Sam Kazemian (Frax), Sandeep Nailwal (Polygon), DeFi Dad (4RC), Dovey Wan (Primitive Ventures), and Mert Mumtaz (Helius). With these resources and supporters, the team is well-equipped to advance NEAR DA and NFFL, expand the team, invest in R&amp;D, and build a strong community that spans across NEAR, Ethereum, and beyond.</p>



<p>“We&#8217;re proud to support the growth of Nuffle Labs as an independent company in the NEAR ecosystem. These 4 excellent co-founders have built first-rate modularity products that showcase the best of NEAR&#8217;s technology with NEAR DA and NFFL, providing cost-effective and performant solutions to projects across Web3,” said Illia Polosukhin, Co-Founder of NEAR Protocol and CEO of NEAR Foundation. “We look forward to continued collaboration with the NEAR Foundation as they expand and evolve.”</p>



<p>Avichal Garg, General Partner at lead investor Electric Capital, said, “We are excited to back Nuffle Labs, the builders behind NEAR DA and the NEAR Fast Finality Layer (NFFL). As the core team that developed these products from the ground up, Nuffle Labs has the expertise to advance these modular solutions, creating a world where intra- and interchain transactions are cheap, fast, and secure.”</p>



<p>“I have had the great privilege of getting to know the founders of Nuffle and working with them from day zero,” said Anand Iyer, General Partner at Canonical Crypto. “Their passion for solving blockchain scaling combined with their expertise from building solutions at NEAR has me genuinely excited for them and their future.”</p>



<p><strong>Understanding NEAR Data Availability (NEAR DA)</strong></p>



<p>NEAR DA utilizes the sharded architecture of NEAR Protocol to provide a modular data availability layer for Ethereum rollups with extremely high throughput and low cost. On mainnet launch, RSS3 – an open information protocol bridging AI and Web3 – experienced a substantial cost reduction, paying a daily average of $10 compared to their previous $1,000. NEAR DA currently has a throughput of 24MB/s, significantly higher than its closest competitor’s 6.67MB/s – making NEAR DA the most scalable, cheapest, and reliable DA solution on the market.</p>



<p>NEAR DA’s scalability is further enhanced by its ability to support multiple rollups, whether they are optimistic or ZK-rollups. NEAR Data Availability (NEAR DA) provides:</p>



<ul>
<li>Cost-efficiency: Storing data on NEAR Protocol is significantly cheaper than on Ethereum, making it easier for projects to build as well as faster.</li>



<li>Effortless Validation: NEAR Protocol&#8217;s trustless off-chain light client simplifies validation, ensuring accurate and reliable transactions.</li>



<li>User-Friendly Interaction: NEAR Protocol provides easy access to on-chain data through RPC, making blockchain interaction seamless for developers and users.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Exploring NEAR Fast Finality Layer (NFFL)</strong></p>



<p>The name Nuffle Labs is derived from the acronym NFFL. The Nuffle Fast Finality Layer (NFFL) is an EigenLayer Actively Validated Service (AVS) designed to aggregate state across various rollups. By leveraging NEAR DA, NFFL provides a fast, universal, and secure finality layer. It enhances block finality across different protocols and integrates additional public DA layers into the blockchain stack, paving the way for innovative cross-chain applications. NFFL is currently live on testnet––learn more <a href="https://nffl.nethermind.io/">about the protocol</a>.</p>



<p><strong>What&#8217;s next for Nuffle Labs?</strong></p>



<p>“We are thrilled about the incredible opportunity to grow and develop NEAR’s modular product offerings at Nuffle Labs,” said Altan Tutar, CEO of Nuffle Labs. The other Nuffle co-founders are Sam Wang, Firat Sertgoz, and Donovan Dall. “We deeply appreciate the support from the NEAR Foundation and are honored by the validation from such distinguished investors. Their confidence in our vision and capabilities energizes us as we continue to innovate and expand.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Looking ahead, Nuffle Labs will focus on advancing the development of the NFFL AVS on EigenLayer and further enhancing the robustness and efficiency of NEAR DA to support Ethereum’s rollup-centric future. The team is committed to furthering innovation in modular blockchain design and defragmenting the Web3 ecosystem.</p>



<p>Follow along with the Nuffle team’s progress on their <a href="http://nuff.tech/">new site here</a> and follow the <a href="https://x.com/NuffleLabs">Nuffle Labs X(Twitter) account</a>. L2 builders interested in a partnership with Nuffle or those interested in applying to work with Nuffle can get in touch via the Nuffle Labs website.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nuffle-labs/">NEAR Modular Spins Out to Become Nuffle Labs with $13M in Funding</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21409</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing *NEAR Name Tokens &#8211; Multichain, Cross-Platform Digital Identities In Web3</title>
		<link>/blog/introducing-near-name-tokens/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 13:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Following the recently announced partnership between NEAR Foundation and&#160;D3, we’re excited to introduce *NEAR Name Tokens; a multichain, cross-platform digital …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/introducing-near-name-tokens/">Introducing *NEAR Name Tokens &#8211; Multichain, Cross-Platform Digital Identities In Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Following the recently announced <a href="/blog/near-protocol-partners-with-d3-to-apply-for-near-top-level-domain/">partnership between NEAR Foundation and&nbsp;D3</a>, we’re excited to introduce *NEAR Name Tokens; a multichain, cross-platform digital identity for web3 and beyond.</p>



<p>NEAR Foundation is working with D3 to bridge the gap between traditional internet infrastructure and web3. *NEAR Name Tokens are an important step in developing the <a href="https://d3.inc/blog/educational/futureproof-your-digital-identity-how-d3-aims-to-revolutionize-your-online-persona/">futureproof, interoperable digital identities</a> that will be key to driving implementation of chain abstraction, and of developing web3 more broadly.</p>



<p><strong>Complementing the NEAR Ecosystem with *NEAR Name Tokens</strong></p>



<p>NEAR already offers a deeply integrated identity solution with named NEAR accounts. These NEAR accounts, however, are limited to use across the NEAR ecosystem.</p>



<p>*NEAR Name Tokens will offer users a comprehensive digital identity solution across the wider web3 ecosystem, while keeping NEAR front and center.</p>



<p>Users will be able to use these name tokens in a variety of ways, including:</p>



<ul>
<li>As a simplified wallet address across hundreds of different blockchain networks</li>



<li>As an infrastructure identifier across hundreds of different blockchain networks</li>



<li>As a cross-platform username across various different decentralized platforms, including DeFi, GameFi, SocialFi, SportFi and other related applications</li>



<li>As Verifiable Credentials (VCs) to platforms and services that you interact with</li>



<li>To gain access to unique benefits and rewards programs for participating in the D3 ecosystem</li>



<li>As expressions of interest for the eventual .NEAR equivalent domain on the internet</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Why *NEAR Instead of .NEAR</strong></p>



<p>*NEAR Name Tokens feature a star, or asterisk (*), between the name and extension—such as <em>you*near</em>—instead of a period (.). In part, this is because NEAR accounts already use a .NEAR extension, and we want to avoid confusion for users.</p>



<p>More importantly, however, we use *NEAR because Name Tokens are unique web3 identifiers, not real domains, and we want to avoid any confusion between these as well. For years, several naming systems across web3 have thrown around the word “domain” quite liberally, without offering any of the actual utility offered by real domains.</p>



<p>Real domains are fully integrated with the Domain Name System, the distributed service that allows users to access websites and email infrastructure with ease. Billions of internet-capable devices—such as computers, tablets, mobile phones, Internet of Things devices, and more—support the DNS and real domains without the need for specialized software or plugins.</p>



<p>Integrating web3 with DNS will be critical in bringing interoperable digital identities to web3. To that end, NEAR Foundation has partnered with D3 to apply for and obtain the .near top-level domain—like the “.org” in <em>near.org</em>—during the upcoming application period for new TLDs, the first in over a decade.</p>



<p><strong>Exclusive Early Access Period to *NEAR Name Tokens for NEAR Account Holders</strong></p>



<p>As part of our initial launch phase later this summer,, existing NEAR account holders will receive exclusive early access to their equivalent *NEAR Name Tokens. For instance, if you already have the <em>name.near</em> NEAR account registered prior to launch, you will receive exclusive access to register <em>name*near</em> for a period of 90 days before names are released for public availability.</p>



<p>Similarly, should a NEAR account be available for any new *NEAR Name Token registrations, D3 will claim it on behalf of users to ensure a uniform experience across the NEAR ecosystem. Users can <a href="https://d3.app/near">sign up for early access</a>, and you’ll be  notified you prior to the official launch of *NEAR Name Tokens later this summer</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/introducing-near-name-tokens/">Introducing *NEAR Name Tokens &#8211; Multichain, Cross-Platform Digital Identities In Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21393</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Foundation Partners with NEAT Protocol to Accelerate the Growth of AI Applications with 1 million $NEAR Delegation</title>
		<link>/blog/neat-protocol/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 12:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21390</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Foundation announces today that NEAT, a rollup protocol designed for scaling AI applications on NEAR, has received 1 million …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/neat-protocol/">NEAR Foundation Partners with NEAT Protocol to Accelerate the Growth of AI Applications with 1 million $NEAR Delegation</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR Foundation announces today that NEAT, a rollup protocol designed for scaling AI applications on NEAR, has received 1 million $NEAR token staking delegation from NEAR Foundation. All NEAR token rewards from the delegation will be redistributed to $NEAT stakers, producing approximately 120-200% APY. This funding is part of NEAR Foundation&#8217;s efforts to support AI and blockchain projects on NEAR, and to promote use cases of AI integration with blockchain technology more broadly. NEAT, as the first rollup scaling protocol to receive official support from the NEAR Foundation, will utilize these funds to attract a wider user base to its ecosystem.</p>



<p>NEAT is a rollup scaling solution built on the NEAR inscription standard, specifically designed to facilitate AI and machine-learning applications on NEAR. NEAT offers an innovative approach for rollups to be built on NEAR. With off-chain indexer nodes for execution and NEAR L1 as the data availability layer, NEAT eliminates the need for rollups to deploy smart contracts or run verification logic on the L1. This streamlined process drastically reduces transaction costs for rollups, making NEAT particularly well suited for computationally intensive applications such as AI and gaming. Additionally, NEAR Catalog, powered by NEAT, is currently developing an advanced indexer that aims to provide projects and applications in the NEAR ecosystem with cost-effective and flexible indexing and querying capabilities.</p>



<p><strong>NEAT Token and Benefits</strong><br></p>



<p>The $NEAT token exists in two forms, NRC-20 and NEP-141, with a total supply of 42 million tokens. $NEAT tokens offers the following benefits:</p>



<p>1. Stakers of $NEAT-NEP141 will receive the staking rewards generated from the 1 million $NEAR tokens provided by the Foundation. A portion of these staking rewards will also be allocated to support the exploration of AI integration with NEAT.</p>



<p>2. $NEAT-NEP141 stakers will receive a share of the fees generated from wrap/unwrap operations (currently set at 1% fee rate) and a portion of the fees from the NRC-20 marketplace.</p>



<p>3. After the decentralized indexer is operational, a portion of the indexing fees will be distributed to $NEAT-NEP141 stakers.</p>



<p>4. Holders of $NEAT-NRC20 tokens will be eligible to receive airdrops of newly minted NRC-20 tokens.</p>



<p>5. $NEAT serves as a utility token within the NEAT ecosystem, enabling services/assets payments, DeFi integration, AI governance, and more.</p>



<p><strong>The Road Ahead: Revolutionizing AI with Decentralized Indexing</strong></p>



<p><strong><br></strong>NEAT is building the first fully customizable decentralized indexer network, which allows any project to easily store data on the NEAR blockchain, deploy custom indexing logic on a decentralized set of indexer nodes, and achieve verifiable execution through zero-knowledge proofs. This approach aims to address potential failure points and attack vectors associated with centralized indexers.</p>



<p>One of the most exciting use cases for decentralized indexing is in the field of artificial intelligence. With NRC-20 and NEAT Indexers, it becomes possible to store AI data, parameters, algorithms, models, and outputs as on-chain inscriptions and integrate them with off-chain execution through zero-knowledge proofs. For instance, one can imagine creating fully open-source AI-powered games, where users participate in shaping the game&#8217;s narrative, and the history is permanently stored on-chain through inscriptions. AI agents&#8217; models, parameters, and decisions can be represented as inscribed NFTs, and their training and model parameters can be stored on-chain.</p>



<p>This combination of blockchain transparency and off-chain computational efficiency allows AI to be truly accessible and open to everyone, contributing to the development of a genuinely open network.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/neat-protocol/">NEAR Foundation Partners with NEAT Protocol to Accelerate the Growth of AI Applications with 1 million $NEAR Delegation</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21390</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unveiling new partnerships at the International Tech Summit in Bermuda</title>
		<link>/blog/international-tech-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 13:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21341</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The NEAR Foundation announced a slew of partnerships and developments at this year’s International Tech Summit in Bermuda, organized by …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/international-tech-summit/">Unveiling new partnerships at the International Tech Summit in Bermuda</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The NEAR Foundation announced a slew of partnerships and developments at this year’s International Tech Summit in Bermuda, organized by Penrose Partners.</p>



<p>The new collaborations will leverage Bermuda’s unique crypto-friendly regulatory environment to accelerate the integration of digital assets into global markets. They’ll also enhance NEAR’s role in advancing blockchain applications across sectors. From NFTs to insurance, here’s the full rundown.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-foundation-and-penrose-a-strategic-alliance-at-the-tech-summit">NEAR Foundation and Penrose: A strategic alliance at the Tech Summit</h2>



<p>As the presenting partner of the International Tech Summit, the NEAR Foundation cemented a significant relationship with Penrose Partners, a leading international digital asset advisory firm. It’s part of NEAR&#8217;s strategic effort to tap into Bermuda&#8217;s thriving crypto scene, supported by progressive regulations under the island’s Digital Asset Business Act.</p>



<p>During the summit, NEAR Foundation’s executive team and leaders from the institutional business segment were active participants, supporting various digital payment activations and Bermuda’s first-ever NFT art gallery. This engagement highlights NEAR&#8217;s commitment to exploring substantial business opportunities in Bermuda, particularly within its vast insurance sector, and strengthening its ties with local government and regulatory bodies.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-nayms-and-near-innovating-on-chain-insurance">Nayms and NEAR: Innovating on-chain insurance</h2>



<p>NEAR Foundation announced a partnership with Nayms that marks a pioneering step toward revolutionizing the insurance industry through blockchain technology. Nayms, a regulated marketplace for on-chain insurance, aligns with NEAR Foundation to develop innovative web3 products linked to insurance pools.</p>



<p>NEAR Foundation and Nayms aim to address the challenges of pricing and securing insurance for blockchain ventures, crucial to the legitimacy and growth of digital assets. As not only a leader in the regulation of digital assets but a massive global hub for insurance and reinsurance, Bermuda represents fertile ground for the collaboration.</p>



<p>The partners are setting out to transform traditional insurance models by enabling novel ways to underwrite risks associated with NEAR-based companies. The goal is to disrupt a multi-trillion-dollar market and offer institutional investors the chance to engage with new, attractive risk-adjusted investment opportunities in the field of on-chain insurance.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-mountain-protocol-and-near-foundation-expanding-digital-dollar-use">Mountain Protocol and NEAR Foundation: Expanding digital dollar use</h2>



<p>The partnership between NEAR Foundation and Mountain Protocol introduces the integration of Mountain’s USDM, a leading yield-bearing stablecoin, onto the NEAR protocol. This collaboration is set to transform how local businesses in Bermuda manage their treasuries by leveraging the stability and efficiency of digital dollars.</p>



<p>This strategic alliance enhances Bermuda&#8217;s capacity to utilize digital dollars, like USDM, within its extensive insurance and reinsurance programs. It taps into a $150 billion stablecoin market, reflecting Bermuda’s advanced digital asset regulation and its thriving financial ecosystem.</p>



<p>Additionally, NEAR Foundation will explore the potential of USDM in everyday applications, notably in partnership with HITCH, Bermuda&#8217;s leading transportation app. It’s about demonstrating how stablecoins can streamline transactions, reduce costs for drivers and riders, and showcase the practical benefits of blockchain technology in daily consumer interactions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-expanding-digital-transactions-with-hitch-and-near">Expanding digital transactions with HITCH and NEAR</h2>



<p>As mentioned, NEAR Foundation also announced a partnership with HITCH to further embed digital assets into everyday transactions. The goal is to reimagine how local businesses and consumers handle transactions by adopting US digital dollars—USDC and USDM—within HITCH’s payment systems.</p>



<p>This initiative is expected to enhance cash management for businesses and streamline payment processes, offering greater efficiency and cost savings. By reducing transaction fees, HITCH can reinvest these gains into the local economy or offer enhanced rewards to drivers and riders.</p>



<p>Beyond improving ride-sharing transactions, the collaboration is set to broaden the use of digital dollars in Bermuda. HITCH plans to enable payments for government services like vehicle licensing and payroll taxes through its app, demonstrating the broad potential of digital currencies to simplify and secure routine financial activities.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-extending-the-open-web-experience-with-mintbase-s-nft-gallery">Extending the open web experience with Mintbase’s NFT gallery</h2>



<p>Following the NEAR Foundation partnerships with Mountain Protocol and HITCH, the International Tech Summit also featured a significant venture into the world of digital art, powered by Mintbase. This event marked the debut of Bermuda&#8217;s first NFT art exhibition, curated by local art consultancy Mazar-Fox Art Consulting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Aptly named “Redefining the Boundaries Between Art and Technology” and set in the iconic cruise passenger terminal at Hamilton&#8217;s Pier Six, the exhibition featured a mix of international and Bermudian artists, as well as educational workshops on NFTs conducted by Mintbase to deepen attendees’ knowledge and engagement.</p>



<p>These sessions included practical onboarding for attendees that enabled them to create and interact with digital art firsthand. Special edition NFTs were also offered as exclusive rewards for those who purchased limited edition merchandise, further integrating the digital art experience into the summit’s framework and enhancing the interactive nature of the gallery.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-closing-thoughts-bermuda-as-a-nexus-of-digital-innovation">Closing thoughts: Bermuda as a nexus of digital innovation</h2>



<p>The International Tech Summit highlighted Bermuda’s pivotal role as a hub for digital asset regulation and innovation—and it set the stage for significant advancements in blockchain applications.</p>



<p>The partnerships announced between NEAR Foundation and key players like Penrose, Nayms, Mountain Protocol, HITCH, and Mintbase are important steps toward integrating digital assets and the open web into everyday business and consumer practices.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/international-tech-summit/">Unveiling new partnerships at the International Tech Summit in Bermuda</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21341</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Innovative Alliance Marks Milestone That Drives Digital Finance </title>
		<link>/blog/innovative-alliance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 15:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21336</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Today NEAR Foundation announced a partnership with Lulo X and Peersyst Technology. The goal of the collaboration is to redefine …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/innovative-alliance/">Innovative Alliance Marks Milestone That Drives Digital Finance </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Today NEAR Foundation announced a partnership with Lulo X and Peersyst Technology. The goal of the collaboration is to redefine the parameters of digital finance by offering a secure, stable digital currency that broadens economic perspectives within Web3. As a result, Lulo X users will enjoy greater autonomy and less friction over their finances.</p>



<p>Lulo X, a pioneering Colombian fintech firm, is on a mission to challenge financial barriers and help users build a better future. This partnership will leverage NEAR Protocol&#8217;s innovative blockchain technology to facilitate seamless and secure transactions, while also building their native stablecoin on the NEAR blockchain.</p>



<p><em>“We are building a financial infrastructure that is characterized by its ease of use and robust security. We want to improve the most basic financial activities, ensuring digital transactions and making financial tools accessible to everyone,”</em> says <strong>Natalia Jiménez</strong>, CEO of Lulo X.</p>



<p>Peersyst Technology brings its expertise in blockchain implementation to ensure the robustness of the platform. Together with NEAR, the two organizations will create cutting-edge solutions that simplify the complexities of digital finance, offering users more control over their economic activities.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-expanding-financial-horizons-with-lulo-x">Expanding Financial Horizons with Lulo X</h2>



<p>Lulo X&#8217;s commitment, as articulated by CEO Natalia Jiménez, is to dismantle financial barriers through a platform noted for its ease of use, security, and democratization of finance.</p>



<p>“We are at the forefront of a new era where technology powers sustainability in finance. Partnering with the NEAR Foundation is a step towards redefining digital finance to be secure, inclusive and democratic. This alliance is the key to a future where financial empowerment is a universal right. We are committed to a future that is not only prosperous but sustainable, aligning financial growth with the well-being of our planet,&#8221; Jiménez says.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This collaboration with NEAR will amplify the security and efficiency of transactions, integrating biometric safeguards and fraud prevention measures that underline Lulo X&#8217;s dedication to user protection. It’s founded on principles of financial education, regulatory cooperation, and innovative infrastructure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NEAR&#8217;s advanced blockchain technology supports Lulo X&#8217;s vision, facilitating the development of tailored financial products that foster informed decision-making and economic inclusion. The Lulo X stablecoin on NEAR is a major step in that direction.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ensuring-success-with-peersyst-technology">Ensuring Success with Peersyst Technology</h2>



<p>Peersyst Technology will also be instrumental in implementing the NEAR Protocol&#8217;s innovative stablecoin solutions, bringing a wealth of experience in blockchain projects. Their technical prowess ensures that the infrastructure developed with Lulo X is not only scalable but also robust enough to handle the complexities of real-world financial applications.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Peersyst&#8217;s commitment to the development of blockchain-powered currencies and payment systems, especially in Latin America, has been unwavering. Our collaboration with leading protocols is a testament to the maturity of the technology, paving the way for its widespread adoption in finance.” highlights Ferran Prat, CEO of Peersyst.</p>



<p>This partnership leverages Peersyst&#8217;s blockchain expertise to ensure the stable and efficient operation of financial solutions. By integrating cutting-edge blockchain technology with NEAR&#8217;s platform, Peersyst facilitates the creation of financial services that are both secure and user-friendly, enhancing the overall reliability of the system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Their contribution is vital for developing a framework that supports high transaction volumes and complex data security requirements, essential for fostering trust and widespread adoption among users.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-near-ecosystem-continues-to-broaden-fintech">The NEAR Ecosystem Continues to Broaden Fintech</h2>



<p>The partnerships between NEAR, Lulo X, and Peersyst Technology aims to introduce robust, scalable financial solutions that make economic activities more accessible and efficient.</p>



<p>&#8220;This partnership with Lulo X and Peersyst is a step forward in harnessing Stablecoins for fast and cost-effective payments. It reflects our mutual goal of democratizing financial access and expanding NEAR&#8217;s presence in Latin America. The high performance and low fees of the NEAR Protocol are poised to deliver unparalleled benefits for Web3 users and applications, catalyzing stablecoin-based payment solutions in the region.&#8221;</p>



<p>The partnership is a sign of major progress in fintech. By providing the platform and resources for innovations like savings in digital dollars and – bolstered by Peersyst and the NEAR blockchain – the intersection of finance and the open web will become more safe, fair, and inclusive.</p>



<p></p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/innovative-alliance/">Innovative Alliance Marks Milestone That Drives Digital Finance </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21336</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Launches Infrastructure Committee with $4 Million in Funding </title>
		<link>/blog/near-launches-infrastructure-committee/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR has seen a massive surge in users and transactions over the last few months. It’s important to have a …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-launches-infrastructure-committee/">NEAR Launches Infrastructure Committee with $4 Million in Funding </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR has seen a massive surge in users and transactions over the last few months. It’s important to have a smooth-running blockchain for project and founder expansion. Today, the NEAR Foundation launches the Infrastructure Committee, a new initiative aimed to strengthen NEAR&#8217;s Key Infrastructure. With $4 million earmarked for infrastructure projects, the initiative is meant to support the success of NEAR projects while distributing funds and sourcing projects in an open, transparent way.</p>



<p>What is Key Infrastructure? It includes RPC nodes, relayers, indexers, bridges, wallets, load balancers, and oracles. Also, NEAR should be listed correctly on all the DEX tools available. Incidents and outages need to be easily reported and fixed.</p>



<p><strong>The committee is made up of  ecosystem leaders and NEAR partners from across core NEAR orgs. Its goals are to:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Decentralize decision-making</li>



<li>Enhance critical infrastructure</li>



<li>Streamline efforts for greater clarity and decentralization</li>
</ul>



<p>The committee primarily focuses on proposals, with multiple Requests For Proposals (RFPs) planned to meet important ecosystem needs. These proposals will undergo review and asynchronous voting by the committee.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-progress-of-the-infrastructure-committee">Progress of the Infrastructure Committee</h2>



<p><strong>The Infrastructure Committee has already funded five critical infrastructure proposals:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Jutsu IDE infrastructure implementation (AI development environment)</li>



<li>FASTNEAR infrastructure services (new RPC nodes and custom endpoints)</li>



<li>Aurora Web 3.0 Wallet Support Services</li>



<li>The building of a Treasury App for use by governing committees</li>



<li>An audit of the Ledger integrations</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>The committee also inherited some projects that it will now actively manage:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Aurora RPC SpeedUp</li>



<li>MyNEARWallet maintenance by Meteor</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>With over half of the allocated $4 million budget remaining, there is an open invitation to the community to bring forward innovative infrastructure projects such as:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Faster RPC Nodes</li>



<li>Specific common endpoints to replace broad RPC queries</li>



<li>New bridges to improve cross-chain transactions and increase the number of chains supported</li>



<li>ICANN-compliant DNS and expansion of top-level domains</li>



<li>Focused relayers to support gas-free and other specialized relayer needs</li>
</ul>



<p>The committee encourages community members to contribute their ideas, proposals, and feedback, and welcomes a range of perspectives from founders, developers, and NEAR enthusiasts on how to improve the foundations of NEAR technology.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>The current Infrastructure Committee is comprised of the following members:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Abhishek Vaidyanathan, NEAR Foundation (serving as a non-voting meeting Chair)</li>



<li>Alex Shevchenko, Aurora Labs</li>



<li>Bowen Wang, Director of Protocol, Pagoda</li>



<li>Vlad Frolov, DevHub</li>



<li>Sandi Fatic, Calimero</li>



<li>Eric Winer, Pagoda</li>



<li>Illia Polosukhin, NEAR Foundation (serving as an ad-hoc member on an as-needed basis)</li>



<li>Christopher Donovan, NEAR Foundation (serving as an ad-hoc member on an as-needed basis)</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>The Working Group comprises the following admins and advisors:</strong><strong><br></strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Project Oversight &#8211; Konrad Merino, Head of Blockchain Success, NEAR Foundation</li>



<li>Product Manager &#8211; Gautham Ravi, Sr. Product Manager, Pagoda</li>



<li>Project Manager &#8211; Trentin C Bergeron, Sr. Technical Program Manager, Pagoda</li>



<li>Technical BD &#8211; Vikas Pandey, Success &amp; Partner Engineering, NEAR Foundation</li>



<li>Technical Advisor &#8211; Robert Tsia, SRE Manager, Pagoda</li>



<li>Technical Advisor &#8211; Ernesto Cejas Padilla, Sr. SRE, Pagoda</li>



<li>Technical Advisor &#8211; Firat Sertgoz, Engineering Manager, Pagoda</li>



<li>Technical Advisor &#8211; Patrick Engvall, Sr. Engineer, Pagoda</li>



<li>Technical Advisor &#8211; Pierre Leguen, Software Engineer, NEAR Foundation Finance</li>



<li>Broadcast MC &amp; Project Advisor &#8211; Marcus Ribeiro, Ecosystem Relations, NEAR Foundation</li>
</ul>



<p>For those looking to participate, the <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/wiki/Proposal-Process-%E2%80%90-Team">Interim Proposal and Funding Process</a> provides a comprehensive guide on how to submit proposals. To foster transparency and public engagement, the committee has established clear processes to track and discuss proposals openly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The community can view the <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1sjUgUnY_Ufw8RjfUFj5K2RM6gYC3XBRVu1iYXzD3cBQ/edit?usp=sharing">public tracking of proposals</a> document and participate in <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/discussions">public discussions</a>, including announcements of Requests for Proposals (RFPs). The committee’s meeting notes will be shared with the community to maintain openness about the committee&#8217;s decisions and discussions.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-engaging-the-community-and-fostering-collaboration">Engaging the Community and Fostering Collaboration</h2>



<p>To facilitate community engagement, anyone interested can join the <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/discussions">discussion</a> on the Github repo, which will serve as the hub for suggestions, collaboration, and support among members interested in contributing to NEAR infrastructure.<br></p>



<p>The <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/wiki/Infrastructure-Committee">Infrastructure Mandate &amp; Charter</a> and <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/wiki/Infrastructure-Working-Group">Working Group Details</a> will offer additional insights into the committee’s mission, structure, and ongoing projects. These resources are designed to educate and inspire community members to contribute their skills and ideas towards building a more robust and scalable NEAR ecosystem.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-future-plans-for-the-near-infrastructure-committee">Future Plans for the NEAR Infrastructure Committee</h2>



<p>As NEAR continues to grow, so will the necessity for robust infrastructure to support an increasing number of transactions and users. Future enhancements include the introduction of a more sophisticated incident management system and post-mortem processes for infrastructure outages.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The development of a Blockchain Operating System (BOS)-based app for proposal management will be another significant move towards optimizing the efficiency of the funding process. This upgrade will streamline the proposal and funding workflow, making it easier for community members to submit and manage their projects.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The committee’s work will also support NEAR’s growth and chain abstraction efforts, ensuring the blockchain can handle the anticipated surge in traffic as more users join the ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Those interested in getting involved with the Infrastructure Committee can join the <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/discussions">Working Group Discussion on GitHub</a> to collaborate on initiatives, discuss proposals and RFPs, or ask questions.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-launches-infrastructure-committee/">NEAR Launches Infrastructure Committee with $4 Million in Funding </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21321</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
