<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Community Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/category/community/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/category/community/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 19:05:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Community Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/category/community/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">234542837</site>	<item>
		<title>Shape the User-Owned Future at [REDACTED] in Bangkok</title>
		<link>/blog/redacted/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 15:54:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEARCON 2022 was epic. NEARCON 2023 was iconic. NEARCON 2024? Not this year. Gm to [REDACTED]. [REDACTED] is a global …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/redacted/">Shape the User-Owned Future at [REDACTED] in Bangkok</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEARCON 2022 was epic. NEARCON 2023 was iconic.</p>



<p>NEARCON 2024? <em>Not this year.</em></p>



<p>Gm to [REDACTED].</p>



<p>[REDACTED] is a global convergence to shape the future of User-Owned AI and Chain Abstraction—a future where technology belongs to the people, not corporations. Imagine stepping into a ‘Sovereign Paradise’ where the air buzzes with inspiration and opportunities to learn about AI and Web3. At [REDACTED], you&#8217;re not just attending another tech conference: you are contributing to a pivotal moment in the digital revolution. This IRL movement unifies the AI x Web3 collective as we embark on a transformative future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>[REDACTED] is November 9-11, in Bangkok, Thailand. Be a part of the learnings and insights shared at [REDACTED] by joining Keynotes, Firesides, Workshops, or Hacking.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">[REDACTED] is an IRL movement, and the application to attend is LIVE at <a href="http://redactedbangkok.ai/">redactedbangkok.ai</a>.</h2>



<p>AI is transforming the internet and the way we interact with computing. AI and Web3 can work together to ensure the power of intelligence is where it belongs: in the hands of users. NEAR is leading at this intersection of AI x Web3, and the NEAR Foundation is gathering the global AI x Web3 community in Bangkok to share key innovations and insights, form deep connections that can only happen IRL, and build the user-owned future together.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">[REDACTED] is free, but attendance is by application only.</h2>



<p><a href="http://redactedbangkok.ai/">Apply now</a> to claim your spot among 1,500+ devs, founders, researchers, regulators, creatives, and leaders. Here’s what to expect as you journey through [REDACTED]</p>



<ul>
<li>Upskill your AI knowledge in essential workshops and deep-dive discussions led by the teams defining the intersection of AI x Web3.</li>



<li>Gain insights on how to develop AI x Web3 products and applications. </li>



<li>Connect with collaborators on building the tools, driving adoption, empowering users and communities, and taking back sovereignty.</li>



<li>Interact with projects from NEAR and other Ecosystems, solving problems with AI x Web3 technical solutions. </li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">And stay tuned to participate in the [REDACTED] hybrid hackathon for a chance to win over $500k in prizes.</h2>



<p>The [REDACTED] hackathon is an opportunity to collaborate over eight weeks—both online and IRL in Bangkok—with top problem-solvers on the biggest issues in Chain Abstraction and AI x Web3, with category experts from NEAR and beyond providing interactive discussion and support.</p>



<p>The future of AI, decentralized ecosystems, and community-driven innovation is taking shape live at [REDACTED]. Apply to attend at <a href="http://redactedbangkok.ai/">redactedbangkok.ai</a>.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/redacted/">Shape the User-Owned Future at [REDACTED] in Bangkok</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21428</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Modular Spins Out to Become Nuffle Labs with $13M in Funding</title>
		<link>/blog/nuffle-labs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21409</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The NEAR Foundation announces the launch of Nuffle Labs, a new venture spinning out from Pagoda and the NEAR Foundation. …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nuffle-labs/">NEAR Modular Spins Out to Become Nuffle Labs with $13M in Funding</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The NEAR Foundation announces the launch of Nuffle Labs, a new venture spinning out from Pagoda and the NEAR Foundation. Founded by the core contributors to the NEAR Data Availability Layer (NEAR DA) and the NEAR Fast Finality Layer (NFFL), the NEAR Modular product suite is now spinning out into an independent entity dedicated to improving and amplifying NEAR’s modularity offerings. The new entity has secured $13 million in funding, including a strategic grant from NEAR Foundation and external investment led by Electric Capital.</p>



<p>The spinout of Nuffle Labs reflects not only the strength of the core team and the products they are building, but also illustrates the Foundation’s commitment to decentralization by turning core functions over to proven teams in the ecosystem. As an independent team, Nuffle Labs will be better positioned to operate at the forefront of modular blockchain design, nurture its own decentralized community, and forge more partnerships across the Web3 ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Nuffle Labs will leverage NEAR Protocol’s cost-effective, fast, and proven technology to offer rollups enhanced modularity. It is responsible for two key products in NEAR’s modular suite: NEAR Data Availability (NEAR DA) and NEAR Fast Finality Layer, now Nuffle Fast Finality Layer (NFFL).</p>



<p><strong>Nuffle Labs secures $13M in funding to support their growth</strong></p>



<p>Nuffle Labs’ spinout comes with substantial investment, including a strategic grant from the NEAR Foundation as well as funding from external investors including Electric Capital, Canonical Crypto, Fabric Ventures, Robot Ventures, Caladan, and Lyrik Ventures. Notable angel investors include Jordi Alexander (Selini), Blackdragon VC, Bowen Wang (NEAR), Sreeram Kannan (EigenLayer), Sam Kazemian (Frax), Sandeep Nailwal (Polygon), DeFi Dad (4RC), Dovey Wan (Primitive Ventures), and Mert Mumtaz (Helius). With these resources and supporters, the team is well-equipped to advance NEAR DA and NFFL, expand the team, invest in R&amp;D, and build a strong community that spans across NEAR, Ethereum, and beyond.</p>



<p>“We&#8217;re proud to support the growth of Nuffle Labs as an independent company in the NEAR ecosystem. These 4 excellent co-founders have built first-rate modularity products that showcase the best of NEAR&#8217;s technology with NEAR DA and NFFL, providing cost-effective and performant solutions to projects across Web3,” said Illia Polosukhin, Co-Founder of NEAR Protocol and CEO of NEAR Foundation. “We look forward to continued collaboration with the NEAR Foundation as they expand and evolve.”</p>



<p>Avichal Garg, General Partner at lead investor Electric Capital, said, “We are excited to back Nuffle Labs, the builders behind NEAR DA and the NEAR Fast Finality Layer (NFFL). As the core team that developed these products from the ground up, Nuffle Labs has the expertise to advance these modular solutions, creating a world where intra- and interchain transactions are cheap, fast, and secure.”</p>



<p>“I have had the great privilege of getting to know the founders of Nuffle and working with them from day zero,” said Anand Iyer, General Partner at Canonical Crypto. “Their passion for solving blockchain scaling combined with their expertise from building solutions at NEAR has me genuinely excited for them and their future.”</p>



<p><strong>Understanding NEAR Data Availability (NEAR DA)</strong></p>



<p>NEAR DA utilizes the sharded architecture of NEAR Protocol to provide a modular data availability layer for Ethereum rollups with extremely high throughput and low cost. On mainnet launch, RSS3 – an open information protocol bridging AI and Web3 – experienced a substantial cost reduction, paying a daily average of $10 compared to their previous $1,000. NEAR DA currently has a throughput of 24MB/s, significantly higher than its closest competitor’s 6.67MB/s – making NEAR DA the most scalable, cheapest, and reliable DA solution on the market.</p>



<p>NEAR DA’s scalability is further enhanced by its ability to support multiple rollups, whether they are optimistic or ZK-rollups. NEAR Data Availability (NEAR DA) provides:</p>



<ul>
<li>Cost-efficiency: Storing data on NEAR Protocol is significantly cheaper than on Ethereum, making it easier for projects to build as well as faster.</li>



<li>Effortless Validation: NEAR Protocol&#8217;s trustless off-chain light client simplifies validation, ensuring accurate and reliable transactions.</li>



<li>User-Friendly Interaction: NEAR Protocol provides easy access to on-chain data through RPC, making blockchain interaction seamless for developers and users.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Exploring NEAR Fast Finality Layer (NFFL)</strong></p>



<p>The name Nuffle Labs is derived from the acronym NFFL. The Nuffle Fast Finality Layer (NFFL) is an EigenLayer Actively Validated Service (AVS) designed to aggregate state across various rollups. By leveraging NEAR DA, NFFL provides a fast, universal, and secure finality layer. It enhances block finality across different protocols and integrates additional public DA layers into the blockchain stack, paving the way for innovative cross-chain applications. NFFL is currently live on testnet––learn more <a href="https://nffl.nethermind.io/">about the protocol</a>.</p>



<p><strong>What&#8217;s next for Nuffle Labs?</strong></p>



<p>“We are thrilled about the incredible opportunity to grow and develop NEAR’s modular product offerings at Nuffle Labs,” said Altan Tutar, CEO of Nuffle Labs. The other Nuffle co-founders are Sam Wang, Firat Sertgoz, and Donovan Dall. “We deeply appreciate the support from the NEAR Foundation and are honored by the validation from such distinguished investors. Their confidence in our vision and capabilities energizes us as we continue to innovate and expand.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Looking ahead, Nuffle Labs will focus on advancing the development of the NFFL AVS on EigenLayer and further enhancing the robustness and efficiency of NEAR DA to support Ethereum’s rollup-centric future. The team is committed to furthering innovation in modular blockchain design and defragmenting the Web3 ecosystem.</p>



<p>Follow along with the Nuffle team’s progress on their <a href="http://nuff.tech/">new site here</a> and follow the <a href="https://x.com/NuffleLabs">Nuffle Labs X(Twitter) account</a>. L2 builders interested in a partnership with Nuffle or those interested in applying to work with Nuffle can get in touch via the Nuffle Labs website.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nuffle-labs/">NEAR Modular Spins Out to Become Nuffle Labs with $13M in Funding</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21409</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing *NEAR Name Tokens &#8211; Multichain, Cross-Platform Digital Identities In Web3</title>
		<link>/blog/introducing-near-name-tokens/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 13:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Following the recently announced partnership between NEAR Foundation and&#160;D3, we’re excited to introduce *NEAR Name Tokens; a multichain, cross-platform digital …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/introducing-near-name-tokens/">Introducing *NEAR Name Tokens &#8211; Multichain, Cross-Platform Digital Identities In Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Following the recently announced <a href="/blog/near-protocol-partners-with-d3-to-apply-for-near-top-level-domain/">partnership between NEAR Foundation and&nbsp;D3</a>, we’re excited to introduce *NEAR Name Tokens; a multichain, cross-platform digital identity for web3 and beyond.</p>



<p>NEAR Foundation is working with D3 to bridge the gap between traditional internet infrastructure and web3. *NEAR Name Tokens are an important step in developing the <a href="https://d3.inc/blog/educational/futureproof-your-digital-identity-how-d3-aims-to-revolutionize-your-online-persona/">futureproof, interoperable digital identities</a> that will be key to driving implementation of chain abstraction, and of developing web3 more broadly.</p>



<p><strong>Complementing the NEAR Ecosystem with *NEAR Name Tokens</strong></p>



<p>NEAR already offers a deeply integrated identity solution with named NEAR accounts. These NEAR accounts, however, are limited to use across the NEAR ecosystem.</p>



<p>*NEAR Name Tokens will offer users a comprehensive digital identity solution across the wider web3 ecosystem, while keeping NEAR front and center.</p>



<p>Users will be able to use these name tokens in a variety of ways, including:</p>



<ul>
<li>As a simplified wallet address across hundreds of different blockchain networks</li>



<li>As an infrastructure identifier across hundreds of different blockchain networks</li>



<li>As a cross-platform username across various different decentralized platforms, including DeFi, GameFi, SocialFi, SportFi and other related applications</li>



<li>As Verifiable Credentials (VCs) to platforms and services that you interact with</li>



<li>To gain access to unique benefits and rewards programs for participating in the D3 ecosystem</li>



<li>As expressions of interest for the eventual .NEAR equivalent domain on the internet</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Why *NEAR Instead of .NEAR</strong></p>



<p>*NEAR Name Tokens feature a star, or asterisk (*), between the name and extension—such as <em>you*near</em>—instead of a period (.). In part, this is because NEAR accounts already use a .NEAR extension, and we want to avoid confusion for users.</p>



<p>More importantly, however, we use *NEAR because Name Tokens are unique web3 identifiers, not real domains, and we want to avoid any confusion between these as well. For years, several naming systems across web3 have thrown around the word “domain” quite liberally, without offering any of the actual utility offered by real domains.</p>



<p>Real domains are fully integrated with the Domain Name System, the distributed service that allows users to access websites and email infrastructure with ease. Billions of internet-capable devices—such as computers, tablets, mobile phones, Internet of Things devices, and more—support the DNS and real domains without the need for specialized software or plugins.</p>



<p>Integrating web3 with DNS will be critical in bringing interoperable digital identities to web3. To that end, NEAR Foundation has partnered with D3 to apply for and obtain the .near top-level domain—like the “.org” in <em>near.org</em>—during the upcoming application period for new TLDs, the first in over a decade.</p>



<p><strong>Exclusive Early Access Period to *NEAR Name Tokens for NEAR Account Holders</strong></p>



<p>As part of our initial launch phase later this summer,, existing NEAR account holders will receive exclusive early access to their equivalent *NEAR Name Tokens. For instance, if you already have the <em>name.near</em> NEAR account registered prior to launch, you will receive exclusive access to register <em>name*near</em> for a period of 90 days before names are released for public availability.</p>



<p>Similarly, should a NEAR account be available for any new *NEAR Name Token registrations, D3 will claim it on behalf of users to ensure a uniform experience across the NEAR ecosystem. Users can <a href="https://d3.app/near">sign up for early access</a>, and you’ll be  notified you prior to the official launch of *NEAR Name Tokens later this summer</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/introducing-near-name-tokens/">Introducing *NEAR Name Tokens &#8211; Multichain, Cross-Platform Digital Identities In Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21393</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Foundation Partners with NEAT Protocol to Accelerate the Growth of AI Applications with 1 million $NEAR Delegation</title>
		<link>/blog/neat-protocol/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 12:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21390</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Foundation announces today that NEAT, a rollup protocol designed for scaling AI applications on NEAR, has received 1 million …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/neat-protocol/">NEAR Foundation Partners with NEAT Protocol to Accelerate the Growth of AI Applications with 1 million $NEAR Delegation</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR Foundation announces today that NEAT, a rollup protocol designed for scaling AI applications on NEAR, has received 1 million $NEAR token staking delegation from NEAR Foundation. All NEAR token rewards from the delegation will be redistributed to $NEAT stakers, producing approximately 120-200% APY. This funding is part of NEAR Foundation&#8217;s efforts to support AI and blockchain projects on NEAR, and to promote use cases of AI integration with blockchain technology more broadly. NEAT, as the first rollup scaling protocol to receive official support from the NEAR Foundation, will utilize these funds to attract a wider user base to its ecosystem.</p>



<p>NEAT is a rollup scaling solution built on the NEAR inscription standard, specifically designed to facilitate AI and machine-learning applications on NEAR. NEAT offers an innovative approach for rollups to be built on NEAR. With off-chain indexer nodes for execution and NEAR L1 as the data availability layer, NEAT eliminates the need for rollups to deploy smart contracts or run verification logic on the L1. This streamlined process drastically reduces transaction costs for rollups, making NEAT particularly well suited for computationally intensive applications such as AI and gaming. Additionally, NEAR Catalog, powered by NEAT, is currently developing an advanced indexer that aims to provide projects and applications in the NEAR ecosystem with cost-effective and flexible indexing and querying capabilities.</p>



<p><strong>NEAT Token and Benefits</strong><br></p>



<p>The $NEAT token exists in two forms, NRC-20 and NEP-141, with a total supply of 42 million tokens. $NEAT tokens offers the following benefits:</p>



<p>1. Stakers of $NEAT-NEP141 will receive the staking rewards generated from the 1 million $NEAR tokens provided by the Foundation. A portion of these staking rewards will also be allocated to support the exploration of AI integration with NEAT.</p>



<p>2. $NEAT-NEP141 stakers will receive a share of the fees generated from wrap/unwrap operations (currently set at 1% fee rate) and a portion of the fees from the NRC-20 marketplace.</p>



<p>3. After the decentralized indexer is operational, a portion of the indexing fees will be distributed to $NEAT-NEP141 stakers.</p>



<p>4. Holders of $NEAT-NRC20 tokens will be eligible to receive airdrops of newly minted NRC-20 tokens.</p>



<p>5. $NEAT serves as a utility token within the NEAT ecosystem, enabling services/assets payments, DeFi integration, AI governance, and more.</p>



<p><strong>The Road Ahead: Revolutionizing AI with Decentralized Indexing</strong></p>



<p><strong><br></strong>NEAT is building the first fully customizable decentralized indexer network, which allows any project to easily store data on the NEAR blockchain, deploy custom indexing logic on a decentralized set of indexer nodes, and achieve verifiable execution through zero-knowledge proofs. This approach aims to address potential failure points and attack vectors associated with centralized indexers.</p>



<p>One of the most exciting use cases for decentralized indexing is in the field of artificial intelligence. With NRC-20 and NEAT Indexers, it becomes possible to store AI data, parameters, algorithms, models, and outputs as on-chain inscriptions and integrate them with off-chain execution through zero-knowledge proofs. For instance, one can imagine creating fully open-source AI-powered games, where users participate in shaping the game&#8217;s narrative, and the history is permanently stored on-chain through inscriptions. AI agents&#8217; models, parameters, and decisions can be represented as inscribed NFTs, and their training and model parameters can be stored on-chain.</p>



<p>This combination of blockchain transparency and off-chain computational efficiency allows AI to be truly accessible and open to everyone, contributing to the development of a genuinely open network.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/neat-protocol/">NEAR Foundation Partners with NEAT Protocol to Accelerate the Growth of AI Applications with 1 million $NEAR Delegation</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21390</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unveiling new partnerships at the International Tech Summit in Bermuda</title>
		<link>/blog/international-tech-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 13:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21341</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The NEAR Foundation announced a slew of partnerships and developments at this year’s International Tech Summit in Bermuda, organized by …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/international-tech-summit/">Unveiling new partnerships at the International Tech Summit in Bermuda</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The NEAR Foundation announced a slew of partnerships and developments at this year’s International Tech Summit in Bermuda, organized by Penrose Partners.</p>



<p>The new collaborations will leverage Bermuda’s unique crypto-friendly regulatory environment to accelerate the integration of digital assets into global markets. They’ll also enhance NEAR’s role in advancing blockchain applications across sectors. From NFTs to insurance, here’s the full rundown.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-foundation-and-penrose-a-strategic-alliance-at-the-tech-summit">NEAR Foundation and Penrose: A strategic alliance at the Tech Summit</h2>



<p>As the presenting partner of the International Tech Summit, the NEAR Foundation cemented a significant relationship with Penrose Partners, a leading international digital asset advisory firm. It’s part of NEAR&#8217;s strategic effort to tap into Bermuda&#8217;s thriving crypto scene, supported by progressive regulations under the island’s Digital Asset Business Act.</p>



<p>During the summit, NEAR Foundation’s executive team and leaders from the institutional business segment were active participants, supporting various digital payment activations and Bermuda’s first-ever NFT art gallery. This engagement highlights NEAR&#8217;s commitment to exploring substantial business opportunities in Bermuda, particularly within its vast insurance sector, and strengthening its ties with local government and regulatory bodies.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-nayms-and-near-innovating-on-chain-insurance">Nayms and NEAR: Innovating on-chain insurance</h2>



<p>NEAR Foundation announced a partnership with Nayms that marks a pioneering step toward revolutionizing the insurance industry through blockchain technology. Nayms, a regulated marketplace for on-chain insurance, aligns with NEAR Foundation to develop innovative web3 products linked to insurance pools.</p>



<p>NEAR Foundation and Nayms aim to address the challenges of pricing and securing insurance for blockchain ventures, crucial to the legitimacy and growth of digital assets. As not only a leader in the regulation of digital assets but a massive global hub for insurance and reinsurance, Bermuda represents fertile ground for the collaboration.</p>



<p>The partners are setting out to transform traditional insurance models by enabling novel ways to underwrite risks associated with NEAR-based companies. The goal is to disrupt a multi-trillion-dollar market and offer institutional investors the chance to engage with new, attractive risk-adjusted investment opportunities in the field of on-chain insurance.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-mountain-protocol-and-near-foundation-expanding-digital-dollar-use">Mountain Protocol and NEAR Foundation: Expanding digital dollar use</h2>



<p>The partnership between NEAR Foundation and Mountain Protocol introduces the integration of Mountain’s USDM, a leading yield-bearing stablecoin, onto the NEAR protocol. This collaboration is set to transform how local businesses in Bermuda manage their treasuries by leveraging the stability and efficiency of digital dollars.</p>



<p>This strategic alliance enhances Bermuda&#8217;s capacity to utilize digital dollars, like USDM, within its extensive insurance and reinsurance programs. It taps into a $150 billion stablecoin market, reflecting Bermuda’s advanced digital asset regulation and its thriving financial ecosystem.</p>



<p>Additionally, NEAR Foundation will explore the potential of USDM in everyday applications, notably in partnership with HITCH, Bermuda&#8217;s leading transportation app. It’s about demonstrating how stablecoins can streamline transactions, reduce costs for drivers and riders, and showcase the practical benefits of blockchain technology in daily consumer interactions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-expanding-digital-transactions-with-hitch-and-near">Expanding digital transactions with HITCH and NEAR</h2>



<p>As mentioned, NEAR Foundation also announced a partnership with HITCH to further embed digital assets into everyday transactions. The goal is to reimagine how local businesses and consumers handle transactions by adopting US digital dollars—USDC and USDM—within HITCH’s payment systems.</p>



<p>This initiative is expected to enhance cash management for businesses and streamline payment processes, offering greater efficiency and cost savings. By reducing transaction fees, HITCH can reinvest these gains into the local economy or offer enhanced rewards to drivers and riders.</p>



<p>Beyond improving ride-sharing transactions, the collaboration is set to broaden the use of digital dollars in Bermuda. HITCH plans to enable payments for government services like vehicle licensing and payroll taxes through its app, demonstrating the broad potential of digital currencies to simplify and secure routine financial activities.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-extending-the-open-web-experience-with-mintbase-s-nft-gallery">Extending the open web experience with Mintbase’s NFT gallery</h2>



<p>Following the NEAR Foundation partnerships with Mountain Protocol and HITCH, the International Tech Summit also featured a significant venture into the world of digital art, powered by Mintbase. This event marked the debut of Bermuda&#8217;s first NFT art exhibition, curated by local art consultancy Mazar-Fox Art Consulting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Aptly named “Redefining the Boundaries Between Art and Technology” and set in the iconic cruise passenger terminal at Hamilton&#8217;s Pier Six, the exhibition featured a mix of international and Bermudian artists, as well as educational workshops on NFTs conducted by Mintbase to deepen attendees’ knowledge and engagement.</p>



<p>These sessions included practical onboarding for attendees that enabled them to create and interact with digital art firsthand. Special edition NFTs were also offered as exclusive rewards for those who purchased limited edition merchandise, further integrating the digital art experience into the summit’s framework and enhancing the interactive nature of the gallery.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-closing-thoughts-bermuda-as-a-nexus-of-digital-innovation">Closing thoughts: Bermuda as a nexus of digital innovation</h2>



<p>The International Tech Summit highlighted Bermuda’s pivotal role as a hub for digital asset regulation and innovation—and it set the stage for significant advancements in blockchain applications.</p>



<p>The partnerships announced between NEAR Foundation and key players like Penrose, Nayms, Mountain Protocol, HITCH, and Mintbase are important steps toward integrating digital assets and the open web into everyday business and consumer practices.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/international-tech-summit/">Unveiling new partnerships at the International Tech Summit in Bermuda</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21341</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Innovative Alliance Marks Milestone That Drives Digital Finance </title>
		<link>/blog/innovative-alliance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 15:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21336</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Today NEAR Foundation announced a partnership with Lulo X and Peersyst Technology. The goal of the collaboration is to redefine …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/innovative-alliance/">Innovative Alliance Marks Milestone That Drives Digital Finance </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Today NEAR Foundation announced a partnership with Lulo X and Peersyst Technology. The goal of the collaboration is to redefine the parameters of digital finance by offering a secure, stable digital currency that broadens economic perspectives within Web3. As a result, Lulo X users will enjoy greater autonomy and less friction over their finances.</p>



<p>Lulo X, a pioneering Colombian fintech firm, is on a mission to challenge financial barriers and help users build a better future. This partnership will leverage NEAR Protocol&#8217;s innovative blockchain technology to facilitate seamless and secure transactions, while also building their native stablecoin on the NEAR blockchain.</p>



<p><em>“We are building a financial infrastructure that is characterized by its ease of use and robust security. We want to improve the most basic financial activities, ensuring digital transactions and making financial tools accessible to everyone,”</em> says <strong>Natalia Jiménez</strong>, CEO of Lulo X.</p>



<p>Peersyst Technology brings its expertise in blockchain implementation to ensure the robustness of the platform. Together with NEAR, the two organizations will create cutting-edge solutions that simplify the complexities of digital finance, offering users more control over their economic activities.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-expanding-financial-horizons-with-lulo-x">Expanding Financial Horizons with Lulo X</h2>



<p>Lulo X&#8217;s commitment, as articulated by CEO Natalia Jiménez, is to dismantle financial barriers through a platform noted for its ease of use, security, and democratization of finance.</p>



<p>“We are at the forefront of a new era where technology powers sustainability in finance. Partnering with the NEAR Foundation is a step towards redefining digital finance to be secure, inclusive and democratic. This alliance is the key to a future where financial empowerment is a universal right. We are committed to a future that is not only prosperous but sustainable, aligning financial growth with the well-being of our planet,&#8221; Jiménez says.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This collaboration with NEAR will amplify the security and efficiency of transactions, integrating biometric safeguards and fraud prevention measures that underline Lulo X&#8217;s dedication to user protection. It’s founded on principles of financial education, regulatory cooperation, and innovative infrastructure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NEAR&#8217;s advanced blockchain technology supports Lulo X&#8217;s vision, facilitating the development of tailored financial products that foster informed decision-making and economic inclusion. The Lulo X stablecoin on NEAR is a major step in that direction.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ensuring-success-with-peersyst-technology">Ensuring Success with Peersyst Technology</h2>



<p>Peersyst Technology will also be instrumental in implementing the NEAR Protocol&#8217;s innovative stablecoin solutions, bringing a wealth of experience in blockchain projects. Their technical prowess ensures that the infrastructure developed with Lulo X is not only scalable but also robust enough to handle the complexities of real-world financial applications.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Peersyst&#8217;s commitment to the development of blockchain-powered currencies and payment systems, especially in Latin America, has been unwavering. Our collaboration with leading protocols is a testament to the maturity of the technology, paving the way for its widespread adoption in finance.” highlights Ferran Prat, CEO of Peersyst.</p>



<p>This partnership leverages Peersyst&#8217;s blockchain expertise to ensure the stable and efficient operation of financial solutions. By integrating cutting-edge blockchain technology with NEAR&#8217;s platform, Peersyst facilitates the creation of financial services that are both secure and user-friendly, enhancing the overall reliability of the system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Their contribution is vital for developing a framework that supports high transaction volumes and complex data security requirements, essential for fostering trust and widespread adoption among users.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-near-ecosystem-continues-to-broaden-fintech">The NEAR Ecosystem Continues to Broaden Fintech</h2>



<p>The partnerships between NEAR, Lulo X, and Peersyst Technology aims to introduce robust, scalable financial solutions that make economic activities more accessible and efficient.</p>



<p>&#8220;This partnership with Lulo X and Peersyst is a step forward in harnessing Stablecoins for fast and cost-effective payments. It reflects our mutual goal of democratizing financial access and expanding NEAR&#8217;s presence in Latin America. The high performance and low fees of the NEAR Protocol are poised to deliver unparalleled benefits for Web3 users and applications, catalyzing stablecoin-based payment solutions in the region.&#8221;</p>



<p>The partnership is a sign of major progress in fintech. By providing the platform and resources for innovations like savings in digital dollars and – bolstered by Peersyst and the NEAR blockchain – the intersection of finance and the open web will become more safe, fair, and inclusive.</p>



<p></p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/innovative-alliance/">Innovative Alliance Marks Milestone That Drives Digital Finance </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21336</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Launches Infrastructure Committee with $4 Million in Funding </title>
		<link>/blog/near-launches-infrastructure-committee/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR has seen a massive surge in users and transactions over the last few months. It’s important to have a …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-launches-infrastructure-committee/">NEAR Launches Infrastructure Committee with $4 Million in Funding </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR has seen a massive surge in users and transactions over the last few months. It’s important to have a smooth-running blockchain for project and founder expansion. Today, the NEAR Foundation launches the Infrastructure Committee, a new initiative aimed to strengthen NEAR&#8217;s Key Infrastructure. With $4 million earmarked for infrastructure projects, the initiative is meant to support the success of NEAR projects while distributing funds and sourcing projects in an open, transparent way.</p>



<p>What is Key Infrastructure? It includes RPC nodes, relayers, indexers, bridges, wallets, load balancers, and oracles. Also, NEAR should be listed correctly on all the DEX tools available. Incidents and outages need to be easily reported and fixed.</p>



<p><strong>The committee is made up of  ecosystem leaders and NEAR partners from across core NEAR orgs. Its goals are to:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Decentralize decision-making</li>



<li>Enhance critical infrastructure</li>



<li>Streamline efforts for greater clarity and decentralization</li>
</ul>



<p>The committee primarily focuses on proposals, with multiple Requests For Proposals (RFPs) planned to meet important ecosystem needs. These proposals will undergo review and asynchronous voting by the committee.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-progress-of-the-infrastructure-committee">Progress of the Infrastructure Committee</h2>



<p><strong>The Infrastructure Committee has already funded five critical infrastructure proposals:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Jutsu IDE infrastructure implementation (AI development environment)</li>



<li>FASTNEAR infrastructure services (new RPC nodes and custom endpoints)</li>



<li>Aurora Web 3.0 Wallet Support Services</li>



<li>The building of a Treasury App for use by governing committees</li>



<li>An audit of the Ledger integrations</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>The committee also inherited some projects that it will now actively manage:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Aurora RPC SpeedUp</li>



<li>MyNEARWallet maintenance by Meteor</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>With over half of the allocated $4 million budget remaining, there is an open invitation to the community to bring forward innovative infrastructure projects such as:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Faster RPC Nodes</li>



<li>Specific common endpoints to replace broad RPC queries</li>



<li>New bridges to improve cross-chain transactions and increase the number of chains supported</li>



<li>ICANN-compliant DNS and expansion of top-level domains</li>



<li>Focused relayers to support gas-free and other specialized relayer needs</li>
</ul>



<p>The committee encourages community members to contribute their ideas, proposals, and feedback, and welcomes a range of perspectives from founders, developers, and NEAR enthusiasts on how to improve the foundations of NEAR technology.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>The current Infrastructure Committee is comprised of the following members:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Abhishek Vaidyanathan, NEAR Foundation (serving as a non-voting meeting Chair)</li>



<li>Alex Shevchenko, Aurora Labs</li>



<li>Bowen Wang, Director of Protocol, Pagoda</li>



<li>Vlad Frolov, DevHub</li>



<li>Sandi Fatic, Calimero</li>



<li>Eric Winer, Pagoda</li>



<li>Illia Polosukhin, NEAR Foundation (serving as an ad-hoc member on an as-needed basis)</li>



<li>Christopher Donovan, NEAR Foundation (serving as an ad-hoc member on an as-needed basis)</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>The Working Group comprises the following admins and advisors:</strong><strong><br></strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Project Oversight &#8211; Konrad Merino, Head of Blockchain Success, NEAR Foundation</li>



<li>Product Manager &#8211; Gautham Ravi, Sr. Product Manager, Pagoda</li>



<li>Project Manager &#8211; Trentin C Bergeron, Sr. Technical Program Manager, Pagoda</li>



<li>Technical BD &#8211; Vikas Pandey, Success &amp; Partner Engineering, NEAR Foundation</li>



<li>Technical Advisor &#8211; Robert Tsia, SRE Manager, Pagoda</li>



<li>Technical Advisor &#8211; Ernesto Cejas Padilla, Sr. SRE, Pagoda</li>



<li>Technical Advisor &#8211; Firat Sertgoz, Engineering Manager, Pagoda</li>



<li>Technical Advisor &#8211; Patrick Engvall, Sr. Engineer, Pagoda</li>



<li>Technical Advisor &#8211; Pierre Leguen, Software Engineer, NEAR Foundation Finance</li>



<li>Broadcast MC &amp; Project Advisor &#8211; Marcus Ribeiro, Ecosystem Relations, NEAR Foundation</li>
</ul>



<p>For those looking to participate, the <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/wiki/Proposal-Process-%E2%80%90-Team">Interim Proposal and Funding Process</a> provides a comprehensive guide on how to submit proposals. To foster transparency and public engagement, the committee has established clear processes to track and discuss proposals openly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The community can view the <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1sjUgUnY_Ufw8RjfUFj5K2RM6gYC3XBRVu1iYXzD3cBQ/edit?usp=sharing">public tracking of proposals</a> document and participate in <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/discussions">public discussions</a>, including announcements of Requests for Proposals (RFPs). The committee’s meeting notes will be shared with the community to maintain openness about the committee&#8217;s decisions and discussions.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-engaging-the-community-and-fostering-collaboration">Engaging the Community and Fostering Collaboration</h2>



<p>To facilitate community engagement, anyone interested can join the <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/discussions">discussion</a> on the Github repo, which will serve as the hub for suggestions, collaboration, and support among members interested in contributing to NEAR infrastructure.<br></p>



<p>The <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/wiki/Infrastructure-Committee">Infrastructure Mandate &amp; Charter</a> and <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/wiki/Infrastructure-Working-Group">Working Group Details</a> will offer additional insights into the committee’s mission, structure, and ongoing projects. These resources are designed to educate and inspire community members to contribute their skills and ideas towards building a more robust and scalable NEAR ecosystem.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-future-plans-for-the-near-infrastructure-committee">Future Plans for the NEAR Infrastructure Committee</h2>



<p>As NEAR continues to grow, so will the necessity for robust infrastructure to support an increasing number of transactions and users. Future enhancements include the introduction of a more sophisticated incident management system and post-mortem processes for infrastructure outages.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The development of a Blockchain Operating System (BOS)-based app for proposal management will be another significant move towards optimizing the efficiency of the funding process. This upgrade will streamline the proposal and funding workflow, making it easier for community members to submit and manage their projects.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The committee’s work will also support NEAR’s growth and chain abstraction efforts, ensuring the blockchain can handle the anticipated surge in traffic as more users join the ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Those interested in getting involved with the Infrastructure Committee can join the <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/discussions">Working Group Discussion on GitHub</a> to collaborate on initiatives, discuss proposals and RFPs, or ask questions.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-launches-infrastructure-committee/">NEAR Launches Infrastructure Committee with $4 Million in Funding </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21321</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Ecosystem Kicks Up a Sandstorm at TOKEN2049 Dubai</title>
		<link>/blog/near-ecosystem-kicks-up-a-sandstorm-at-token2049-dubai/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21312</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>After making waves at last year&#8217;s Singapore edition, we&#8217;re turning up the heat for TOKEN2049 in Dubai, the city that&#8217;s …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-ecosystem-kicks-up-a-sandstorm-at-token2049-dubai/">NEAR Ecosystem Kicks Up a Sandstorm at TOKEN2049 Dubai</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>After making waves at last year&#8217;s Singapore edition, we&#8217;re turning up the heat for TOKEN2049 in Dubai, the city that&#8217;s rapidly becoming a hotbed for Fintech and AI innovation. This year, the NEAR ecosystem is buzzing with excitement to introduce discussions on chain abstraction and spotlight some of our most dynamic projects, including Calimero, Sweat Economy, and Aurora, to the forefront of the global tech scene.</em></p>



<p><strong>Tech, Coffee, &amp; Bubbles!</strong><br></p>



<p>By day, make your way to our booth to engage with the NEAR collective and the visionaries from Calimero, Sweat Economy, and Aurora. Unpack the ways we&#8217;re transforming the Web3 space with breakthroughs in chain abstraction, data availability, frameworks for building decentralized application protocols, and Blockchain as a Service (BaaS). Indulge in the flavors of traditional Arabic coffee and pick up the hottest swag.<br></p>



<p>Yet, the experience doesn&#8217;t stop at coffee.<br></p>



<p>As the enthusiastic sponsor of TOKEN2049 Dubai&#8217;s closing party, NEAR is preparing an unforgettable evening. Anticipate a gala filled with select champagne and spirits, celebrating the milestones and fellowship of the Web3 community.</p>



<p><strong>Can&#8217;t-Miss Speaking Engagements</strong></p>



<p>At TOKEN2049 Dubai, NEAR Protocol is diving into the conversations that are shaping the future of Web3. We&#8217;re kicking things off with a panel on &#8220;AI x Web3: Pioneering Decentralized Intelligence,&#8221; featuring NEAR&#8217;s own Illia Polosukhin alongside experts like Ahmad Shadid from io.net, Niraj Pant of Ritual, Sean Ren of Sahara, and moderated by Tarun Chitra of Gauntlet. They&#8217;ll unpack the exciting crossroads of AI and Web3 in fostering decentralized intelligence. Then, don&#8217;t miss our fireside chat, &#8220;Sweat Economy&#8217;s Billion-User Blueprint for Scaling Consumer Crypto Apps,&#8221; where Chris Donovan, COO of NEAR Foundation and Oleg Fomenko, Co-founder &amp; CEO of&nbsp; Sweat Economy open up about their ground-breaking collaboration.</p>



<p>Swing by our booth for a firsthand look at how NEAR is redefining norms with chain abstraction, data availability, and more—all powered by a healthy dose of caffeine.<br><br>TOKEN2049 is gearing up to be a dynamic assembly featuring the forefront of Web3 innovation, an event you won&#8217;t want to miss. For updates on our activities, side events, and speakers, please visit our <a href="https://lu.ma/d1mzjpw3">Lu.ma</a> page and the <a href="https://week.token2049.com/">TOKEN2049</a> landing page!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-ecosystem-kicks-up-a-sandstorm-at-token2049-dubai/">NEAR Ecosystem Kicks Up a Sandstorm at TOKEN2049 Dubai</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21312</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Korea BUIDL Week Recap: One Account to Rule Them All</title>
		<link>/blog/korea-buidl-week-recap-one-account-to-rule-them-all/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 05:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Last week, Korea BUIDL Week was the epicenter of cutting-edge thought leadership in Web3. From cross-chain innovations to the convergence …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/korea-buidl-week-recap-one-account-to-rule-them-all/">Korea BUIDL Week Recap: One Account to Rule Them All</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Last week, Korea BUIDL Week was the epicenter of cutting-edge thought leadership in Web3. From cross-chain innovations to the convergence of AI and blockchain, the week brought together industry pioneers to explore the technologies shaping the decentralized future.</p>



<p><strong>Chain Abstraction Day Tackles Interoperability</strong></p>



<p>Chain Abstraction Day kicked Korea BUIDL Week off by tackling the need for seamless blockchain interoperability. NEAR’s Co-founder and CEO, Illia Polosukhin, made a compelling case for &#8220;Why Web3 Needs Chain Abstraction&#8221; by highlighting how abstracting away individual chains can unlock Web3&#8217;s full potential. Mike Purvis of Proximity Labs then painted a vision of &#8220;Ushering in the Era of Bridgeless Cross-Chain DeFi,&#8221; while Riqi Ras presented &#8220;Bitcoin Beyond Gold&#8221;, showcasing snippets of a testnet transaction where a NEAR account signed transactions on Bitcoin. This proof-of-concept highlighted the potential of chain signatures to not just interact with Bitcoin, but even enable trading of Bitcoin Ordinals natively using the cross-chain signing capabilities.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Blockchain Brain Trust: Vitalik Envisions Account Abstraction, Illia Unleashes Chain Signatures</strong></p>



<p>At BUIDL Asia, anticipation was high for Vitalik Buterin&#8217;s talk on &#8220;The Future of Account Abstraction.&#8221; By abstracting user accounts, he explored enabling frictionless cross-chain experiences. “The next 10 years are going to be about really upgrading the ecosystem at the user level,” Buterin said at the event. Illia Polosukhin then took center stage, announcing NEAR&#8217;s groundbreaking &#8220;Chain Signatures&#8221; for managing assets across chains via a single account. Illia demonstrated how Chain Signatures allow signing transactions on multiple chains from a single NEAR account, paving the way for seamless cross-chain dApp development.</p>



<p>Illia and Vitalik later joined forces for a can&#8217;t-miss fireside chat dissecting the &#8220;AI/Crypto Fact vs Fiction.&#8221; As two towering minds in their respective fields, they offered unparalleled insights into AI&#8217;s transformative potential for Web3. The lively discussion separated hype from reality, exploring how AI could enhance privacy, scalability, and usability of decentralized systems. Vitalik and Illia also examined the risks of centralized AI models and the importance of developing decentralized AI aligned with Web3&#8217;s core values.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1200" src="/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-21317" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image.jpeg 1600w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-300x225.jpeg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-1024x768.jpeg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-768x576.jpeg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-1536x1152.jpeg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure>



<p><strong>ETH Seoul Dives Deep into Chain Signatures and Decentralized Intelligence</strong></p>



<p>The event baton was then passed to ETH Seoul, where Mike Purvis expounded on &#8220;Chain Signatures: Cross-Chain Without Bridges.&#8221; Purvis explained how this technology enables secure cross-chain communication, eliminating the need for centralized bridges. He demonstrated how it could pave the way for seamless blockchain interoperability and conducted a workshop showcasing potential use cases.&nbsp; Boris Polania made a case for &#8220;Decentralized Intelligence&#8221;&nbsp; discussing how combining blockchain transparency with AI data analysis could revolutionize collective decision-making processes. The conference featured comprehensive developer tracks put together by DevHub, covering everything from building on NEAR to integrating Chain Signatures. ETH Seoul also hosted a hackathon where teams built innovative decentralized apps, with members of the NEAR ecosystem serving as judges to evaluate and provide feedback on the projects.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DeFiBrain, an AI-powered DeFi investment assistant that harnesses NEAR to discover and analyze promising DeFi products, won NEAR&#8217;s Chain Signatures bounty and ETH Seoul&#8217;s first prize. DeFiBrain impressed with its advanced AI models and seamless NEAR integration. The first prize of $5,000 for the NEARDevHub&#8217;s &#8220;AI Governance is NEAR&#8221; bounty was awarded to Connor AI, which integrates AI into DAOs to automate execution processes and empower decentralized decision-making. Connor AI was commended for its novel AI-DAO approach.</p>



<p><strong>Vitalik Outlines Ethereum&#8217;s Scaling Roadmap, Illia Tackles AI Misconceptions</strong></p>



<p>Not to be outdone, Vitalik outlined his vision for Ethereum&#8217;s future in &#8220;Dencun: Where We Go From Here.&#8221; During his talk, he primarily focused on EIP 4844, also known as “Blobs”, which represents a significant upgrade for Ethereum scaling. This upgrade allows Layer 2 networks to post batched transactions at a much lower cost. Consequently, Vitalik issued a call-to-action, encouraging developers to build solutions for today&#8217;s needs. Closing the event, Illia Polosukhin delivered a talk cheekily titled &#8220;Secrets About AI that Web3 Doesn&#8217;t Want You To Know,&#8221; likely pulling back the curtain on AI&#8217;s game-changing implications. Illia&#8217;s provocative talk challenged misconceptions about the limitations of current AI while hinting at potential breakthroughs that could supercharge decentralized applications.</p>



<p><strong>SheFi Emphasizes Cultivating Inclusive Web3 Communities</strong></p>



<p>Finally, SheFi spotlighted building inclusive Web3 communities. NEAR&#8217;s Yadira Blocker led the discussion on cultivating Web3 culture and community &#8211; a critical topic as the ecosystem grows. The panel emphasized genuine communities are earned through authentic connections, not purchased. It also discussed how global Web3 communities localize efforts while valuing in-person meetups to drive progress collaboratively. Unlike Web2, community heavily influences Web3 marketing and adoption.</p>



<p>From multi-chain architectures to AI convergence, Korea BUIDL Week demonstrated that Web3 is rapidly evolving towards a future of seamless cross-chain functionality, enhanced intelligence, and open participation. The insights shared will undoubtedly help shape the coming decades of decentralized innovation.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/korea-buidl-week-recap-one-account-to-rule-them-all/">Korea BUIDL Week Recap: One Account to Rule Them All</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21306</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>LiNEAR Protocol Introduces Omnichain Liquid Restaking to Advance NEAR’s Chain Abstraction </title>
		<link>/blog/linear-protocol-introduces-omnichain-liquid-restaking/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 02:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21300</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>LiNEAR, the leading DeFi protocol on NEAR with the highest TVL, is planning to enhance the security of NEAR&#8217;s Chain …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/linear-protocol-introduces-omnichain-liquid-restaking/">LiNEAR Protocol Introduces Omnichain Liquid Restaking to Advance NEAR’s Chain Abstraction </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://linearprotocol.org/">LiNEAR</a>, the leading DeFi protocol on <a href="https://near.org/">NEAR</a> with the highest TVL, is planning to enhance the security of NEAR&#8217;s Chain Abstracted network through restaking, ensuring a secure future for a chain-agnostic and chain-abstracted Web3 experience. Established by early core contributors to NEAR, LiNEAR has made significant contributions to advancing the ecosystem, beginning with its innovative liquid staking features, notably the Automatic Validator Optimization Algorithm. This algorithm greatly improves the security and decentralization of the NEAR network by dynamically reallocating stakes across as many as 200 active nodes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>LiNEAR’s vision has always been enabling easier participation in the decentralized web. With the NEAR ecosystem&#8217;s commitment to advancing Chain Abstraction by removing the complexities of blockchain technology for users, LiNEAR is also expanding its offering and focusing on restaking to eliminate barriers to entry for the multichain ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>LiNEAR Protocol will be providing a robust security model through <strong>omnichain liquid restaking</strong>, avoiding the pitfalls of centralized and permissioned solutions in pursuit of an improved Web3 user experience. Restaking can potentially secure Chain Abstraction infrastructures for three key reasons: it offers instant security by leveraging existing blockchain security mechanisms; ensures capital efficiency by allowing nodes and stakers of a blockchain to participate with minimal additional capital; and promotes base layer alignment, closely bonding the networks with the blockchains which they serve.</p>



<p>NEAR‘s Chain Abstraction comprises social authentication, <a href="/blog/unlocking-web3-usability-with-account-aggregation/">account aggregation</a>, Chain Signatures, and the multichain intent relayer. These elements combine to allow users to transact across various blockchains using a single account and interface, without the need to understand the underlying infrastructure or switch networks.</p>



<p>To realize this vision, two new decentralized infrastructures are required: the <a href="/blog/chain-signatures-launch-to-enable-transactions-on-any-blockchain-from-a-near-account/">Chain Signatures</a> MPC network and the Multichain Gas Relayer. The Chain Signatures MPC network functions as a decentralized signer of users’ NEAR accounts, controlling all other accounts on different blockchains. The Multichain Gas Relayer consists of off-chain relayers that listen to and compete to execute users&#8217; intents on different chains. Both infrastructures operate externally to any existing blockchain, including NEAR.</p>



<p>LiNEAR&#8217;s liquid restaking solution aims to secure the Chain Signatures MPC network, mitigating the risks of centralization. Similarly, the Multichain Gas Relayer would be able to operate in a trustless manner with restaked verification, removing embedded trust assumptions and enabling users to confidently delegate executions to the relayer network. This entire security framework can be supported by $NEAR and $LiNEAR, and other assets such as $SOL, $BTC, and more in the future, ensuring alignment with different blockchains connected through Chain Abstraction.</p>



<p>NEAR community members interested in restaking can get started on <a href="https://linearprotocol.org/">LiNEAR</a> and help move the network towards a more secure and easy-to-use Web3 world.</p>



<p><strong>About LiNEAR</strong></p>



<p>LiNEAR Protocol is an innovative omnichain liquidity staking/restaking platform and the leading DeFi protocol on NEAR. It pioneered revolutionary features such as automatic validator optimization, which significantly decentralizes and secures the network by allowing users to re-delegate to 200+ validators. LiNEAR offers seamless multichain restaking across multiple networks, such as NEAR, Ethereum, Bitcoin, Solana, and more, ensuring a secure future for a chain-agnostic and chain-abstracted Web3 experience.</p>



<p>Join LiNEAR’s Community</p>



<p><a href="https://linearprotocol.org/">Website</a> | <a href="https://twitter.com/LinearProtocol">Twitter</a> | <a href="https://medium.com/@LiNEAR_LSD">Medium</a> | <a href="https://discord.com/invite/bkkvWwMf2T">Discord</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/linear-protocol-introduces-omnichain-liquid-restaking/">LiNEAR Protocol Introduces Omnichain Liquid Restaking to Advance NEAR’s Chain Abstraction </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21300</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
