<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Community Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/category/community/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/category/community/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 15:49:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Community Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/category/community/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">234542837</site>	<item>
		<title>NEAR Foundation and Delphi Labs Partner to Launch New AI Accelerator</title>
		<link>/blog/delphi-labs-ai-accelerator/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 15:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[User-Owned AI]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21548</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The NEAR Foundation and Delphi Labs are pleased to announce the first cohort of their joint AI Accelerator Program, a …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/delphi-labs-ai-accelerator/">NEAR Foundation and Delphi Labs Partner to Launch New AI Accelerator</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The NEAR Foundation and Delphi Labs are pleased to announce the first cohort of their joint AI Accelerator Program, a strategic initiative designed to support and rapidly scale high-potential projects building at the intersection of AI and Web3.</p>



<p>The selected teams will benefit from a comprehensive support package, including technical guidance, funding opportunities, and access to NEAR and Delphi’s expert networks. Each team will also receive $50,000 in compute credits from Aethir, the accelerator program’s premier compute partner. These credits will ensure that every team has the necessary computational resources to develop and deploy resource-intensive AI models—and focus on building without being constrained by infrastructure limitations.</p>



<p>Beginning October 15 and running through early December, NEAR Foundation and Delphi Labs have selected the following cohort teams:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><a href="https://hyper.space/"><strong>Hyperspace</strong></a>: Hyperspace is building a decentralized, peer-to-peer AI network. Their mission is to create a unified platform for AI interactions through a &#8220;generative browser&#8221; serving as a unified interface for AI-powered web interactions.
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Selection notes:</strong> Hyperspace has demonstrated traction with over 7,000 unique nodes in their P2P network and a robust product suite, most recently launching <a href="https://play.hyper.space/">Play</a>, a generative browser agent.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><a href="https://almanak.co/"><strong>Almanak</strong></a>: Almanak is an end-to-end platform to build, test, train, optimize, and deploy agents for DeFi. Their mission is to democratize access to sophisticated financial strategies through the use of AI agents.
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Selection notes:</strong> Almanak&#8217;s team has spent the last two years building a platform that uses agent-based simulations to optimize on-chain strategies. Their agents are already managing sizable AUM for institutional partners, demonstrating strong traction and expertise in their domain.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><a href="https://www.questflow.ai/"><strong>Questflow</strong></a>: Building a next-generation AI agent economy, Questflow is developing a decentralized network that orchestrates multi-agent AI automation. Users can dispatch incentives to both AI and human workers, creating a collaborative environment for autonomous and human-assisted processes.
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Selection notes:</strong> Questflow aims to dominate the AI agentic workflow market, particularly in SEO. Their gamified reward system and strong focus on winning specific verticals make them a standout candidate for advancing AI automation workflows.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><a href="https://www.qstarlabs.ai/"><strong>Q Star Labs</strong></a>: Q Star Labs is developing a decentralized generative AI protocol for creating interactive, autonomous AI influencers at scale. Their Reinforcement Learning-based algorithm, Q STAR, is designed for long-term strategic planning to optimize AI content generation and engagement.
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Selection notes:</strong> The Q Star Labs team has a unique blend of expertise in AI, crypto, and finance, launching AI influencers that have organically grown to over 27,000 followers.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><a href="https://zettablock.com/"><strong>ZettaBlock</strong></a><strong>:</strong> ZettaBlock is laying the groundwork for open and trustless AI development through a decentralized platform that provides developers with the infrastructure needed to unify on-chain and off-chain data. By offering modular, adaptable data solutions, ZettaBlock empowers the AI economy with the tools needed to integrate both historical and real-time data from multiple sources.
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Selection notes</strong><strong>: </strong>ZettaBlock’s leadership in both AI and data infrastructure makes them a pivotal player in the future of decentralized AI. They’re already supporting major protocols like EigenLayer and Chainlink. Their vision for a unified AI data platform aligns perfectly with NEAR Foundation and Delphi’s mission to foster open and scalable AI infrastructure that developers can rely on.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><a href="https://www.joinmagic.ai/"><strong>Magic</strong></a><strong>: </strong>Magic is redefining how private data is used in AI. Their decentralized platform allows companies and developers to train AI models using private data, all while preserving the integrity and privacy of the underlying information. This is achieved through an innovative stack of privacy protocols and decentralized coordination.
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Selection notes</strong><strong>: </strong>Magic is tackling one of the toughest challenges in AI—privacy-preserving data access. Their team, with deep roots at Stanford AI Lab, has developed unique methods to keep data secure while enabling AI innovation at scale. Their ability to unlock private data for developers, without compromising security, makes Magic an essential piece of the decentralized AI puzzle.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><a href="https://www.dfusion.ai/"><strong>dFusion</strong></a><strong>: </strong>dFusion is building a platform to solve one of AI’s biggest hurdles: reliable data quality. They’re focused on creating a consensus-driven framework that curates and validates high-quality data, ensuring that AI models are trained on information that is accurate, corroborated, and trustworthy.
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Selection notes</strong><strong>: </strong>dFusion’s commitment to consensus-based knowledge curation sets them apart from other players in the data space. By focusing on data integrity and consensus, they’re creating a unique foundation for AI development—one that ensures reliability and transparency. Their work opens up new opportunities for building AI applications that need trustworthy data, which is critical as decentralized AI continues to evolve.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><a href="https://www.perilabs.net/"><strong>Peri Labs</strong></a>: Peri Labs is building an open marketplace leveraging underutilized computational resources across billions of consumer devices to power optimized AI models. The Peri Protocol abstracts the complexity of diverse hardware ecosystems, enabling seamless AI model deployment at scale.
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Selection notes</strong><strong>: </strong>Peri Labs differentiates itself with a focus on edge compute, uniquely integrating idle resources from consumer-grade devices to run AI models effectively. Their emphasis on model compression, optimization, and decentralized inference positions them as pioneers in making edge AI truly scalable, providing an efficient, privacy-preserving alternative to centralized cloud solutions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>



<p>In addition to the resources above, the NEAR x Delphi AI Accelerator Program includes some more unique opportunities for participants:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Industry-leading speakers</strong>: Participants will hear from founders, investors, and experts from AI and Web3, providing insights into current trends and future opportunities. </li>
</ul>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>IRL Founder Retreat</strong>: An in-person retreat week in New York City for networking, collaboration, and team-building.</li>



<li><strong>Closing Demo Day</strong>: The program will conclude with a Demo Day in early December, showcasing participating teams to our extensive investor network.</li>
</ul>



<p>NEAR is a leading blockchain platform designed to accelerate the development of decentralized applications with a focus on usability and scalability. Delphi Labs is a research and development firm that specializes in Web3 and DeFi.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NEAR and Delphi Labs share the common strategic vision of a user-owned AI ecosystem, built on Web3 rails, that provides genuinely better alternatives to developers and users than the prevailing model of centralized AI controlled by big tech companies and governments. The goal is to maximize the benefits of AI for people and communities—and minimize the potential risks—by putting the power of AI where it belongs: in the hands of users.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The NEAR ecosystem is quickly becoming the go-to home for decentralized, User-Owned AI, and this new AI Accelerator Program with Delphi Labs is a critical step toward integrating projects with significant potential into that ecosystem, setting the stage for the next generation of AI-powered decentralized apps.</p>



<p>NEAR’s first AI x Web3 incubator cohort, which ran from June to August 2024, saw participants achieve significant early milestones while contributing essential pieces to the growing User-Owned AI stack. These milestones include: <a href="https://hyperbolic.xyz/">Hyperbolic</a> hosting the latest open source AI models, including Llama 3.1 405B; <a href="https://mizu.global/">Mizu</a> launching their beta platform and attracting 20K users in the first week; and <a href="https://cryptopond.xyz/">Pond</a> launching their first GNN model for wallet predictions and achieving a 20% prediction rate. The teams have built on the momentum from the incubator to attract serious seed funding interest, collectively raising $26M, with Hyperbolic successfully closing a $7M round.</p>



<p>Stay tuned for details on the cohort’s Demo Day, which will take place on December 14. Teams with a strong vision for decentralized AI applications and infrastructure are encouraged to <a href="https://www.hzn.xyz/">apply</a> for the next accelerator program cohort to take place early next year.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/delphi-labs-ai-accelerator/">NEAR Foundation and Delphi Labs Partner to Launch New AI Accelerator</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21548</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>At the Intersection of AI x Web3</title>
		<link>/blog/token2049/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 15:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21528</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Get ready for a September to remember! Join NEAR at Token2049 Singapore as we showcase the seamless integration of cutting-edge …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/token2049/">At the Intersection of AI x Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Get ready for a September to remember! Join NEAR at Token2049 Singapore as we showcase the seamless integration of cutting-edge technologies shaping the future of Web3. This month, we&#8217;re not just talking about AI and chain abstraction as separate entities—we&#8217;re demonstrating how these crucial components of the modern tech stack work in harmony to create powerful, scalable, and user-centric decentralized systems.</p>



<p>Don’t forget to visit us near the Main Stage during Token2049 at Booth #P28 + P29. Our team, along with partners SWEAT, Proximity Labs, and Aurora, will be on hand to answer questions and engage with the community.</p>



<p><strong>Showcasing the Synergy: AI and Chain Abstraction in Action</strong></p>



<p>The intersection of AI and blockchain is no longer a distant future—it&#8217;s happening now, and NEAR is at the forefront. Our packed Token2049 week kicks off with the HELLO [AI] First Token Party on September 16th, where we&#8217;ll be exploring the next frontier of AI-Powered Blockchain Applications. Expect mind-bending discussions on topics like AI-driven smart contracts, decentralized machine learning marketplaces, and the tokenization of AI models.</p>



<p>Following this, we dive deep into the technical challenges and opportunities at The Scaling AI Summit (September 16-17). Here, NEAR&#8217;s co-founder, Alex Skidanov, will deliver a keynote focusing on the fundamental building blocks of user-owned AI, a concept at the forefront of NEAR’s vision. He&#8217;ll explore how this approach is reshaping the landscape of artificial intelligence and empowering users in unprecedented ways.But NEAR&#8217;s involvement goes far beyond a single keynote. Throughout the summit, we&#8217;re showcasing how our innovative approach to chain abstraction is revolutionizing the integration of AI models across diverse blockchain architectures. From optimizing cross-chain AI computations to enabling seamless data sharing for federated learning, NEAR is paving the way for a new era of scalable, interoperable AI-blockchain solutions.</p>



<p><strong>NEAR is Booked &amp; Busy</strong></p>



<p>September 17th stands out as a day packed with groundbreaking events:</p>



<p>1. Open #AI House: We&#8217;re not just talking about AI; we&#8217;re democratizing it. NEAR joins a panel on &#8220;Let&#8217;s Democratize AI&#8221; featuring industry leaders discussing how NEAR&#8217;s open-source ethos is reshaping the AI landscape.</p>



<p>2. NEAR AI Tech Showcase: Get ready for a deep dive into our latest AI innovations. We&#8217;ll demonstrate how our chain abstraction techniques are enabling more efficient training and deployment of AI models on-chain.</p>



<p>3. Modular &amp; L2 Day | TOKEN2049 Singapore: Vikas Pandey from NEAR Foundation will be shedding light on how our modular approach is revolutionizing blockchain customization and optionality.</p>



<p>4. Chain Abstraction X DeFi Brunch: Join us for a delicious brunch and discover how NEARy is simplifying DeFi interactions, making it easier than ever to hold many assets from different chains on one wallet.</p>



<p>5. From September 17-19, NEAR Singapore is hosting a 3-day SkyPool Lounge &amp; Party during TOKEN2049 Singapore. This isn&#8217;t just a networking event; it&#8217;s a technical showcase. Expect in-depth discussions on the ecosystem, live coding sessions, and interactive demos that highlight the practical applications of our chain abstraction and AI technologies.</p>



<p><strong>Spotlight on Speaking Engagements</strong></p>



<p>NEAR&#8217;s visionaries are set to captivate audiences across multiple high-profile events this September. At Token2049, don&#8217;t miss Alex Skidanov&#8217;s compelling panel discussion on &#8220;Decentralized AI: The Power of Permissionless Intelligence,&#8221; where he&#8217;ll explore how blockchain technology is democratizing AI development and deployment. Alex will also deliver a solo presentation titled &#8220;Building Web3 Apps of the Future with User-Owned AI,&#8221; diving deep into the technical intricacies of integrating AI with decentralized systems and showcasing how NEAR&#8217;s infrastructure is paving the way for a new generation of intelligent, user-centric applications.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Meanwhile, at Connect 2049, Mark Mi will take the stage to discuss &#8220;The Future of Open Source AI,&#8221; illuminating how NEAR&#8217;s commitment to open-source principles is fostering a more accessible, innovative, and collaborative AI ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The intellectual feast continues at The Scaling AI Summit, where cutting-edge technical demonstrations from Ringfence AI and Bitte will augment Alex Skidanov&#8217;s keynote. These demos will bring theory into practice, offering attendees a tangible glimpse of how NEAR&#8217;s technologies are being applied to solve real-world challenges at the intersection of AI and blockchain. From decentralized machine learning to blockchain-powered AI marketplaces, these presentations and demos will showcase the full spectrum of NEAR&#8217;s pioneering work in the rapidly evolving landscape of decentralized AI.</p>



<p><strong>Shaping the Future of Web3 and AI</strong></p>



<p>As we navigate through this action-packed Token2049 Week in Singapore, one thing becomes clear: NEAR is not just participating in the conversation about chain abstraction and AI—we&#8217;re leading it. Our technical innovations are setting new standards for interoperability, scalability, and user-owned intelligence.</p>



<p>We invite you to join us at these events, either in person or through our live streams. Stay tuned to our official channels for real-time updates, technical deep-dives, and opportunities to engage with our team of experts.</p>



<p>The future of Web3 and AI is being written now, and NEAR is holding the pen.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/token2049/">At the Intersection of AI x Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21528</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ecosystem Update: Announcing Near One, Chain Abstraction Spinouts </title>
		<link>/blog/ecosystem-update-announcing-near-one-chain-abstraction-spinouts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 15:43:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Decentralization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21492</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The NEAR Foundation announces today the formation of two new ecosystem nodes: Near One is spinning out of Pagoda and …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/ecosystem-update-announcing-near-one-chain-abstraction-spinouts/">Ecosystem Update: Announcing Near One, Chain Abstraction Spinouts </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The NEAR Foundation announces today the formation of two new ecosystem nodes: Near One is spinning out of Pagoda and a Chain Abstraction team is launching with members from Pagoda and Proximity Labs. In line with the NEAR ecosystem&#8217;s commitment to decentralization, these teams are spinning out key initiatives that have reached sufficient maturity. They join earlier spinouts including Aurora, Calimero, DevHub, and most recently Nuffle Labs, in becoming independent companies. </p>



<p>Spinouts of NEAR ecosystem initiatives allow teams to focus on their core competencies and move quickly and autonomously with clear and aligned incentives. Importantly, an open and decentralized ecosystem encourages transparency and gives everyone a fair chance to seek funding and support for their contributions. A decentralized ecosystem is also more antifragile and sustainable due to an ever-increasing number of collaborating and competing projects.&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Near One</h4>



<p>The Pagoda team developing the core NEAR blockchain protocol is now <a href="http://nearone.org/">Near One</a>, a team of 30 employees led by Bowen Wang, Head of Protocol. Near One’s mandate is to develop and maintain the NEAR Protocol and roadmap, providing high-performance and scalable infrastructure to support the wide range of activities in the NEAR ecosystem, including consumer apps, Chain Abstraction, modularity, DeFi, and User-Owned AI. Working independently will allow Near One to operate with greater speed and autonomy, and also makes room for multiple node/protocol teams to build on NEAR without relying on an “official” one. Near One will share exciting news about the next phase of sharding later this month.&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Chain Abstraction Spinout</h4>



<p>Following the successful launch of <a href="/blog/chain-signatures-mainnet-launches/">Chain Signatures</a> mainnet, an independent team with key contributors from Pagoda and other nodes will focus on developing the technology and partnerships needed to make the Chain Abstraction vision a reality. This new team will continue the NEAR ecosystem’s leadership in advancing Chain Abstraction for all of Web3. More information and a name for this project are forthcoming in September, so stay tuned.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Future of Pagoda and Pagoda Services</h4>



<p>Given that these two spinouts represent a large percentage of Pagoda’s current staff and responsibilities, the NEAR Foundation Council decided to change the model for funding the other ecosystem services Pagoda has been operating. These will now be distributed via the <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group">Infrastructure Committee</a> to a decentralized set of providers over the next six months. For updates on Pagoda’s transition timeline and process, please consult this <a href="https://docs.near.org/blog/2024-08-13-pagoda-services">Future of Pagoda Services</a> page.</p>



<p>These transitions mean that Pagoda will be winding down, with some Pagoda employees joining other ecosystem nodes including the NEAR Foundation, NEAR.AI, and DevHub teams. Remaining team members will be offered support to found new ecosystem projects, join other ecosystem teams, or bid as independent providers to take over existing work via an RFP process run by the Infrastructure Committee. People with strong knowledge of NEAR technologies are always encouraged to start new projects and seek funding support: this is the most transparent, fair, and sustainable approach for growing the ecosystem as it approaches 4 years since mainnet launch.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NEAR ecosystem teams interested in hiring Pagoda team members are encouraged to share openings on the <a href="https://careers.near.org/jobs">Jobs Board</a> and to consult this <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/12XYaf4SZN5s4AgyFwp27IDvn21BpvKxuZMgp2C9VHhY/edit?resourcekey=&amp;gid=761891858#gid=761891858">opt-in list</a> of people open to new roles. There will also be a hacker house-style Pagoda offsite in Tarrytown, New York in early September, now open to ecosystem contributors interested in connecting with team members and brainstorming independent projects (apply to attend <a href="https://forms.gle/QBtKMBRoPqM3ripc8">here</a>).&nbsp;</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Looking Ahead</h4>



<p>In addition to the launch of Chain Signatures mainnet last week and the upcoming mainnet launch of Nightshade 2.0, the NEAR ecosystem has seen major recent success across a range of key metrics. Last month, in July 2024, the NEAR ecosystem had more than 20 million monthly active users across apps and projects––the highest on any L1 chain, with over 110 million accounts overall. NEAR also reached over 3 million daily active users, the highest of any chain, averaging between six and seven million transactions per day, and has the highest 12-month user retention among L1 blockchains.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A more decentralized and autonomous ecosystem of independent projects will be better equipped to expand on this impressive growth and bring NEAR’s vision and best-in-class technology to a billion users. Those interested in keeping up with the latest news and launches on NEAR should follow along on <a href="https://x.com/nearprotocol">X</a>, attend monthly ecosystem <a href="https://lu.ma/3lit1jwx">Town Halls</a>, watch <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL9tzQn_TEuFWMuPiQOXhaE5lpOTnxLPZY">NEAR AI Office Hours</a>, and attend the [REDACTED] <a href="https://redactedbangkok.ai/">conference and hackathon</a> in Bangkok, Nov. 9-11.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/ecosystem-update-announcing-near-one-chain-abstraction-spinouts/">Ecosystem Update: Announcing Near One, Chain Abstraction Spinouts </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21492</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>[REDACTED] Speakers Announced, Hackathon Registration Is Live</title>
		<link>/blog/redacted-speakers-announced-hackathon-registration-is-live/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 14:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developer relations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redacted]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21462</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It’s getting really real: [REDACTED] is just around the corner, and we have some major updates. You may recall that …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/redacted-speakers-announced-hackathon-registration-is-live/">[REDACTED] Speakers Announced, Hackathon Registration Is Live</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>It’s getting really real: [REDACTED] is just around the corner, and we have some major updates.</p>



<p>You may recall that <a href="https://redactedbangkok.ai/">[REDACTED]</a> is a global convergence to shape the future of User-Owned AI and Chain Abstraction—a future where technology belongs to the people, not corporations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s an IRL movement gathering November 9-11 in Bangkok. It’s a worldwide hackathon kicking off September 5. It’s a defining moment to unify the collective working on these technologies to reclaim our sovereignty.</p>



<p><em>Are you in?</em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The IRL movement: speakers announced, apply to attend</h2>



<p>[REDACTED] is a whole IRL movement: 1,500+ devs, builders, founders, funders, researchers, regulators, and more gathering in person, November 9-11, at the Avani+ Riverside Hotel Bangkok.</p>



<p>Some things can only happen IRL, and some are just way better. Like:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Gaining insights from the teams defining the intersection of AI and Web3</li>



<li>Upskilling and learning how to develop AI x Web3 products and apps</li>



<li>Forming deep connections to build the user-owned future together</li>
</ul>



<p>[REDACTED] will feature a wide range of curated sessions, workshops, and discussions led by the people driving AI x Web3 and Chain Abstraction. We can finally share that this includes:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Illia Polosukhin (NEAR)</li>



<li>Curtis Spencer (Electric Capital)</li>



<li>Anand Iyer (Canonical)</li>



<li>Maartje Bus (Messari)</li>



<li>Matt Stephenson (Pantera)</li>



<li>Calanthia Mei (Masa)</li>



<li>Evrard-Nil Daillet (Google)</li>
</ul>



<p>And more to come as we get closer to Bangkok.</p>



<p>Tickets to the [REDACTED] IRL movement are totally free—you just have to <a href="https://redactedbangkok.ai/">apply</a> to attend, either as a participant or as a hacker (about which, see below). Visa letters are available to support visa applications.</p>



<p>For the absolute latest on the movement, <a href="https://t.me/redactedbangkok">join the official [REDACTED] Telegram channel</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">[REDACTED] Hackathon Registration Is Live</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="[REDACTED] Hackathon Registration Is LIVE" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QrciN2vJ3gY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>Registration for the [REDACTED] hackathon is <a href="https://redacted.devpost.com/">OPEN</a>.</p>



<p>The [REDACTED] hackathon sets top problem-solvers to collaborating on the biggest issues in AI x Web3 and Chain Abstraction. Kicking off September 5, it’s eight weeks remote so teams can go deep, and it culminates at the IRL movement in Bangkok, November 9-11.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hackers accepted into the hackathon can expect workshops and tutorials on industry-leading tools, interactive discussion and support from category/ecosystem experts, and, oh yeah, a chance at over $500k+ in bounties and prizes.</p>



<p>There will also be travel scholarships so qualifying hackers can be IRL in Bangkok for the awards ceremony—and to participate in the IRL movement.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Get Involved with [REDACTED]</h2>



<p>There are a lot of ways [for partners?] to get involved with [REDACTED], from digital marketing exposure and exclusive access to side events to major visibility at the IRL movement. <a href="https://airtable.com/appdLXQkwmt4rqtW0/pag8inbcwhbrWjXW9/form">Find what’s right for you.</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/redacted-speakers-announced-hackathon-registration-is-live/">[REDACTED] Speakers Announced, Hackathon Registration Is Live</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21462</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>EthCC 2024: User-Owned AI Takes Center Stage</title>
		<link>/blog/ethcc-2024-user-owned-ai-takes-center-stage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 18:25:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21447</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Last week, the Ethereum community gathered in Brussels for EthCC, the largest annual European Ethereum event focused on technology and …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/ethcc-2024-user-owned-ai-takes-center-stage/">EthCC 2024: User-Owned AI Takes Center Stage</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Last week, the Ethereum community gathered in Brussels for EthCC, the largest annual European Ethereum event focused on technology and community. Usually held in Paris, this year&#8217;s event moved to Brussels due to the Summer Olympics. Despite initial mixed reactions to the change in location, the Web3 community descended on the Belgian capital for an intense week of conferences, networking, and learning. The NEAR ecosystem was front and center, touting the same vision it has held since its inception: building a world where all people control their own assets, data, and power of governance.</p>



<p>The week kicked off with NEAR co-founder Illia Polosukhin delivering a keynote at the Open Source AI Summit titled &#8220;Why the World Needs User-Owned AI.&#8221; Illia presented the case for investing in open-source, User-Owned AI, emphasizing the importance of collaboration in proactively managing risk, improving user safety, and formally verifying code. He stressed that all data used in training AI models must be open-source to ensure transparency, unpack potential biases, and debug issues effectively.</p>



<p>Later in the week, Illia delivered a keynote presentation on the NEAR AI Hub and AI Developer concept. His talk sparked considerable interest, particularly regarding the transformative potential of Developer AI. The audience was captivated by the vision of a system where individuals, regardless of their technical expertise or financial resources, could transform their ideas into fully-fledged, decentralized, and scalable applications simply by interacting with an AI-driven development platform. This lower barrier to entry for app creation promises to accelerate innovation across the blockchain ecosystem and even in Web2.</p>



<p>NEAR&#8217;s presence at EthCC extended beyond AI discussions. Altan Tutar, CEO of Nuffle Labs, showcased Nuffle&#8217;s pioneering work on data availability, demonstrating how NEAR technology is scaling Ethereum L2s. This presentation highlighted NEAR Protocol&#8217;s versatility beyond its L1 capabilities and its potential to defragment Web3.</p>



<p>Alex Shevchenko from Aurora Labs introduced Forwarder, a personal bridge designed for seamless token transfers between centralized exchanges and various chains, addressing the rapid growth of new blockchains in the ecosystem.</p>



<p>A significant highlight of NEAR&#8217;s participation was the Chain Abstraction Day Brussels on July 10th. Co-hosted with Agoric Systems, this event marked the culmination of NEAR&#8217;s year-long series on interoperability and the future of multi-chain apps and transactions. The day-long program covered different methodologies to achieve chain abstraction to intents, data availability, and infrastructure, including a talk from Illia on what&#8217;s next in the NEAR ecosystem&#8217;s <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=saCoQE39Cvo">contributions to Chain Abstraction</a>. A special fireside chat between Agoric&#8217;s Dean Tribble and Illia delved into architecting next-gen Web3 apps.</p>



<p>The NEAR AI Tech Showcase on July 11th further demonstrated NEAR&#8217;s commitment to innovation. The event featured live demonstrations of AI-powered blockchain applications, giving attendees hands-on experience with the latest developments from the NEAR ecosystem. Underpinning these developments was the NEAR Horizon AI Incubation Program, a strategic initiative designed to kickstart NEAR&#8217;s AI ecosystem by collaborating with top-tier Web3 x AI projects.</p>



<p>NEAR&#8217;s presence at EthCC 2024 offered the rest of the Web3 ecosystem a tangible vision of a User-Owned AI future with real technologies already taking shape. By championing the transfer of power and ownership to users, NEAR aims to unlock a myriad of benefits: enhanced productivity, improved search results, personalized experiences, and novel economic opportunities, all while maintaining a steadfast commitment to privacy and security. The ecosystem&#8217;s overarching goal remained clear: to onboard 1 billion users to a new open internet. NEAR&#8217;s unique position at the intersection of blockchain and AI showcased its readiness to address the growing demand for decentralized artificial intelligence, leveraging Web3&#8217;s inherent strengths to forge a truly user-owned digital landscape. As the event concluded, it was evident that EthCC 2024 marked a defining moment for NEAR Protocol, highlighting its visionary approach, technological prowess, and unwavering commitment to a decentralized, user-centric future.</p>



<p>Interested in learning more about User-Owned AI and the teams building the ecosystem? Check out the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL9tzQn_TEuFWMuPiQOXhaE5lpOTnxLPZY">NEAR AI Office Hours</a> series.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/ethcc-2024-user-owned-ai-takes-center-stage/">EthCC 2024: User-Owned AI Takes Center Stage</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21447</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR at EthCC 2024: Pioneering AI x Web3 </title>
		<link>/blog/near-at-ethcc-2024/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21437</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As EthCC 2024 descends upon Brussels, the city&#8217;s historic charm provides a captivating backdrop for one of the crypto industry&#8217;s …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethcc-2024/">NEAR at EthCC 2024: Pioneering AI x Web3 </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As EthCC 2024 descends upon Brussels, the city&#8217;s historic charm provides a captivating backdrop for one of the crypto industry&#8217;s most anticipated events. Amidst cobblestone streets and Gothic architecture, NEAR Foundation is set to make waves with its pioneering approach to AI x Web3. This year&#8217;s conference promises to be a melting pot of ideas, where NEAR&#8217;s forward-thinking vision will take center stage.</p>



<p>The week-long extravaganza kicks off on July 6th with the Open Source AI Summit. Here, NEAR is positioning itself as the home for User-Owned AI. Championing a User-Owned AI future means building a New Internet that democratizes AI development and access, ensuring users, not centralized companies, control AI. By championing this concept, NEAR is set to ignite discussions on how blockchain can revolutionize the AI landscape, putting power back into the hands of individuals and fostering a new era of technological autonomy.<br></p>



<p>Building on the momentum of the Open Source AI Summit, the spotlight shifts on July 7th to the next-generation modular infrastructure for all layers at Contextualised Connect Brussels by YAP Global. Altan Tutar, CEO of Nuffle Labs, will take center stage before a room packed with media representatives, showcasing Nuffle&#8217;s pioneering work on data availability. By leveraging NEAR technology to scale Ethereum L2s, Nuffle demonstrates NEAR Protocol&#8217;s versatility beyond its L1 capabilities, blurring ecosystem boundaries and fostering collaboration with tier-1 projects like EigenLayer. This strategic expansion and technological validation position NEAR as a crucial player in the broader blockchain landscape, attracting more developers, users, and collaborations with major projects, thereby extending NEAR&#8217;s relevance and utility in the evolving decentralized technology space.</p>



<p><br>Without missing a beat, on July 9th, EthCC&#8217;s main event showcases two game-changing presentations. Illia Polosukhin, CEO of NEAR Foundation, will dive into &#8220;Build Your Next Web3 App with AI,&#8221; offering a practical roadmap for integrating AI into blockchain development. Following this, Alex Shevchenko, CEO of Aurora Labs, will address &#8220;Simplifying Access Across Blockchain and Exchanges,&#8221; highlighting NEAR&#8217;s innovative approach to interoperability. These talks will demonstrate NEAR&#8217;s commitment to advancing AI integration and cross-chain accessibility, positioning the ecosystem at the forefront of Web3 innovation.</p>



<p><br>Chain Abstraction Day Brussels on July 10th marks the culmination of NEAR&#8217;s year-long series, solidifying its place as a cornerstone event at EthCC. Co-hosted with Agoric Systems, this gathering positions Chain Abstraction at the forefront of discussions on interoperability and the future of multi-chain environments. Expect deep dives into the technical aspects of defragmenting and unifying Web3, including infrastructure, data availability, and the role of venture capital. Get hands-on with the latest tools, learn from cutting-edge research, and see real-world applications in action through developer success stories. Live lightning demos will bring the power of chain abstraction to life. This event offers invaluable insights and practical knowledge for everyone, from seasoned blockchain developers to Web3 newcomers, helping you streamline and scale your projects.<br><br>Capping off the week, Illia Polosukhin delivers a keynote at Agents Unleashed, where he deep dives into the potential of AI-powered blockchain applications. This summit is designed to unite developers and innovators in the Web3 autonomous AI agent space, offering a comprehensive look at the current use case landscape. Following this, NEAR HZN presents the NEAR AI Tech Showcase on July 11th. This event promises to be a testament to NEAR&#8217;s innovative spirit, featuring live demonstrations of AI-powered blockchain applications. Attendees will get hands-on experience with the latest developments from the NEAR ecosystem, seeing firsthand how AI is reshaping the blockchain landscape. Underpinning these developments is the NEAR Horizon AI Incubation Program, a strategic initiative designed to kickstart NEAR&#8217;s AI ecosystem. By collaborating with top-tier decentralized AI projects, this program aims to co-design crucial infrastructure that will enable sophisticated AI applications on NEAR. Collectively, these events and initiatives demonstrate NEAR&#8217;s commitment to advancing user-owned AI, where intelligence tooling optimizes for individual users and communities rather than corporate profit, unlocking benefits like higher productivity, personalized experiences, and novel economic opportunities.<br><br>As attendees move between historic venues and modern conference spaces, they&#8217;ll witness firsthand how NEAR is pioneering AI x Web3. NEAR&#8217;s presence at EthCC 2024 is more than just a series of presentations &#8211; it&#8217;s a demonstration of a User-Owned AI future. Putting the power and ownership in the hands of the user unlocks benefits such as higher productivity, better search results, more personalized experiences, and novel economic opportunities that are all privacy-first.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-at-ethcc-2024/">NEAR at EthCC 2024: Pioneering AI x Web3 </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21437</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shape the User-Owned Future at [REDACTED] in Bangkok</title>
		<link>/blog/redacted/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 15:54:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEARCON 2022 was epic. NEARCON 2023 was iconic. NEARCON 2024? Not this year. Gm to [REDACTED]. [REDACTED] is a global …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/redacted/">Shape the User-Owned Future at [REDACTED] in Bangkok</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEARCON 2022 was epic. NEARCON 2023 was iconic.</p>



<p>NEARCON 2024? <em>Not this year.</em></p>



<p>Gm to [REDACTED].</p>



<p>[REDACTED] is a global convergence to shape the future of User-Owned AI and Chain Abstraction—a future where technology belongs to the people, not corporations. Imagine stepping into a ‘Sovereign Paradise’ where the air buzzes with inspiration and opportunities to learn about AI and Web3. At [REDACTED], you&#8217;re not just attending another tech conference: you are contributing to a pivotal moment in the digital revolution. This IRL movement unifies the AI x Web3 collective as we embark on a transformative future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>[REDACTED] is November 9-11, in Bangkok, Thailand. Be a part of the learnings and insights shared at [REDACTED] by joining Keynotes, Firesides, Workshops, or Hacking.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">[REDACTED] is an IRL movement, and the application to attend is LIVE at <a href="http://redactedbangkok.ai/">redactedbangkok.ai</a>.</h2>



<p>AI is transforming the internet and the way we interact with computing. AI and Web3 can work together to ensure the power of intelligence is where it belongs: in the hands of users. NEAR is leading at this intersection of AI x Web3, and the NEAR Foundation is gathering the global AI x Web3 community in Bangkok to share key innovations and insights, form deep connections that can only happen IRL, and build the user-owned future together.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">[REDACTED] is free, but attendance is by application only.</h2>



<p><a href="http://redactedbangkok.ai/">Apply now</a> to claim your spot among 1,500+ devs, founders, researchers, regulators, creatives, and leaders. Here’s what to expect as you journey through [REDACTED]</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Upskill your AI knowledge in essential workshops and deep-dive discussions led by the teams defining the intersection of AI x Web3.</li>



<li>Gain insights on how to develop AI x Web3 products and applications. </li>



<li>Connect with collaborators on building the tools, driving adoption, empowering users and communities, and taking back sovereignty.</li>



<li>Interact with projects from NEAR and other Ecosystems, solving problems with AI x Web3 technical solutions. </li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">And stay tuned to participate in the [REDACTED] hybrid hackathon for a chance to win over $500k in prizes.</h2>



<p>The [REDACTED] hackathon is an opportunity to collaborate over eight weeks—both online and IRL in Bangkok—with top problem-solvers on the biggest issues in Chain Abstraction and AI x Web3, with category experts from NEAR and beyond providing interactive discussion and support.</p>



<p>The future of AI, decentralized ecosystems, and community-driven innovation is taking shape live at [REDACTED]. Apply to attend at <a href="http://redactedbangkok.ai/">redactedbangkok.ai</a>.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/redacted/">Shape the User-Owned Future at [REDACTED] in Bangkok</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21428</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Modular Spins Out to Become Nuffle Labs with $13M in Funding</title>
		<link>/blog/nuffle-labs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21409</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The NEAR Foundation announces the launch of Nuffle Labs, a new venture spinning out from Pagoda and the NEAR Foundation. …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nuffle-labs/">NEAR Modular Spins Out to Become Nuffle Labs with $13M in Funding</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The NEAR Foundation announces the launch of Nuffle Labs, a new venture spinning out from Pagoda and the NEAR Foundation. Founded by the core contributors to the NEAR Data Availability Layer (NEAR DA) and the NEAR Fast Finality Layer (NFFL), the NEAR Modular product suite is now spinning out into an independent entity dedicated to improving and amplifying NEAR’s modularity offerings. The new entity has secured $13 million in funding, including a strategic grant from NEAR Foundation and external investment led by Electric Capital.</p>



<p>The spinout of Nuffle Labs reflects not only the strength of the core team and the products they are building, but also illustrates the Foundation’s commitment to decentralization by turning core functions over to proven teams in the ecosystem. As an independent team, Nuffle Labs will be better positioned to operate at the forefront of modular blockchain design, nurture its own decentralized community, and forge more partnerships across the Web3 ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Nuffle Labs will leverage NEAR Protocol’s cost-effective, fast, and proven technology to offer rollups enhanced modularity. It is responsible for two key products in NEAR’s modular suite: NEAR Data Availability (NEAR DA) and NEAR Fast Finality Layer, now Nuffle Fast Finality Layer (NFFL).</p>



<p><strong>Nuffle Labs secures $13M in funding to support their growth</strong></p>



<p>Nuffle Labs’ spinout comes with substantial investment, including a strategic grant from the NEAR Foundation as well as funding from external investors including Electric Capital, Canonical Crypto, Fabric Ventures, Robot Ventures, Caladan, and Lyrik Ventures. Notable angel investors include Jordi Alexander (Selini), Blackdragon VC, Bowen Wang (NEAR), Sreeram Kannan (EigenLayer), Sam Kazemian (Frax), Sandeep Nailwal (Polygon), DeFi Dad (4RC), Dovey Wan (Primitive Ventures), and Mert Mumtaz (Helius). With these resources and supporters, the team is well-equipped to advance NEAR DA and NFFL, expand the team, invest in R&amp;D, and build a strong community that spans across NEAR, Ethereum, and beyond.</p>



<p>“We&#8217;re proud to support the growth of Nuffle Labs as an independent company in the NEAR ecosystem. These 4 excellent co-founders have built first-rate modularity products that showcase the best of NEAR&#8217;s technology with NEAR DA and NFFL, providing cost-effective and performant solutions to projects across Web3,” said Illia Polosukhin, Co-Founder of NEAR Protocol and CEO of NEAR Foundation. “We look forward to continued collaboration with the NEAR Foundation as they expand and evolve.”</p>



<p>Avichal Garg, General Partner at lead investor Electric Capital, said, “We are excited to back Nuffle Labs, the builders behind NEAR DA and the NEAR Fast Finality Layer (NFFL). As the core team that developed these products from the ground up, Nuffle Labs has the expertise to advance these modular solutions, creating a world where intra- and interchain transactions are cheap, fast, and secure.”</p>



<p>“I have had the great privilege of getting to know the founders of Nuffle and working with them from day zero,” said Anand Iyer, General Partner at Canonical Crypto. “Their passion for solving blockchain scaling combined with their expertise from building solutions at NEAR has me genuinely excited for them and their future.”</p>



<p><strong>Understanding NEAR Data Availability (NEAR DA)</strong></p>



<p>NEAR DA utilizes the sharded architecture of NEAR Protocol to provide a modular data availability layer for Ethereum rollups with extremely high throughput and low cost. On mainnet launch, RSS3 – an open information protocol bridging AI and Web3 – experienced a substantial cost reduction, paying a daily average of $10 compared to their previous $1,000. NEAR DA currently has a throughput of 24MB/s, significantly higher than its closest competitor’s 6.67MB/s – making NEAR DA the most scalable, cheapest, and reliable DA solution on the market.</p>



<p>NEAR DA’s scalability is further enhanced by its ability to support multiple rollups, whether they are optimistic or ZK-rollups. NEAR Data Availability (NEAR DA) provides:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Cost-efficiency: Storing data on NEAR Protocol is significantly cheaper than on Ethereum, making it easier for projects to build as well as faster.</li>



<li>Effortless Validation: NEAR Protocol&#8217;s trustless off-chain light client simplifies validation, ensuring accurate and reliable transactions.</li>



<li>User-Friendly Interaction: NEAR Protocol provides easy access to on-chain data through RPC, making blockchain interaction seamless for developers and users.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Exploring NEAR Fast Finality Layer (NFFL)</strong></p>



<p>The name Nuffle Labs is derived from the acronym NFFL. The Nuffle Fast Finality Layer (NFFL) is an EigenLayer Actively Validated Service (AVS) designed to aggregate state across various rollups. By leveraging NEAR DA, NFFL provides a fast, universal, and secure finality layer. It enhances block finality across different protocols and integrates additional public DA layers into the blockchain stack, paving the way for innovative cross-chain applications. NFFL is currently live on testnet––learn more <a href="https://nffl.nethermind.io/">about the protocol</a>.</p>



<p><strong>What&#8217;s next for Nuffle Labs?</strong></p>



<p>“We are thrilled about the incredible opportunity to grow and develop NEAR’s modular product offerings at Nuffle Labs,” said Altan Tutar, CEO of Nuffle Labs. The other Nuffle co-founders are Sam Wang, Firat Sertgoz, and Donovan Dall. “We deeply appreciate the support from the NEAR Foundation and are honored by the validation from such distinguished investors. Their confidence in our vision and capabilities energizes us as we continue to innovate and expand.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Looking ahead, Nuffle Labs will focus on advancing the development of the NFFL AVS on EigenLayer and further enhancing the robustness and efficiency of NEAR DA to support Ethereum’s rollup-centric future. The team is committed to furthering innovation in modular blockchain design and defragmenting the Web3 ecosystem.</p>



<p>Follow along with the Nuffle team’s progress on their <a href="http://nuff.tech/">new site here</a> and follow the <a href="https://x.com/NuffleLabs">Nuffle Labs X(Twitter) account</a>. L2 builders interested in a partnership with Nuffle or those interested in applying to work with Nuffle can get in touch via the Nuffle Labs website.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nuffle-labs/">NEAR Modular Spins Out to Become Nuffle Labs with $13M in Funding</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21409</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing *NEAR Name Tokens &#8211; Multichain, Cross-Platform Digital Identities In Web3</title>
		<link>/blog/introducing-near-name-tokens/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 13:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Following the recently announced partnership between NEAR Foundation and&#160;D3, we’re excited to introduce *NEAR Name Tokens; a multichain, cross-platform digital …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/introducing-near-name-tokens/">Introducing *NEAR Name Tokens &#8211; Multichain, Cross-Platform Digital Identities In Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Following the recently announced <a href="/blog/near-protocol-partners-with-d3-to-apply-for-near-top-level-domain/">partnership between NEAR Foundation and&nbsp;D3</a>, we’re excited to introduce *NEAR Name Tokens; a multichain, cross-platform digital identity for web3 and beyond.</p>



<p>NEAR Foundation is working with D3 to bridge the gap between traditional internet infrastructure and web3. *NEAR Name Tokens are an important step in developing the <a href="https://d3.inc/blog/educational/futureproof-your-digital-identity-how-d3-aims-to-revolutionize-your-online-persona/">futureproof, interoperable digital identities</a> that will be key to driving implementation of chain abstraction, and of developing web3 more broadly.</p>



<p><strong>Complementing the NEAR Ecosystem with *NEAR Name Tokens</strong></p>



<p>NEAR already offers a deeply integrated identity solution with named NEAR accounts. These NEAR accounts, however, are limited to use across the NEAR ecosystem.</p>



<p>*NEAR Name Tokens will offer users a comprehensive digital identity solution across the wider web3 ecosystem, while keeping NEAR front and center.</p>



<p>Users will be able to use these name tokens in a variety of ways, including:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>As a simplified wallet address across hundreds of different blockchain networks</li>



<li>As an infrastructure identifier across hundreds of different blockchain networks</li>



<li>As a cross-platform username across various different decentralized platforms, including DeFi, GameFi, SocialFi, SportFi and other related applications</li>



<li>As Verifiable Credentials (VCs) to platforms and services that you interact with</li>



<li>To gain access to unique benefits and rewards programs for participating in the D3 ecosystem</li>



<li>As expressions of interest for the eventual .NEAR equivalent domain on the internet</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Why *NEAR Instead of .NEAR</strong></p>



<p>*NEAR Name Tokens feature a star, or asterisk (*), between the name and extension—such as <em>you*near</em>—instead of a period (.). In part, this is because NEAR accounts already use a .NEAR extension, and we want to avoid confusion for users.</p>



<p>More importantly, however, we use *NEAR because Name Tokens are unique web3 identifiers, not real domains, and we want to avoid any confusion between these as well. For years, several naming systems across web3 have thrown around the word “domain” quite liberally, without offering any of the actual utility offered by real domains.</p>



<p>Real domains are fully integrated with the Domain Name System, the distributed service that allows users to access websites and email infrastructure with ease. Billions of internet-capable devices—such as computers, tablets, mobile phones, Internet of Things devices, and more—support the DNS and real domains without the need for specialized software or plugins.</p>



<p>Integrating web3 with DNS will be critical in bringing interoperable digital identities to web3. To that end, NEAR Foundation has partnered with D3 to apply for and obtain the .near top-level domain—like the “.org” in <em>near.org</em>—during the upcoming application period for new TLDs, the first in over a decade.</p>



<p><strong>Exclusive Early Access Period to *NEAR Name Tokens for NEAR Account Holders</strong></p>



<p>As part of our initial launch phase later this summer,, existing NEAR account holders will receive exclusive early access to their equivalent *NEAR Name Tokens. For instance, if you already have the <em>name.near</em> NEAR account registered prior to launch, you will receive exclusive access to register <em>name*near</em> for a period of 90 days before names are released for public availability.</p>



<p>Similarly, should a NEAR account be available for any new *NEAR Name Token registrations, D3 will claim it on behalf of users to ensure a uniform experience across the NEAR ecosystem. Users can <a href="https://d3.app/near">sign up for early access</a>, and you’ll be  notified you prior to the official launch of *NEAR Name Tokens later this summer</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/introducing-near-name-tokens/">Introducing *NEAR Name Tokens &#8211; Multichain, Cross-Platform Digital Identities In Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21393</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Foundation Partners with NEAT Protocol to Accelerate the Growth of AI Applications with 1 million $NEAR Delegation</title>
		<link>/blog/neat-protocol/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 12:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21390</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Foundation announces today that NEAT, a rollup protocol designed for scaling AI applications on NEAR, has received 1 million …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/neat-protocol/">NEAR Foundation Partners with NEAT Protocol to Accelerate the Growth of AI Applications with 1 million $NEAR Delegation</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR Foundation announces today that NEAT, a rollup protocol designed for scaling AI applications on NEAR, has received 1 million $NEAR token staking delegation from NEAR Foundation. All NEAR token rewards from the delegation will be redistributed to $NEAT stakers, producing approximately 120-200% APY. This funding is part of NEAR Foundation&#8217;s efforts to support AI and blockchain projects on NEAR, and to promote use cases of AI integration with blockchain technology more broadly. NEAT, as the first rollup scaling protocol to receive official support from the NEAR Foundation, will utilize these funds to attract a wider user base to its ecosystem.</p>



<p>NEAT is a rollup scaling solution built on the NEAR inscription standard, specifically designed to facilitate AI and machine-learning applications on NEAR. NEAT offers an innovative approach for rollups to be built on NEAR. With off-chain indexer nodes for execution and NEAR L1 as the data availability layer, NEAT eliminates the need for rollups to deploy smart contracts or run verification logic on the L1. This streamlined process drastically reduces transaction costs for rollups, making NEAT particularly well suited for computationally intensive applications such as AI and gaming. Additionally, NEAR Catalog, powered by NEAT, is currently developing an advanced indexer that aims to provide projects and applications in the NEAR ecosystem with cost-effective and flexible indexing and querying capabilities.</p>



<p><strong>NEAT Token and Benefits</strong><br></p>



<p>The $NEAT token exists in two forms, NRC-20 and NEP-141, with a total supply of 42 million tokens. $NEAT tokens offers the following benefits:</p>



<p>1. Stakers of $NEAT-NEP141 will receive the staking rewards generated from the 1 million $NEAR tokens provided by the Foundation. A portion of these staking rewards will also be allocated to support the exploration of AI integration with NEAT.</p>



<p>2. $NEAT-NEP141 stakers will receive a share of the fees generated from wrap/unwrap operations (currently set at 1% fee rate) and a portion of the fees from the NRC-20 marketplace.</p>



<p>3. After the decentralized indexer is operational, a portion of the indexing fees will be distributed to $NEAT-NEP141 stakers.</p>



<p>4. Holders of $NEAT-NRC20 tokens will be eligible to receive airdrops of newly minted NRC-20 tokens.</p>



<p>5. $NEAT serves as a utility token within the NEAT ecosystem, enabling services/assets payments, DeFi integration, AI governance, and more.</p>



<p><strong>The Road Ahead: Revolutionizing AI with Decentralized Indexing</strong></p>



<p><strong><br></strong>NEAT is building the first fully customizable decentralized indexer network, which allows any project to easily store data on the NEAR blockchain, deploy custom indexing logic on a decentralized set of indexer nodes, and achieve verifiable execution through zero-knowledge proofs. This approach aims to address potential failure points and attack vectors associated with centralized indexers.</p>



<p>One of the most exciting use cases for decentralized indexing is in the field of artificial intelligence. With NRC-20 and NEAT Indexers, it becomes possible to store AI data, parameters, algorithms, models, and outputs as on-chain inscriptions and integrate them with off-chain execution through zero-knowledge proofs. For instance, one can imagine creating fully open-source AI-powered games, where users participate in shaping the game&#8217;s narrative, and the history is permanently stored on-chain through inscriptions. AI agents&#8217; models, parameters, and decisions can be represented as inscribed NFTs, and their training and model parameters can be stored on-chain.</p>



<p>This combination of blockchain transparency and off-chain computational efficiency allows AI to be truly accessible and open to everyone, contributing to the development of a genuinely open network.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/neat-protocol/">NEAR Foundation Partners with NEAT Protocol to Accelerate the Growth of AI Applications with 1 million $NEAR Delegation</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21390</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
