<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Community Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/category/community/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/category/community/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:36:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Community Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/category/community/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>NEAR Launches Infrastructure Committee with $4 Million in Funding </title>
		<link>/blog/near-launches-infrastructure-committee/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:36:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR has seen a massive surge in users and transactions over the last few months. It’s important to have a …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-launches-infrastructure-committee/">NEAR Launches Infrastructure Committee with $4 Million in Funding </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR has seen a massive surge in users and transactions over the last few months. It’s important to have a smooth-running blockchain for project and founder expansion. Today, the NEAR Foundation launches the Infrastructure Committee, a new initiative aimed to strengthen NEAR&#8217;s Key Infrastructure. With $4 million earmarked for infrastructure projects, the initiative is meant to support the success of NEAR projects while distributing funds and sourcing projects in an open, transparent way.</p>



<p>What is Key Infrastructure? It includes RPC nodes, relayers, indexers, bridges, wallets, load balancers, and oracles. Also, NEAR should be listed correctly on all the DEX tools available. Incidents and outages need to be easily reported and fixed.</p>



<p><strong>The committee is made up of  ecosystem leaders and NEAR partners from across core NEAR orgs. Its goals are to:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Decentralize decision-making</li>



<li>Enhance critical infrastructure</li>



<li>Streamline efforts for greater clarity and decentralization</li>
</ul>



<p>The committee primarily focuses on proposals, with multiple Requests For Proposals (RFPs) planned to meet important ecosystem needs. These proposals will undergo review and asynchronous voting by the committee.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-progress-of-the-infrastructure-committee">Progress of the Infrastructure Committee</h2>



<p><strong>The Infrastructure Committee has already funded five critical infrastructure proposals:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Jutsu IDE infrastructure implementation (AI development environment)</li>



<li>FASTNEAR infrastructure services (new RPC nodes and custom endpoints)</li>



<li>Aurora Web 3.0 Wallet Support Services</li>



<li>The building of a Treasury App for use by governing committees</li>



<li>An audit of the Ledger integrations</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>The committee also inherited some projects that it will now actively manage:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Aurora RPC SpeedUp</li>



<li>MyNEARWallet maintenance by Meteor</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>With over half of the allocated $4 million budget remaining, there is an open invitation to the community to bring forward innovative infrastructure projects such as:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Faster RPC Nodes</li>



<li>Specific common endpoints to replace broad RPC queries</li>



<li>New bridges to improve cross-chain transactions and increase the number of chains supported</li>



<li>ICANN-compliant DNS and expansion of top-level domains</li>



<li>Focused relayers to support gas-free and other specialized relayer needs</li>
</ul>



<p>The committee encourages community members to contribute their ideas, proposals, and feedback, and welcomes a range of perspectives from founders, developers, and NEAR enthusiasts on how to improve the foundations of NEAR technology.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>The current Infrastructure Committee is comprised of the following members:</strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Abhishek Vaidyanathan, NEAR Foundation (serving as a non-voting meeting Chair)</li>



<li>Alex Shevchenko, Aurora Labs</li>



<li>Bowen Wang, Director of Protocol, Pagoda</li>



<li>Vlad Frolov, DevHub</li>



<li>Sandi Fatic, Calimero</li>



<li>Eric Winer, Pagoda</li>



<li>Illia Polosukhin, NEAR Foundation (serving as an ad-hoc member on an as-needed basis)</li>



<li>Christopher Donovan, NEAR Foundation (serving as an ad-hoc member on an as-needed basis)</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>The Working Group comprises the following admins and advisors:</strong><strong><br></strong></p>



<ul>
<li>Project Oversight &#8211; Konrad Merino, Head of Blockchain Success, NEAR Foundation</li>



<li>Product Manager &#8211; Gautham Ravi, Sr. Product Manager, Pagoda</li>



<li>Project Manager &#8211; Trentin C Bergeron, Sr. Technical Program Manager, Pagoda</li>



<li>Technical BD &#8211; Vikas Pandey, Success &amp; Partner Engineering, NEAR Foundation</li>



<li>Technical Advisor &#8211; Robert Tsia, SRE Manager, Pagoda</li>



<li>Technical Advisor &#8211; Ernesto Cejas Padilla, Sr. SRE, Pagoda</li>



<li>Technical Advisor &#8211; Firat Sertgoz, Engineering Manager, Pagoda</li>



<li>Technical Advisor &#8211; Patrick Engvall, Sr. Engineer, Pagoda</li>



<li>Technical Advisor &#8211; Pierre Leguen, Software Engineer, NEAR Foundation Finance</li>



<li>Broadcast MC &amp; Project Advisor &#8211; Marcus Ribeiro, Ecosystem Relations, NEAR Foundation</li>
</ul>



<p>For those looking to participate, the <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/wiki/Proposal-Process-%E2%80%90-Team">Interim Proposal and Funding Process</a> provides a comprehensive guide on how to submit proposals. To foster transparency and public engagement, the committee has established clear processes to track and discuss proposals openly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The community can view the <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1sjUgUnY_Ufw8RjfUFj5K2RM6gYC3XBRVu1iYXzD3cBQ/edit?usp=sharing">public tracking of proposals</a> document and participate in <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/discussions">public discussions</a>, including announcements of Requests for Proposals (RFPs). The committee’s meeting notes will be shared with the community to maintain openness about the committee&#8217;s decisions and discussions.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-engaging-the-community-and-fostering-collaboration">Engaging the Community and Fostering Collaboration</h2>



<p>To facilitate community engagement, anyone interested can join the <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/discussions">discussion</a> on the Github repo, which will serve as the hub for suggestions, collaboration, and support among members interested in contributing to NEAR infrastructure.<br></p>



<p>The <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/wiki/Infrastructure-Committee">Infrastructure Mandate &amp; Charter</a> and <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/wiki/Infrastructure-Working-Group">Working Group Details</a> will offer additional insights into the committee’s mission, structure, and ongoing projects. These resources are designed to educate and inspire community members to contribute their skills and ideas towards building a more robust and scalable NEAR ecosystem.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-future-plans-for-the-near-infrastructure-committee">Future Plans for the NEAR Infrastructure Committee</h2>



<p>As NEAR continues to grow, so will the necessity for robust infrastructure to support an increasing number of transactions and users. Future enhancements include the introduction of a more sophisticated incident management system and post-mortem processes for infrastructure outages.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The development of a Blockchain Operating System (BOS)-based app for proposal management will be another significant move towards optimizing the efficiency of the funding process. This upgrade will streamline the proposal and funding workflow, making it easier for community members to submit and manage their projects.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The committee’s work will also support NEAR’s growth and chain abstraction efforts, ensuring the blockchain can handle the anticipated surge in traffic as more users join the ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Those interested in getting involved with the Infrastructure Committee can join the <a href="https://github.com/near/Infrastructure-Working-Group/discussions">Working Group Discussion on GitHub</a> to collaborate on initiatives, discuss proposals and RFPs, or ask questions.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-launches-infrastructure-committee/">NEAR Launches Infrastructure Committee with $4 Million in Funding </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Ecosystem Kicks Up a Sandstorm at TOKEN2049 Dubai</title>
		<link>/blog/near-ecosystem-kicks-up-a-sandstorm-at-token2049-dubai/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21312</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>After making waves at last year&#8217;s Singapore edition, we&#8217;re turning up the heat for TOKEN2049 in Dubai, the city that&#8217;s …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-ecosystem-kicks-up-a-sandstorm-at-token2049-dubai/">NEAR Ecosystem Kicks Up a Sandstorm at TOKEN2049 Dubai</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>After making waves at last year&#8217;s Singapore edition, we&#8217;re turning up the heat for TOKEN2049 in Dubai, the city that&#8217;s rapidly becoming a hotbed for Fintech and AI innovation. This year, the NEAR ecosystem is buzzing with excitement to introduce discussions on chain abstraction and spotlight some of our most dynamic projects, including Calimero, Sweat Economy, and Aurora, to the forefront of the global tech scene.</em></p>



<p><strong>Tech, Coffee, &amp; Bubbles!</strong><br></p>



<p>By day, make your way to our booth to engage with the NEAR collective and the visionaries from Calimero, Sweat Economy, and Aurora. Unpack the ways we&#8217;re transforming the Web3 space with breakthroughs in chain abstraction, data availability, frameworks for building decentralized application protocols, and Blockchain as a Service (BaaS). Indulge in the flavors of traditional Arabic coffee and pick up the hottest swag.<br></p>



<p>Yet, the experience doesn&#8217;t stop at coffee.<br></p>



<p>As the enthusiastic sponsor of TOKEN2049 Dubai&#8217;s closing party, NEAR is preparing an unforgettable evening. Anticipate a gala filled with select champagne and spirits, celebrating the milestones and fellowship of the Web3 community.</p>



<p><strong>Can&#8217;t-Miss Speaking Engagements</strong></p>



<p>At TOKEN2049 Dubai, NEAR Protocol is diving into the conversations that are shaping the future of Web3. We&#8217;re kicking things off with a panel on &#8220;AI x Web3: Pioneering Decentralized Intelligence,&#8221; featuring NEAR&#8217;s own Illia Polosukhin alongside experts like Ahmad Shadid from io.net, Niraj Pant of Ritual, Sean Ren of Sahara, and moderated by Tarun Chitra of Gauntlet. They&#8217;ll unpack the exciting crossroads of AI and Web3 in fostering decentralized intelligence. Then, don&#8217;t miss our fireside chat, &#8220;Sweat Economy&#8217;s Billion-User Blueprint for Scaling Consumer Crypto Apps,&#8221; where Chris Donovan, COO of NEAR Foundation and Oleg Fomenko, Co-founder &amp; CEO of&nbsp; Sweat Economy open up about their ground-breaking collaboration.</p>



<p>Swing by our booth for a firsthand look at how NEAR is redefining norms with chain abstraction, data availability, and more—all powered by a healthy dose of caffeine.<br><br>TOKEN2049 is gearing up to be a dynamic assembly featuring the forefront of Web3 innovation, an event you won&#8217;t want to miss. For updates on our activities, side events, and speakers, please visit our <a href="https://lu.ma/d1mzjpw3">Lu.ma</a> page and the <a href="https://week.token2049.com/">TOKEN2049</a> landing page!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-ecosystem-kicks-up-a-sandstorm-at-token2049-dubai/">NEAR Ecosystem Kicks Up a Sandstorm at TOKEN2049 Dubai</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Korea BUIDL Week Recap: One Account to Rule Them All</title>
		<link>/blog/korea-buidl-week-recap-one-account-to-rule-them-all/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 05:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Last week, Korea BUIDL Week was the epicenter of cutting-edge thought leadership in Web3. From cross-chain innovations to the convergence …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/korea-buidl-week-recap-one-account-to-rule-them-all/">Korea BUIDL Week Recap: One Account to Rule Them All</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Last week, Korea BUIDL Week was the epicenter of cutting-edge thought leadership in Web3. From cross-chain innovations to the convergence of AI and blockchain, the week brought together industry pioneers to explore the technologies shaping the decentralized future.</p>



<p><strong>Chain Abstraction Day Tackles Interoperability</strong></p>



<p>Chain Abstraction Day kicked Korea BUIDL Week off by tackling the need for seamless blockchain interoperability. NEAR’s Co-founder and CEO, Illia Polosukhin, made a compelling case for &#8220;Why Web3 Needs Chain Abstraction&#8221; by highlighting how abstracting away individual chains can unlock Web3&#8217;s full potential. Mike Purvis of Proximity Labs then painted a vision of &#8220;Ushering in the Era of Bridgeless Cross-Chain DeFi,&#8221; while Riqi Ras presented &#8220;Bitcoin Beyond Gold&#8221;, showcasing snippets of a testnet transaction where a NEAR account signed transactions on Bitcoin. This proof-of-concept highlighted the potential of chain signatures to not just interact with Bitcoin, but even enable trading of Bitcoin Ordinals natively using the cross-chain signing capabilities.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Blockchain Brain Trust: Vitalik Envisions Account Abstraction, Illia Unleashes Chain Signatures</strong></p>



<p>At BUIDL Asia, anticipation was high for Vitalik Buterin&#8217;s talk on &#8220;The Future of Account Abstraction.&#8221; By abstracting user accounts, he explored enabling frictionless cross-chain experiences. “The next 10 years are going to be about really upgrading the ecosystem at the user level,” Buterin said at the event. Illia Polosukhin then took center stage, announcing NEAR&#8217;s groundbreaking &#8220;Chain Signatures&#8221; for managing assets across chains via a single account. Illia demonstrated how Chain Signatures allow signing transactions on multiple chains from a single NEAR account, paving the way for seamless cross-chain dApp development.</p>



<p>Illia and Vitalik later joined forces for a can&#8217;t-miss fireside chat dissecting the &#8220;AI/Crypto Fact vs Fiction.&#8221; As two towering minds in their respective fields, they offered unparalleled insights into AI&#8217;s transformative potential for Web3. The lively discussion separated hype from reality, exploring how AI could enhance privacy, scalability, and usability of decentralized systems. Vitalik and Illia also examined the risks of centralized AI models and the importance of developing decentralized AI aligned with Web3&#8217;s core values.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1200" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-21317" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image.jpeg 1600w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-300x225.jpeg 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-1024x768.jpeg 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-768x576.jpeg 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/image-1536x1152.jpeg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure>



<p><strong>ETH Seoul Dives Deep into Chain Signatures and Decentralized Intelligence</strong></p>



<p>The event baton was then passed to ETH Seoul, where Mike Purvis expounded on &#8220;Chain Signatures: Cross-Chain Without Bridges.&#8221; Purvis explained how this technology enables secure cross-chain communication, eliminating the need for centralized bridges. He demonstrated how it could pave the way for seamless blockchain interoperability and conducted a workshop showcasing potential use cases.&nbsp; Boris Polania made a case for &#8220;Decentralized Intelligence&#8221;&nbsp; discussing how combining blockchain transparency with AI data analysis could revolutionize collective decision-making processes. The conference featured comprehensive developer tracks put together by DevHub, covering everything from building on NEAR to integrating Chain Signatures. ETH Seoul also hosted a hackathon where teams built innovative decentralized apps, with members of the NEAR ecosystem serving as judges to evaluate and provide feedback on the projects.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DeFiBrain, an AI-powered DeFi investment assistant that harnesses NEAR to discover and analyze promising DeFi products, won NEAR&#8217;s Chain Signatures bounty and ETH Seoul&#8217;s first prize. DeFiBrain impressed with its advanced AI models and seamless NEAR integration. The first prize of $5,000 for the NEARDevHub&#8217;s &#8220;AI Governance is NEAR&#8221; bounty was awarded to Connor AI, which integrates AI into DAOs to automate execution processes and empower decentralized decision-making. Connor AI was commended for its novel AI-DAO approach.</p>



<p><strong>Vitalik Outlines Ethereum&#8217;s Scaling Roadmap, Illia Tackles AI Misconceptions</strong></p>



<p>Not to be outdone, Vitalik outlined his vision for Ethereum&#8217;s future in &#8220;Dencun: Where We Go From Here.&#8221; During his talk, he primarily focused on EIP 4844, also known as “Blobs”, which represents a significant upgrade for Ethereum scaling. This upgrade allows Layer 2 networks to post batched transactions at a much lower cost. Consequently, Vitalik issued a call-to-action, encouraging developers to build solutions for today&#8217;s needs. Closing the event, Illia Polosukhin delivered a talk cheekily titled &#8220;Secrets About AI that Web3 Doesn&#8217;t Want You To Know,&#8221; likely pulling back the curtain on AI&#8217;s game-changing implications. Illia&#8217;s provocative talk challenged misconceptions about the limitations of current AI while hinting at potential breakthroughs that could supercharge decentralized applications.</p>



<p><strong>SheFi Emphasizes Cultivating Inclusive Web3 Communities</strong></p>



<p>Finally, SheFi spotlighted building inclusive Web3 communities. NEAR&#8217;s Yadira Blocker led the discussion on cultivating Web3 culture and community &#8211; a critical topic as the ecosystem grows. The panel emphasized genuine communities are earned through authentic connections, not purchased. It also discussed how global Web3 communities localize efforts while valuing in-person meetups to drive progress collaboratively. Unlike Web2, community heavily influences Web3 marketing and adoption.</p>



<p>From multi-chain architectures to AI convergence, Korea BUIDL Week demonstrated that Web3 is rapidly evolving towards a future of seamless cross-chain functionality, enhanced intelligence, and open participation. The insights shared will undoubtedly help shape the coming decades of decentralized innovation.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/korea-buidl-week-recap-one-account-to-rule-them-all/">Korea BUIDL Week Recap: One Account to Rule Them All</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>LiNEAR Protocol Introduces Omnichain Liquid Restaking to Advance NEAR’s Chain Abstraction </title>
		<link>/blog/linear-protocol-introduces-omnichain-liquid-restaking/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 02:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21300</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>LiNEAR, the leading DeFi protocol on NEAR with the highest TVL, is planning to enhance the security of NEAR&#8217;s Chain …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/linear-protocol-introduces-omnichain-liquid-restaking/">LiNEAR Protocol Introduces Omnichain Liquid Restaking to Advance NEAR’s Chain Abstraction </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://linearprotocol.org/">LiNEAR</a>, the leading DeFi protocol on <a href="https://near.org/">NEAR</a> with the highest TVL, is planning to enhance the security of NEAR&#8217;s Chain Abstracted network through restaking, ensuring a secure future for a chain-agnostic and chain-abstracted Web3 experience. Established by early core contributors to NEAR, LiNEAR has made significant contributions to advancing the ecosystem, beginning with its innovative liquid staking features, notably the Automatic Validator Optimization Algorithm. This algorithm greatly improves the security and decentralization of the NEAR network by dynamically reallocating stakes across as many as 200 active nodes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>LiNEAR’s vision has always been enabling easier participation in the decentralized web. With the NEAR ecosystem&#8217;s commitment to advancing Chain Abstraction by removing the complexities of blockchain technology for users, LiNEAR is also expanding its offering and focusing on restaking to eliminate barriers to entry for the multichain ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>LiNEAR Protocol will be providing a robust security model through <strong>omnichain liquid restaking</strong>, avoiding the pitfalls of centralized and permissioned solutions in pursuit of an improved Web3 user experience. Restaking can potentially secure Chain Abstraction infrastructures for three key reasons: it offers instant security by leveraging existing blockchain security mechanisms; ensures capital efficiency by allowing nodes and stakers of a blockchain to participate with minimal additional capital; and promotes base layer alignment, closely bonding the networks with the blockchains which they serve.</p>



<p>NEAR‘s Chain Abstraction comprises social authentication, <a href="/blog/unlocking-web3-usability-with-account-aggregation/">account aggregation</a>, Chain Signatures, and the multichain intent relayer. These elements combine to allow users to transact across various blockchains using a single account and interface, without the need to understand the underlying infrastructure or switch networks.</p>



<p>To realize this vision, two new decentralized infrastructures are required: the <a href="/blog/chain-signatures-launch-to-enable-transactions-on-any-blockchain-from-a-near-account/">Chain Signatures</a> MPC network and the Multichain Gas Relayer. The Chain Signatures MPC network functions as a decentralized signer of users’ NEAR accounts, controlling all other accounts on different blockchains. The Multichain Gas Relayer consists of off-chain relayers that listen to and compete to execute users&#8217; intents on different chains. Both infrastructures operate externally to any existing blockchain, including NEAR.</p>



<p>LiNEAR&#8217;s liquid restaking solution aims to secure the Chain Signatures MPC network, mitigating the risks of centralization. Similarly, the Multichain Gas Relayer would be able to operate in a trustless manner with restaked verification, removing embedded trust assumptions and enabling users to confidently delegate executions to the relayer network. This entire security framework can be supported by $NEAR and $LiNEAR, and other assets such as $SOL, $BTC, and more in the future, ensuring alignment with different blockchains connected through Chain Abstraction.</p>



<p>NEAR community members interested in restaking can get started on <a href="https://linearprotocol.org/">LiNEAR</a> and help move the network towards a more secure and easy-to-use Web3 world.</p>



<p><strong>About LiNEAR</strong></p>



<p>LiNEAR Protocol is an innovative omnichain liquidity staking/restaking platform and the leading DeFi protocol on NEAR. It pioneered revolutionary features such as automatic validator optimization, which significantly decentralizes and secures the network by allowing users to re-delegate to 200+ validators. LiNEAR offers seamless multichain restaking across multiple networks, such as NEAR, Ethereum, Bitcoin, Solana, and more, ensuring a secure future for a chain-agnostic and chain-abstracted Web3 experience.</p>



<p>Join LiNEAR’s Community</p>



<p><a href="https://linearprotocol.org/">Website</a> | <a href="https://twitter.com/LinearProtocol">Twitter</a> | <a href="https://medium.com/@LiNEAR_LSD">Medium</a> | <a href="https://discord.com/invite/bkkvWwMf2T">Discord</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/linear-protocol-introduces-omnichain-liquid-restaking/">LiNEAR Protocol Introduces Omnichain Liquid Restaking to Advance NEAR’s Chain Abstraction </a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR at NVIDIA GTC 2024: A Recap of Illia’s Appearance</title>
		<link>/blog/nvidia-gtc-2024/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 21:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21290</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At NVIDIA GTC 2024––the flagship conference of the AI hardware supercompany in San Jose, California––the spotlight was on the intersection …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nvidia-gtc-2024/">NEAR at NVIDIA GTC 2024: A Recap of Illia’s Appearance</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>At NVIDIA GTC 2024––the flagship conference of the AI hardware supercompany in San Jose, California––the spotlight was on the intersection of AI, blockchain, and the next era of open web innovation. Among the distinguished speakers was Illia Polosukhin, co-founder of NEAR Protocol, who contributed his insights into how AI models will evolve and how blockchain and token economies can play key roles. Polosukhin is the only blockchain industry founder to speak at the NVIDIA event.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The “Transforming AI” panel was hosted by Jensen Huang, CEO and co-founder of NVIDIA. Appearing on the panel were all but one of&nbsp; the co-authors of the landmark 2017 research paper “Attention is All You Need,” which introduced the Transformer architecture that revolutionized natural language processing. That lineup of coauthors has gone on to work on projects such as OpenAI, Inceptive, and Essential AI.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The group’s conversation explored the practical applications of blockchain technology, with Illia touching on programmable money and its impact on both the current and future states of digital economies. By addressing the challenges and opportunities presented by the convergence of AI and blockchain, Illia offered a grounded perspective on the potential for these technologies to facilitate a more decentralized and efficient open web.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Illia’s&nbsp; insights also highlighted NEAR&#8217;s commitment to leveraging Web3 technologies&nbsp; for broader adoption and innovation across a range of future tech use cases. Jensen himself noted that he thinks “NEAR is very cool.”&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-from-accelerated-computing-to-ai-and-the-blockchain">From Accelerated Computing to AI and the Blockchain</h2>



<p>Jensen kicked off the panel by providing context around the evolution of computing power and the potential of generative AI as the next industrial revolution. After a round of introductions, Illia dove into the beginnings of his research at Google and the unique challenges that brought AI to the forefront during that time.</p>



<p>&#8220;The team and I were working on simple question answering. You’d go to Google, you ask a question, and it should give you an answer,” Illia recounted. “But Google has very low latency requirements, so if you want to ship actual models that read search results, like tons of documents, you need something that can process that quickly. And models at the time just couldn’t do that.&#8221;</p>



<p>After publishing the paper and leaving Google to explore new opportunities, Illia first worked on NEAR as an AI startup, then pivoted when he and co-founder Alex Skidanov recognized an opportunity in the blockchain space they first encountered as users. They recognized a clear need in the space back in 2018: to make blockchain technology accessible and intuitive for everyday use. Illia discussed with the panel how that realization led him to the concept of programmable money, and subsequently built NEAR Protocol to address blockchain scalability and usability challenges, creating a shift towards a more user-friendly open web economy.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-genesis-of-near-and-programmable-money">The Genesis of NEAR and Programmable Money&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Illia further discussed how his shift from pure AI research to Web3 was driven by the concept of programmable money, not just for cross-border payments but for a range of powerful use cases. This was a direct response to the challenges of coordinating on complex networks and the increasing demand for scalable blockchain solutions. The result is a platform that can handle large transaction volumes without compromising speed or security.</p>



<p>“NEAR has the most users in the world in the blockchain space,” Illia explained. “We’re talking about multiple millions of daily users who don’t even know they’re using blockchain. But they’re actually interfacing with programmable money and programmable value. And now we’re bringing back some of those AI tools to generate more data.”</p>



<p>He then highlighted the need for a shift in how creators are rewarded in an emerging age of generative AI, suggesting that the century-old copyright system must evolve. With artists and creators now leveraging tools like Midjourney and OpenAI for everything from visual art to storytelling, the panel agreed that copyright laws will need an overhaul sooner than later.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-integrating-ai-for-fairer-user-and-creator-economies">Integrating AI for Fairer User and Creator Economies</h2>



<p>With the generative age already underway, Illia further unpacked how NEAR will be central to this new AI-enabled creator economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The way we’re rewarding creators right now is broken,” Illia continued. “And the only way to fix that is to leverage programmable money, programmable value, and blockchain. You need the basic primitive of programmable money because it’s what allows users and groups to coordinate people at scale.”</p>



<p>Illia&#8217;s vision extends to building a version of the open web where programmable value underpins a positive feedback loop, fostering a novel economy enriched by equitable participation. For example, he noted that NEAR is exploring ways for users to contribute their own data, which can help improve AI models. These initiatives demonstrate how tomorrow’s AI economy could benefit both creators and users by allowing more participation and collaboration underpinned by Web3 infrastructure and incentives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“I strongly believe that the way we&#8217;re going to make progress towards software eating the world to machine learning is eating software,” Illia argued. “And the most direct way is to teach machines to code, so you&#8217;re able to actually generate software and transform everyone&#8217;s access.”</p>



<p>Throughout his appearance at NVIDIA GTC 2024, Illia underscored NEAR’s pivotal role in bridging the gap between the open web, programmable money, and AI. By advocating for a reimagined copyright framework and more equitable creator compensation models, Illia presented an accessible and compelling vision for NEAR at the forefront of tomorrow’s user and creator centric AI economy. While this was just a brief glimpse of the emerging AI+Web3 ecosystem on NEAR, it was met with a wave of excitement from the NEAR community and served as a reminder for the whole Web3 space about Illia’s and NEAR’s early roots in the world of AI.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nvidia-gtc-2024/">NEAR at NVIDIA GTC 2024: A Recap of Illia’s Appearance</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR Ecosystem @ Korea BUIDL Week 2024</title>
		<link>/blog/korea-buidl-week-2024/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 13:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>MARCH 26 &#8211; APRIL 2, 2024 As the sun rises in the east, a new dawn breaks for NEAR. Fresh …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/korea-buidl-week-2024/">NEAR Ecosystem @ Korea BUIDL Week 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>MARCH 26 &#8211; APRIL 2, 2024</p>



<p>As the sun rises in the east, a new dawn breaks for NEAR. Fresh from ETHDenver, where we planted a firm flag in the ground to own the Chain Abstraction narrative, the NEAR Ecosystem arrives at Korea BUIDL Week 2024 riding a wave of momentum and armed with exciting updates and alpha destined to reshape the blockchain landscape.</p>



<p>Chain Abstraction – a groundbreaking approach that abstracts away the complexities of different blockchain architectures – was a central focus for us at ETHDenver. We captivated attendees with live demonstrations, showcasing Chain Abstraction&#8217;s potential to enable developers to build seamlessly across multiple networks without the need for custom integrations or bridges.</p>



<p>By boldly staking our claim on this game-changing technology, we made a powerful statement at ETHDenver, signaling our intent to lead the charge in unlocking unprecedented levels of cross-chain communication and composability.</p>



<p>Now, as we descend upon Korea BUIDL Week, we are poised to take Chain Abstraction to the global stage, introducing this transformative narrative and its robust, developer-friendly tooling to an international audience of innovators, entrepreneurs, and industry leaders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Developers, builders, researchers, and enthusiasts – join us for a week of events as we continue to push the boundaries of what&#8217;s possible.</p>



<p><strong>NEAR is Everything Everywhere All at Once at Korea BUIDL Week</strong></p>



<p>We&#8217;re hitting the ground running with NEAR Foundation&#8217;s second <a href="https://lu.ma/ChADay_BUIDLAsia24">Chain Abstraction Day (apply-to-attend)</a> in our year long series, taking place March 26, 2024 during Korea BUIDL Week. We&#8217;re doubling down and taking everyone to the moon!<br><br>Our co-founder and CEO, Illia Polosukhin, will be dropping some major alpha at <a href="https://www.buidl.asia/">BUIDL Asia 2024</a>, sharing insights into NEAR&#8217;s vision for Chain Abstraction and how it&#8217;s poised to unlock unprecedented levels of interoperability and composability across decentralized networks.<br></p>



<p>But that&#8217;s not all – we&#8217;re bringing the heat with dedicated workshops, content, and a massive hackathon bounty prize up for grabs at <a href="https://www.ethseoul.org/">ETH Seoul</a>, challenging the brilliant minds of the blockchain world to push the boundaries of Chain Abstraction. Developers, builders, and innovators: get ready to bring your A-game and compete for this lucrative reward.</p>



<p>Don&#8217;t miss your shot at NEAR&#8217;s massive hackathon bounty prizes at ETHSeoul &#8211; <a href="https://ethseoul2024.devfolio.co/">check out the link</a> to see what lucrative rewards await the winners. <a href="https://ethseoul2024.devfolio.co/">Register for the hackathon</a> today and let your skills shine on the global stage.<br></p>



<p>And if that&#8217;s not enough, NEAR is also proud to support <a href="https://lu.ma/shefisummmitseoul">SheFi Summit Seoul</a>, empowering women builders in Web3. This groundbreaking event showcases the incredible female talent in our ecosystem, with NEAR women taking the stage to share their visionary work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Abstractooors, you won’t want to miss the fun!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/korea-buidl-week-2024/">NEAR Ecosystem @ Korea BUIDL Week 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Graph Expands Subgraph Support to NEAR and 40+ Blockchains</title>
		<link>/blog/the-graph-expands-subgraph-support-to-near-and-40-blockchains/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 17:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21275</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Graph Foundation recently announced the inclusion of NEAR into its expansive subgraph support, now encompassing over 40 leading L1 …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/the-graph-expands-subgraph-support-to-near-and-40-blockchains/">The Graph Expands Subgraph Support to NEAR and 40+ Blockchains</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Graph Foundation recently announced the inclusion of NEAR into its expansive subgraph support, now encompassing over 40 leading L1 and L2 blockchains including Arbitrum, Base, Fantom, Celo, Optimism, Polygon Labs, and Scroll. By integrating with The Graph, NEAR developers gain access to a decentralized network for streamlined data querying, significantly reducing costs and improving synchronization speeds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The partnership highlights the NEAR Foundation&#8217;s ongoing commitment to enhancing developer resources and interoperability within open web ecosystems as part of advancing the Chain Abstraction vision. In 2021, NEAR became The Graph&#8217;s <a href="https://thegraph.com/blog/graph-near/">first non-EVM chain integration</a> for its hosted service, kickstarting the evolution towards a multichain open web ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Subgraph support will take things a step further, facilitating better multichain data accessibility for NEAR builders and increasing the reach and breadth of tools and technologies to support Chain Abstraction. This moment also marks NEAR as the first non-EVM chain to become available on The Graph Network.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-how-subgraph-support-empowers-near-developers">How Subgraph Support Empowers NEAR Developers</h2>



<p>Subgraphs on The Graph are transformative open APIs that efficiently organize and serve blockchain data, accelerating the development of decentralized applications (dApps) on the NEAR Protocol. This integration offers developers further support in efficient data querying, swift access to indexed blockchain data, and seamless interoperability across multiple chains.</p>



<p>By streamlining data retrieval, The Graph&#8217;s subgraph support eliminates the need for exhaustive blockchain scans, allowing for quick navigation, filtering, and location of specific data points. This advancement equips NEAR developers with tools similar to Web 2.0 search engine capabilities, tailored for the precision and complexity of blockchain data.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-graph-s-multichain-support-and-expansion-goals">The Graph&#8217;s Multichain Support and Expansion Goals&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The Graph&#8217;s integration with NEAR and over 40 additional blockchains is a step towards more rich multichain development. By extending beyond Ethereum, The Graph is facilitating a unified, accessible ecosystem for designing advanced, user-focused decentralized applications (dApps) across a diverse range of blockchains.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Enhancing interoperability among different blockchain networks also grants developers access to a broader spectrum of data, supporting the creation of dApps that are both feature-dense and user-friendly. These improvements also promote more unrestricted data exchange across chains for the purposes of dApp development.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-protocol-and-future-of-the-graph-network">NEAR Protocol and Future of The Graph Network</h2>



<p>Looking forward, The Graph Network is aiming to break the barriers of decentralized access to blockchain data, as it plans to introduce new data services to meet the growing needs of Web3. The Graph’s core devs are planning ahead on executing the “<a href="https://thegraph.com/blog/unveiling-updated-sunrise-decentralized-data/">Sunrise of decentralized data</a>” initiative, designed to improve tooling and developer experience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Soon, NEAR devs building on The Graph Network will be able to take advantage of a free query plan, an intuitive subgraph upgrade wizard, and more. The Graph-NEAR Foundation collaboration will further emphasize the shared mission of both teams for a more interconnected and inclusive Web3 ecosystem via Chain Abstraction, enhancing the value of indexing and querying blockchain data.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/the-graph-expands-subgraph-support-to-near-and-40-blockchains/">The Graph Expands Subgraph Support to NEAR and 40+ Blockchains</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FRAX Deploys Decentralized Stablecoin Infrastructure on NEAR Protocol</title>
		<link>/blog/frax-deploys-decentralized-stablecoin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Frax Finance announced the launch of FRAX stablecoin on NEAR via Ref Finance and Burrow through FraxFerry and the Rainbow …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/frax-deploys-decentralized-stablecoin/">FRAX Deploys Decentralized Stablecoin Infrastructure on NEAR Protocol</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Frax Finance announced the launch of FRAX stablecoin on NEAR via Ref Finance and Burrow through FraxFerry and the Rainbow Bridge. This marks a significant milestone for Frax as its first major venture into a non-Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM) ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Frax Finance is the second-largest issuer of decentralized dollar-pegged stablecoins and an industry leader for DeFi infrastructure.</p>



<p>The NEAR ecosystem and Frax contributors will now collaborate through ongoing in-depth research and protocol integrations. One of the biggest opportunities between the two teams will be the introduction of short-term treasury yields on NEAR using sFRAX, a yield-bearing asset that tracks the Federal Reserve&#8217;s Interest on Reserve Balance (IORB).</p>



<p>In the coming months, Frax will natively issue their suite of assets, FRAX, sFRAX, frxETH, and sfrxETH on NEAR and Fraxtal, along with exploring opportunities around NEAR LSTs. Other protocols on NEAR will also be able to explore these exciting frontiers with Frax. While NEAR supports various stablecoins, the decentralized Frax platform sets itself apart by offering additional features like yield and LSTs. These offerings can be utilized by NEAR&#8217;s DeFi protocols for novel ventures.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This deployment is led by Ref and Burrow and will soon expand to other protocols. <a href="https://www.ref.finance/">Ref Finance</a> is a decentralized finance (DeFi) platform built on NEAR Protocol, designed to facilitate the swapping, lending, and borrowing of digital assets. It is a multi-purpose DeFi platform that integrates various financial mechanisms, offering users a comprehensive suite of DeFi tools. <a href="https://burrow.finance/">Burrow</a> is a decentralized finance (DeFi) platform on the NEAR blockchain, offering non-custodial, pool-based lending and borrowing services.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Highlighting the Incentive Campaign</strong></p>



<p>To boost activity and foster growth of Frax on NEAR, Ref will introduce an incentive program offering rewards for Liquidity Providers (LPs) in the USDC/FRAX and NEAR/FRAX pools, as well as the Curve style stableswap pools.</p>



<p>The proliferation of native stablecoins is crucial to the growth of DeFi as it facilitates effortless access to liquidity between protocols for users across various types of exchanges. This allows for more seamless interactions with different projects across the Web3 ecosystem, effectively removing bottlenecks and promoting a smooth trading experience. This also advances the NEAR ecosystem vision of Chain Abstraction, streamlining usability and defragmenting liquidity and UX across all of Web3. Moreover, native stablecoins will significantly enhance the visibility of the NEAR Ecosystem&#8217;s Total Value Locked (TVL) within the market.</p>



<p>On Burrow, borrowers and lenders will earn incentives for using USDC, USDT, and FRAX. Additionally, Burrow will offer rewards for NEAR and liquid staked NEAR, with more details to be announced soon.</p>



<p>This incentive campaign will be expanded&nbsp; to other qualifying DeFi protocols and primitives after the initial rollout on Ref and Burrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you’re new to NEAR, you can find free resources for building apps, deploying smart contracts,creating blockchain operating system(BOS) components, and more on the <a href="https://docs.near.org/#">DevRel resources page.&nbsp;</a>Checkout the official documentation of <a href="https://docs.frax.finance/">Frax</a> to learn more about protocol and other technical specifications.&nbsp;</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/frax-deploys-decentralized-stablecoin/">FRAX Deploys Decentralized Stablecoin Infrastructure on NEAR Protocol</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PotLock and NEAR Foundation Partner to Accelerate Public Goods Funding (PGF)</title>
		<link>/blog/potlock-and-near-foundation-partner-to-accelerate-public-goods-funding-pgf/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 15:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Foundation is proud to announce the inaugural launch of Near Public Goods Funding (NEARPGF) together with PotLock, a new …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/potlock-and-near-foundation-partner-to-accelerate-public-goods-funding-pgf/">PotLock and NEAR Foundation Partner to Accelerate Public Goods Funding (PGF)</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR Foundation is proud to announce the inaugural launch of Near Public Goods Funding (NEARPGF) together with <a href="https://bos.potlock.org/">PotLock</a>, a new quadratic funding (QF) platform on NEAR. NEAR Foundation is allocating $100,000+ in initial funding to pilot funding campaigns conducted through PotLock. This initial contribution aims to empower promising and impactful projects building within the NEAR ecosystem.</p>



<p>Launched in late February, PotLock provides an opportunity for developers and innovators to showcase their projects and for the community to financially support the projects they believe in. By leveraging QF, resources will be allocated more democratically, ensuring projects with widespread community support receive the necessary financial backing to continue building.</p>



<p>The partnership between NEAR Foundation and PotLock will advance innovation across the NEAR ecosystem. From funding open-source developers and AI contributors, to startups in Africa building on NEAR, the goal of the partnership and of NEARPGF more broadly is to catalyze the building of public goods in the NEAR ecosystem.<br><br>Through this partnership, NEAR Foundation and PotLock aim to transform public goods funding into a collaborative, community-driven process. This vision reflects a joint commitment to cultivating an ecosystem where innovation, public utility, and equitable opportunities are at the forefront. By demanding greater accountability and measurable impact from funding recipients, while simultaneously providing a platform for fair compensation and recognition of contributions, the NEAR Foundation and PotLock are setting a new standard for public goods funding within the NEAR ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-qf-rounds-aka-pots">QF Rounds (AKA: “Pots”)</h2>



<p>PotLock’s QF rounds focus on specific areas for growth and innovation within the NEAR ecosystem. The verticals for this round include:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Africa Round </strong>(March 5 &#8211; March 24th): Managed by NEAR Africa, this $3,000 round aims to empower communities and startups across Africa. It seeks to drive regional development, attract new donors, and strengthen existing projects with transformative potential.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Retroactive Builders Round </strong>(March 18th &#8211; April 7)<strong>: </strong>Managed by Build DAO, this $30,000 round rewards builders in the NEAR ecosystem who previously developed open-source projects without compensation.&nbsp;</li>



<li><strong>Open Source Round </strong>(April 22 &#8211; May 5): Overseen by Banyan Collective, this $22,000 round targets a broad range of open-source projects, aiming to support initiatives that contribute to the public good of the NEAR ecosystem.<br><strong>AI Round </strong>(April 22 &#8211; May 5): Managed by Edge Intelligence, this $45,000 round aims to seed and support strategic open source AI builders and contributors.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-understanding-qf">Understanding QF</h2>



<p>Quadratic Funding (QF) aims to revolutionize the way projects receive support by emphasizing the importance of community engagement and collective decision-making. Here&#8217;s how it accomplishes this: </p>



<p><strong>1. Broadening Participation through Small Contributions</strong>: QF encourages participation from all community members by giving significant value to numerous small donations rather than relying solely on a few large ones. This approach diversifies the funding base, allowing a wider array of projects to gain support.xr</p>



<p><strong>2. Enhanced Support with Matching Funds</strong>: Donations are not just contributions; they&#8217;re leveraged through a matching fund. The unique aspect of QF is the use of a quadratic formula to determine the amount of matching funds a project receives. This formula is designed to ensure that projects with a wider base of community support receive a larger portion of the matching funds, thus rewarding projects that appeal to a broader audience.</p>



<p><strong>3. Preventing Manipulation with Advanced Verification</strong>: To maintain the fairness and integrity of the funding process, PotLock utilizes NadaBot, an innovative identity aggregator built on NEAR protocol. NadaBot&#8217;s role is essential in verifying the uniqueness of each participant&#8217;s identity, effectively countering attempts at Sybil attacks where individuals could try to exert undue influence by creating multiple fake identities. </p>



<p>Through these mechanisms, QF seeks to make the process of supporting public goods and initiatives more democratic, ensuring that funding is distributed in a manner that truly represents the interests and priorities of the community.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-s-strategic-funding-objectives">NEAR’s Strategic Funding Objectives</h2>



<p>The NEAR Foundation&#8217;s collaboration with PotLock aims to revitalize the ecosystem and drive innovation through the following objectives:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Equitable Compensation</strong>: Ensure fair compensation for creators of public goods, focusing on undiscovered or under-resourced contributors to recognize their value within the NEAR ecosystem.</li>



<li><strong>Cultivating a Supportive Ecosystem</strong>: Foster a culture that recognizes and rewards contributions, reducing dependence on grants and promoting a self-sustaining community spirit.</li>



<li><strong>Innovative Funding Framework</strong>: Implement a proactive funding approach to stimulate ecosystem dynamism, by exploring novel funding strategies to engage projects across NEAR Social, NEAR Horizon, and DAO tooling.</li>



<li><strong>Enhanced Visibility and Community Engagement</strong>: Increase awareness and participation in public goods and impact initiatives, driving community engagement and spotlighting meaningful projects within the ecosystem.</li>



<li><strong>External Support and Dynamic Sponsorships</strong>: Attract external partners to support these initiatives, enriching the ecosystem through diverse partnerships and sponsorships.</li>



<li><strong>Community Empowerment</strong>: Assist smaller NEAR communities in launching and managing their own funding cycles, ensuring widespread impact across the ecosystem.</li>



<li><strong>Stakeholder Engagement</strong>: Collaborate with a broad range of stakeholders to evaluate the effectiveness of funding allocations and its overall impact on ecosystem growth.</li>
</ul>



<p>By achieving these objectives, the NEAR Foundation envisions a stronger, more innovative ecosystem where equitable compensation and broad participation drive further development in the Web3 space.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-how-potlock-facilitates-funding-rounds">How PotLock Facilitates Funding Rounds</h2>



<p>PotLock operates in distinct phases, each essential to the QF cycle:<br><br><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/QKDaXM-6PZRyOk6BZ44dARUQs8amT2pGrUIr-WoisNH6JD4-gHRLBPy7gGwuox9VgR5dl9mgEK77DR5FuOBtUGiJqG_ztlVLhYkA3ZT7cITRhO04O0xCNUZ0YKuEiAf0FuN2_GQmE1516qL7_DEl-2M" width="602" height="339"></p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Activation</strong>: Once a “Pot” is initiated, participants can donate to a Pot, with their contributions matched by funds from the NEAR Foundation. Donors are recognized on a visual sponsor board.</li>



<li><strong>Application and Review</strong>: Projects submit applications to participate in the funding round. A designated authority, known as a Chef, reviews these submissions for eligibility and potential impact, selecting which will proceed to the matching phase.</li>



<li><strong>Donation and Matching:</strong> Approved projects receive direct contributions from verified donors, amplified by the QF model at the round&#8217;s close, ensuring widespread fund distribution and community engagement.</li>



<li><strong>Payout</strong>: After the matching phase, funds are distributed to projects, followed by a cooldown period before the next cycle begins.</li>
</ul>



<p>PotLock leverages an advanced asset-locking mechanism, allowing funders to securely store their digital assets in vaults protected by smart contracts. This feature is crucial for projects seeking funding, as it assures both security and accessibility of funds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PotLock fosters transparency and verifiability by providing real-time insights into fund movements and allocations. This transparency builds trust by ensuring that funds are used ethically and effectively.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For a detailed understanding of each step and to participate, visit the PotLock’s <a href="https://docs.potlock.io/">documentation</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLJxhkGinB9L-7x-frtiWYPx9AaxSwA5nl">tutorial sections</a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-getting-involved">Getting Involved</h2>



<p>To participate in PotLock’s QF rounds, follow these steps:</p>



<ol>
<li><strong>Project Submission</strong>: Submissions are now <a href="https://bos.potlock.org/?tab=pots">open</a>! Submit your project on the PotLock platform for the upcoming funding cycle <a href="https://bos.potlock.org/?tab=pots">here</a>.</li>



<li><strong>Community Engagement</strong>: Stay informed by joining NEAR&#8217;s Telegram group for discussions, following updates on <a href="https://twitter.com/potlock_?lang=en">Twitter</a> or <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/potlock/">LinkedIn</a>, and subscribing to the <a href="https://subscribe.potlock.org/">newsletter </a>for the latest information.</li>



<li><strong>Fund Projects</strong>: During open funding rounds, verified humans will review projects and contribute to those they believe will positively impact the NEAR ecosystem.</li>
</ol>



<p>All NEAR community members are invited to engage with NEARPGF by <a href="https://docs.potlock.io/user-guides/create-your-project">submitting projects</a> to PotLock that can leverage NEAR technology or by contributing to the funding rounds supporting ecosystem growth. Broad engagement and participation are key to identifying the best projects that will drive innovation on NEAR and expand decision-making about resource allocation to a wider pool of NEAR believers.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/potlock-and-near-foundation-partner-to-accelerate-public-goods-funding-pgf/">PotLock and NEAR Foundation Partner to Accelerate Public Goods Funding (PGF)</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR @ ETHDenver Breakdown: We Came, We Saw, We Abstracted!</title>
		<link>/blog/near-ethdenver-round-up/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 14:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21261</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR&#8217;s presence at ETHDenver was nothing short of a triumph, demonstrating that collaboration is the key to success in the …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-ethdenver-round-up/">NEAR @ ETHDenver Breakdown: We Came, We Saw, We Abstracted!</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR&#8217;s presence at ETHDenver was nothing short of a triumph, demonstrating that collaboration is the key to success in the ever-evolving world of cryptocurrency. Forget about going it alone &#8211; NEAR brought the entire ecosystem to the party, and the results were epic.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-here-s-a-taste-of-the-near-flavored-goodness-that-went-down">Here&#8217;s A Taste Of The Near-Flavored Goodness That Went Down</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/nwiUAYBQhJMWYE14tyx-q6OvXfuwZawUuK09DFXd0J6fF4N9Ov2PUzMAc_qZxSQ2fqdizxS0VtdukuN-XfoVwxaDcaP3uXT2nj_J9wTXpmDdo7J5PvHyBdHYEiHra2xYrHM7jfGFJ3CvSx7N65WfJ40" alt=""/></figure>



<p>The week kicked off with Altan Tutar&#8217;s insightful presentation, &#8220;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PrWs1ty2fXo">The Future of DeFi: NEAR Protocol&#8217;s Role and Potential</a>,&#8221; where he shared NEAR’s DeFi vision, addressing fragmentation and modularity. NEAR aims to become the single platform seamlessly connecting users to DeFi applications across different blockchains.</p>



<p>Illia Polosukhin, NEAR&#8217;s co-founder and CEO, followed suit at the Decentralized AGI Summit. His panel, &#8220;The Evolution to AGI,&#8221; explored the development of sovereign digital AGI and its ethical implications. He emphasized the need to balance centralization and decentralization to foster community ownership and innovation. Keeping AI in check is crucial, after all.</p>



<p>But that wasn’t his only appearance. Illia managed to be ubiquitous across ETHDenver, including an exciting main stage talk with <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=32DKp9CX4NQ">Erik Voorhees on decentralizing AI</a>. He also delivered a captivating presentation on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=m5jJkvCG338">Digital Self-Sovereignty in the Age of AI</a> just before presidential candidate Robert F. Kennedy Jr. took the stage for ETHDenver’s closing session.</p>



<p>The education continued with Kendall Cole from Proximity Labs, who provided insights into <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gCkOTjbJD3c">Threshold Signatures and how they unlock the magic of bridgeless cross-chain interoperability</a>. By enabling &#8220;bridgeless&#8221; cross-chain applications, this technology empowers developers to create applications that seamlessly work across different blockchains, even those without smart contracts like Bitcoin or Dogecoin, using programmable multi-party computation (MPC). Users can interact with these applications effortlessly while security remains ensured through MPC signing nodes.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WzjDN0MG09c">Bowen Wang from Pagoda dove into Stateless validation</a>, addressing both scalability and decentralization. This approach tackles the ever-growing state size by allowing validators to operate without storing the entire history, significantly reducing storage pressure and potentially enabling more powerful hardware and lower costs, fostering a more decentralized network over time. Furthermore, stateless validation using zero-knowledge proofs holds promise for even greater scalability and affordability &#8211; more power to the validators!</p>



<p>Finally, NEAR Foundation’s COO, Chris Donovan, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xPGGJYqSkSM">championed chain abstraction as the key to breaking down the barriers currently fragmenting the Web3 future</a>. The fragmented landscape of blockchains presents a hurdle to widespread adoption and collaboration within Web3. By simplifying the user experience and fostering collaboration across the industry, chain abstraction paves the way for a frictionless and prosperous Web3 future. Think of it as a universal translator for blockchains.</p>



<p>Phew, That was a lot! But NEAR&#8217;s impact went far beyond informative talks. The NEAR booth was ground zero for epicness, attracting big names.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-near-experience-a-journey-down-the-rabbit-hole">The NEAR Experience: A Journey Down the Rabbit Hole</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/-WssyoSbSSQR82cuha_E5m7qaW_Vb2H-vdyNSZn0aNnZPvS3efZXjZ8rQTlluj-GKXIl0qzHJt03izLs0Tyry8uJ7LGXGLbI2CAl-gZiFF9j6Zgt68sVaeyNzimyUnXiFRJUPZyMeZ3B7bxLiSJw1WE" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Forget the standard, white-walled conference booths – the NEAR experience was a sensory explosion. Transformed into an immersive Alice in Wonderland inspired world called &#8220;NEAR in ETHerland,&#8221; it captivated attendees with whimsical tea parties and interactive installations. Unlike the usual Web3 frustrations, NEAR offered attendees a playful sip of the future with their &#8220;NEAR Chain Abstraction Pill&#8221;, symbolizing a smooth, enjoyable blockchain experience.</p>



<p>Stepping into the booth was like falling down the rabbit hole into a world of infinite possibilities. The playful atmosphere sparked curiosity, fostering engaging conversations and leaving attendees buzzing with excitement. The NEAR booth wasn&#8217;t just a booth; it was a conversation starter, a community builder, and an unforgettable experience that left everyone wanting more, solidifying NEAR&#8217;s place as a creative powerhouse.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-chain-abstraction-day-unveiling-the-cake-framework">Chain Abstraction Day: Unveiling the CAKE Framework</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/QruvOCuEh415yrpbIOQFBadPR9Pnfs2WzEklua71JS3Du7IEWDlcAxjgk8CufvjXvatb_0cGOCL8KXs01NfXwa6Ke1i2Z56dHctdhv7iQz30RJY2jQ5FQZFqFpX29TrvkE0WTP1JR9FD1Zx6vDMQ00Y" alt=""/></figure>



<p>NEAR, in partnership with Frontier Research and Agoric, hosted Chain Abstraction Day, a massive event that attracted over 1,200 attendees. This gathering brought together the brightest minds in blockchain, including industry leaders like Sreeram Kannan from EigenLayer and Adrian Brink from Anoma. The day was filled with insightful discussions and collaboration, fostering a shared vision for the future of Web3. We even got to see a live demo showcasing the ability to pay for a <a href="https://twitter.com/SweatEconomy/status/1763196327440048479?s=20">transaction on the BNB chain using $SWEAT</a>, completely abstracted from the user, providing a glimpse into the future of chain abstraction.</p>



<p>A cornerstone of the event was unveiling the CAKE framework (Chain Abstraction Key Elements). This framework provides a foundational understanding of chain abstraction and paves the way for further exploration. Discussions dived into cutting-edge topics like threshold signatures, multi-chain settlements, and abstracted security. The day culminated in the forming of the CAKE working group, a dedicated team committed to pushing the boundaries of chain abstraction.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ai-x-web3-hackathon">AI x Web3 Hackathon</h2>



<p>NEAR actively participated in and supported the AI x Web3 hackathon organized by Edge. This participation reflects the growing momentum and enthusiasm surrounding the convergence of artificial intelligence and Web3 technologies, even though the specific applications and direction of this space are still evolving.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-looking-ahead-launch-and-beyond">Looking Ahead: Launch and Beyond</h2>



<p>ETHDenver was just the beginning for NEAR’s Chain Abstraction vision. The momentum continues at BUIDL Asia 2024, where NEAR promises to unveil even more groundbreaking developments with the launch of Chain Signatures, Relayers, and Web Engine scheduled for the end of March. This marks a significant milestone in NEAR&#8217;s journey towards establishing itself as a leader in chain abstraction.</p>



<p>Till’ next time Abstractooors!</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/near-ethdenver-round-up/">NEAR @ ETHDenver Breakdown: We Came, We Saw, We Abstracted!</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
