<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Multichain Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/multichain/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/multichain/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 13:18:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Multichain Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/multichain/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">234542837</site>	<item>
		<title>Chain Signatures Mainnet Launches: Smart Contracts Can Sign Transactions on Any Blockchain</title>
		<link>/blog/chain-signatures-mainnet-launches/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 13:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chain Abstraction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chain Signatures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Multichain]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21478</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Today marks the official Mainnet release of Chain Signatures, a groundbreaking Chain Abstraction solution built on NEAR. With the testnet phase and security audit now complete, developers can fully leverage Chain Signatures’ unique omnichain capabilities for their dApps on Mainnet. Degens and end users can now enjoy a fully chain abstracted user experience (UX) on the first cohort of Chain Signatures products already live on mainnet.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/chain-signatures-mainnet-launches/">Chain Signatures Mainnet Launches: Smart Contracts Can Sign Transactions on Any Blockchain</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Today marks the official Mainnet release of Chain Signatures, a groundbreaking Chain Abstraction solution built on NEAR. With the testnet phase and security audit now complete, developers can fully leverage Chain Signatures’ unique omnichain capabilities for their dApps on Mainnet. Degens and end users can now enjoy a fully chain abstracted user experience (UX) on the first cohort of Chain Signatures products already live on mainnet.</p>



<p>Chain Signatures utilizes a decentralized multi-party computation (MPC) network enabling NEAR accounts to sign transactions on any blockchain protocol. Chain Signatures are the only MPC solution where smart contracts can sign transactions on any chain and for any number of accounts. This is because accounts are smart contracts by default in the unique NEAR account model.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Chain Signatures reduce the work of multichain dApp development to a single layer: a smart contract on NEAR that can talk to all other chains. In this way, Chain Signatures abstract away the complexity and hassle of multichain dApps, for developers and users alike, and open up an entirely new design space of applications and user interfaces for Web3. Additionally, while existing bridges or cross-chain messaging protocols cannot support all chains or scale at speed, Chain Signatures can support every blockchain without native integration, whether Ethereum, Bitcoin, the Cosmos ecosystem, or (soon) Solana.</p>



<p>Five applications with more than 6 million active users between them are already using Chain Signatures Mainnet as of launch, with more than fifteen projects actively building. Soon there will be a full ecosystem of Chain Signatures products across this new design space, ranging across wallets, DEXs, lending, trading bots, bridges, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><a href="https://sweateconomy.com/">Sweat Wallet</a>: 2.5 million active Sweat Wallet users (on NEAR) can bridge assets to and from any chain, starting with BNB and Base, while paying for gas in $SWEAT.</li>



<li><a href="https://allstake.org/">Allstake</a>: Allstake is now live at Phase 0 with mainnet launch on NEAR, Solana, and Ethereum, supporting top LST and LRT protocols such as LiNEAR Protocol, MetaPool, Marinade, Jito, Renzo, and EtherFi.</li>



<li><a href="https://www.herewallet.app/">HERE Wallet</a>: Mobile, Web, and Telegram wallet supporting transactions on any chain. Check out this Hot Protocol (by Here Wallet) <a href="https://youtu.be/8fkgr7avNZA">demo</a>.</li>



<li><a href="https://wallet.bitte.ai/">Bitte Wallet</a>: Passkey wallets for any chain, including Bitcoin. Connect to all Ethereum apps with Bitte Wallet using WalletConnect. Watch a demo of how Bitte Wallet is using Chain Signatures <a href="https://youtu.be/0IoMCmvcjNY?si=0NJtvYGem_1iEyiL">here</a>.</li>



<li><a href="http://defuse.org/">Defuse</a>: Truly multichain spot DEX. Trade between any assets on any chain in seconds. See how NEAR Chain Signatures are transforming DeFi in this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xERiqWPD6Gk&amp;feature=youtu.be">demo</a>.</li>
</ul>



<p>Kendall Cole of <a href="http://proximity.dev/">Proximity Labs</a> – a contributor to Chain Signatures – said, &#8220;Chain Signatures is pivotal to replacing the fragmented Web3 landscape with a single user and developer layer that addresses current interoperability challenges. This innovation simplifies the user experience, enables DeFi for blockchains like Bitcoin that do not traditionally support smart contracts, and empowers developers to support all chains seamlessly. By eliminating the need for bridges, Chain Signatures can significantly expand the liquidity and utility of assets across various blockchains. We&#8217;re excited to see Chain Abstraction in the wild, transforming how users and developers interact with decentralized finance and making it more accessible.&#8221;</p>



<p>Another key layer of the Chain Signatures stack is the Multichain Gas Relayer. Instead of forcing users to acquire a separate gas token every time they transact on a new chain, the Multichain Gas Relayer performs the gas payment on the destination chain, on the user’s behalf. The user only needs to pay the equivalent amount in an asset they already hold, whether that’s NEAR or other NEAR-native fungible tokens (such as USDC or USDT). The power of Chain Signatures, together with the gas abstraction of the Multichain Gas Relayer, offers a streamlined user experience as exemplified by top dApps like Sweat Wallet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Illia Polosukhin, Co-Founder of Near Protocol and CEO of NEAR Foundation, added, &#8220;Chain Signatures is a game-changing innovation that brings Chain Abstraction to life. Whereas before we had fragmented liquidity in DeFi, now there will be a single DeFi layer for all chains. There is no more need for dozens of wallets and addresses, manual bridging, and paying gas fees in every token. Instead, all of DeFi is accessible from wherever users already are. It’s all possible because smart contracts can now sign transactions for any blockchain, even Bitcoin. This opens up a whole new design space for financial apps in Web3, benefitting degens and also paving the way for new user bases.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>As of mainnet launch, Chain Signatures’ MPC network is secured by eight reputable validators: <a href="https://www.pagoda.co/">Pagoda</a>, <a href="https://www.luganodes.com/">Luganodes</a>, <a href="https://liftedinit.org/">The Lifted Initiative</a>, <a href="https://infstones.com/">InfStones</a>, <a href="https://www.staking4all.org/">Staking4All</a>, <a href="https://node.monster/">Node.Monster,</a> <a href="https://blacksand.xyz/">Black Sand Technologies</a>, and <a href="https://aurora.dev/">Aurora</a>. The initial audit for the Chain Signatures protocol has been conducted by <a href="https://kudelskisecurity.com/">Kudelski</a>, the final report of which will be published soon on the Chain Signatures GitHub.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Chain Signatures development roadmap includes adding EDDSA support before the end of the year, increasing throughput, and increasing the number of nodes. As of mainnet launch, Chain Signatures supports all blockchain protocols based on the ECDSA elliptic curve, which includes most chains such as Ethereum, Bitcoin, Dogecoin, and recently, NEAR. With the additional support for the EDDSA elliptic curve (e.g. Solana, TON), Chain Signatures will be able to sign transactions on every known blockchain by Q4 2024. By the end of the year, Chain Signatures will aim to increase throughput up to 300 transactions/second to match NEAR’s sharded capacity. Finally, the number of validators on the network will gradually increase over time with the aim of achieving 40+ highly independent nodes, which would require 27 for a single signature.</p>



<p>For all app builders in Web3 who want to build multichain experiences from day one, explore these resources and start building:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Chain Signatures: <a href="/blog/getting-started-with-chain-signatures/">Getting Started Guide</a></li>



<li>Multichain Gas Relayer: <a href="https://docs.near.org/build/chain-abstraction/multichain-gas-relayer/getting-started">Getting Started Guide</a></li>



<li><a href="https://form.jotform.com/240777569453167">Request support</a> for building with Chain Signatures</li>



<li>Join the Chain Abstraction Dev Group on <a href="https://t.me/+RXYjlPob_XM5N2Ex">Telegram</a></li>
</ul>



<p>All the above resources and more can be found on the Chain Signatures landing page: <a href="https://near.org/chain-abstraction">https://near.org/chain-abstraction</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/chain-signatures-mainnet-launches/">Chain Signatures Mainnet Launches: Smart Contracts Can Sign Transactions on Any Blockchain</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21478</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting Started with Chain Signatures</title>
		<link>/blog/getting-started-with-chain-signatures/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 22:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chain Abstraction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chain Signatures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Multichain]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21468</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What is Chain Signatures? Chain Signatures is a groundbreaking technology built on NEAR that enables NEAR accounts, including smart contracts, …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/getting-started-with-chain-signatures/">Getting Started with Chain Signatures</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is Chain Signatures?</h2>



<p>Chain Signatures is a groundbreaking technology built on NEAR that enables NEAR accounts, including smart contracts, to sign and execute transactions across multiple blockchains. This innovation leverages Multi-Party Computation (MPC) and a distributed network of node operators to create joint signatures from arbitrary payloads, allowing NEAR users to control external blockchain accounts. This technology enhances blockchain interoperability, giving ownership of diverse assets, cross-chain accounts, and data to a single NEAR account.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Does It Work?</h2>



<p>Chain Signatures operates through a series of steps to enable seamless cross-chain transactions:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Deriving Foreign Addresses:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Chain Signatures uses derivation paths to represent accounts on foreign blockchains.</li>



<li>The NEAR account’s name and the derivation path are used to mathematically <a href="https://docs.near.org/concepts/abstraction/chain-signatures#derivation-paths-one-account-multiple-chains">derive a unique address</a> for the user on the foreign blockchain.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Creating the Transaction:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>The client constructs the hash of the transaction to be signed, which varies by the target blockchain.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Requesting the Signature:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>A NEAR account or smart contract calls the sign method of the MPC smart contract (<a href="https://nearblocks.io/address/v1.signer">v1.signer</a>) to sign a payload.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Relaying the Signature:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>The client reconstructs the valid transaction using the signature and broadcasts it to the destination blockchain.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>



<p>This process eliminates the need for traditional bridges and enables developers to build innovative cross-chain DeFi applications with seamless user experiences.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Use Cases</h2>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>DeFi on Bitcoin (and other chain without smart contracts)</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Chain signatures allow NEAR smart contract to program assets on Bitcoin.</li>



<li>Build lending, swaps, runes launchpads, passkey-based Bitcoin wallets, and more.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Chain agnostic applications</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Since chain signatures can sign transactions for all blockchains, developers can support every single chain with just one smart contract.</li>



<li>Multichain DEXs, lending protocols, oracles, derivatives, and more.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Multichain account abstraction </strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Users can control assets on all chains with just their NEAR account, and can utilize account abstraction features on any chain including passkeys, key rotation, etc.</li>



<li>Using the multichain gas relayer, users can pay for gas fees on any chain using USDC.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Privacy</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Chain signatures can be used to encrypt and decrypt information in a programmatic way.</li>



<li>This enables privacy applications, and even decrypting information based on ownership of assets/NFTs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to Get Started?</h2>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Familiarize Yourself with Chain Signatures:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Understand the <a href="https://docs.near.org/concepts/abstraction/chain-signatures">basics of Chain Signatures</a> and how they simplify blockchain interactions.</li>



<li>Review the technical <a href="https://near.org/blog/unlocking-web3-usability-with-account-aggregation">explainer</a>.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Explore the Use Cases:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Review <a href="/blog/unlocking-multichain-web3-with-near-chain-signatures/">examples of use cases for Chain Signatures</a>, such as Multichain DAO, Multichain NFT Minter, and Bitcoin Runes Airdrop.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Access Resources and Documentation:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Visit the <a href="https://docs.near.org/build/chain-abstraction/chain-signatures">Chain Signatures documentation</a> for detailed technical information and code snippets.</li>



<li>Check out the <a href="https://linktr.ee/chainsignatures">Linktree for Chain Signatures</a> for various resources, including demos and tutorials.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Try the Demos:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Use the <a href="https://github.com/near-examples/chainsig-script">command-line-based demo</a> to derive accounts and send transactions on Bitcoin, Ethereum, Doge, and Ripple.</li>



<li>Check out the <a href="https://github.com/near-examples/near-multichain/tree/main">web app demo</a>.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Engage with the Community:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Join the <a href="https://t.me/chain_abstraction">Chain Abstraction developers’ channel on Telegram</a> to connect with other developers and get support.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Where to Learn More?</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Technical Blogs and Deep Dives:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Read <a href="/blog/unlocking-multichain-web3-with-near-chain-signatures">high-level use cases</a> and technical <a href="https://near.org/blog/unlocking-web3-usability-with-account-aggregation">explainer</a> posts on the NEAR blog.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Community and Support:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Engage with the NEAR community on <a href="http://x.com/nearprotocol">X</a> and participate in <a href="https://t.me/chain_abstraction">discussions</a> to stay updated on the latest developments.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/getting-started-with-chain-signatures/">Getting Started with Chain Signatures</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21468</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Chain Abstraction Is the Next Frontier for Web3</title>
		<link>/blog/why-chain-abstraction-is-the-next-frontier-for-web3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Illia Polosukhin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 19:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[A Post from Illia Polosukhin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chain Abstraction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mission & vision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Multichain]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21182</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Most of today’s dapps are not actually dapps, i.e. decentralized applications. If you need to leave the app in order …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/why-chain-abstraction-is-the-next-frontier-for-web3/">Why Chain Abstraction Is the Next Frontier for Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Most of today’s dapps are not actually dapps, i.e. <em>decentralized applications. </em>If you need to leave the app in order to start using it, it’s not really an app––it’s just a frontend. If users have to manually onboard themselves through exchanges and manage multiple accounts and gas fees and bridges, did you even build an app? I think not––which may explain why only a few million people in the world are using dapps.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If we want to see mainstream adoption of Web3 because we believe a more open, decentralized internet that supports self-sovereignty for all people is <a href="/blog/self-sovereignty-is-near-a-vision-for-our-ecosystem">better for the world</a>, then we will need to do better.</p>



<p>The prevailing narrative in Web3 today is modularity, or separating out the different functional layers of a blockchain, i.e. settlement, data availability, and execution, for the sake of scalability. Layer-twos, optimistic and ZK rollups, data availability layers, sidechains, and state channels are all examples of modularity solutions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This proliferation of blockchains &amp; rollups has led to a degraded experience for users and developers. Modularity and a world of many chains leads to more fragmentation of liquidity, apps, and users––a significant degree of complexity in the user experience that no mainstream user could ever be expected to navigate. This also applies to developers, who feel pressure to commit to a specific tech stack while limiting the audience for their application. Now when you build a dapp, you’re enshrining yourself into a small addressable market by choosing a single chain.</p>



<p>I want to propose a better vision for the entire Ethereum ecosystem and all of Web3: let’s work together on advancing mainstream adoption via chain abstraction. The idea is that blockchains must be abstracted away from the user so they are not barriers to entry or participation. NEAR has been focusing on this vision since 2018 and today has achieved the most users of any network in Web3: 12.4 million monthly active accounts and 34 million accounts overall.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here’s how we can defragment Web3 and onboard billions of users via dapps.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>What does this look like for the user?&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Let’s imagine how using a dapp should actually work: transacting across networks and navigating between experiences with ease, all within a single interface. As one example, Alice picks up her phone and opens <a href="https://kaikai.ai/">KAIKAI</a> from her lockscreen. She orders a smoothie from a local place and sees in the app that there’s a discount offer from her favorite clothing store, Maison, and orders a pair of shoes for the spring. Alice sees she has earned enough KAICHING rewards to get a badge from Maison, not knowing it’s an NFT on Polygon, and redeems it in her account.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When she browses Maison on the KAIKAI app later that day, she notices that her new badge reveals an offer to buy tickets for an exclusive event at their store with a DJ she likes. She buys the ticket with KAICHING and receives 2 tickets, still not knowing it’s an NFT on Arbitrum. Since she gets a +1, Alice invites her friend Bob to come with her and pings him for his address.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bob sends his NEAR address to Alice and opens his app to check out the ticket. He sends Alice some ETH to say thanks for the invite and looks at the different cryptos he has in his account. Since he’s on the metro and has some time, he decides to buy some BTC and borrow against it with USDC so he can mint a Fighting Dragon NFT on Magic Eden. His friend Charles texted him earlier to get one so they could play each other in Year of the Dragon, a new game on NEAR where their dragons can battle each other for coins they can stake.</p>



<p>All of these interactions and transactions can take place in a single interface and in a completely private way. There are no wallets, no switching networks, and no transaction fees to deal with; those are embedded directly in the swap or the buy and handled on behalf of the user. Alice didn’t need to worry about which network the ticket is on and Bob can send her funds for the ticket in whichever crypto he wants, moving seamlessly into buying a different one the next second. All inside of an app. This is the level of seamlessness we should be striving for as an ecosystem.</p>



<p><strong>How do we achieve Chain Abstraction?</strong></p>



<p>Everyone building an app in Web3 will benefit from being able to access such a broad market of potential users as in this example––i.e. anyone who uses apps. Whereas today, developers choose a network based on access to liquidity or the users of a specific rollup or chain, in a chain abstraction future they can just build with the best tech. The users will show up for the best experiences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Imagine if a Gmail user couldn’t just send a message to an Outlook address––it doesn’t make sense. The same is true for Web3 addresses. The core assumption of chain abstraction is: end users don’t care about the underlying blockchain. They just want apps to work. In reality, blockchains are simply infrastructure to receive value out of Web3: security of assets from seizure, economic opportunity, removing middlemen for transactions, global permissionless identity, data provenance, entertaining experiences, and more.</p>



<p>The core goal of chain abstraction is to defragment the increasingly fractured modular landscape of Web3. While this will be most visible at the user experience layer, this defragmentation of liquidity and accounts is possible thanks to innovation at the security layer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Zero knowledge (ZK) introduces a principally new approach to ledger security. Whereas before one needed to trust a decentralized set of validators, now even a single computer can prove that rules were followed with a simple proof. This means that where before, developers would be forced to either build on a shared chain or spend immense resources to launch a new one, now they can just spin one up on their single server.</p>



<p>This new paradigm introduces the idea of cross settlement: as more chains become fully ZK provable, if some proof is published on other chains, there is no way to revert this chain without also needing to revert other chains. Transactions from one chain can also settle on multiple others via ZK proofs. This provides mesh security as all proofs continuously get aggregated, allowing the safe movement of assets between such chains.</p>



<p>In order to achieve unified security, two things are needed at the bottom of the stack: Data availability, which provides a way for everyone to sync even if the operator is offline, and a decentralized sequencer for applications that don’t have a central operator.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The next layer is identity with that security unified. Users can have an address on all possible chains and move assets between them freely. From a user perspective, this should be a single account where they interact with apps on different chains, and assets either get bridged or swapped automatically.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I call this “account aggregation” and will share more details about it in another post soon. NEAR will launch the next version of FastAuth in March 2024, which has mapping for NEAR addresses to EVM, Bitcoin, and other addresses. NEAR accounts can request to sign a transaction for another chain. This allows them to build multichain apps directly as smart contracts on NEAR.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The final layer is unifying the experience layer, or the application layer (e.g. <a href="https://alpha.dapdap.net/">DapDap</a>)––providing a way to interact with apps on various chains without users switching or needing to leave a single interface. A decentralized frontend can provide easy components to build in a chain-abstracted way. NEAR can achieve this through NearJS, combining data indexing and decentralized frontends––V2 also coming in March 2024. </p>



<p><strong>How is NEAR enabling Chain Abstraction?&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>The NEAR ecosystem has been building towards the chain abstraction vision since its beginnings in 2018, focusing on usability, a flexible account model, and a highly scalable blockchain that could support mainstream apps with billions of users. Today, the stack has expanded to support full chain abstraction across chains and all kinds of apps.&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Scalable, integrated blockchain that can grow to 1B+ daily active accounts.</li>



<li>Security aggregation stack consisting of <a href="https://near.org/data-availability">NEAR DA</a>, <a href="https://blockworks.co/news/polygon-developers-zk-proofs">zkWASM</a> (collaboration with Polygon Labs), and <a href="https://near.org/blog/near-foundation-and-eigen-labs-partner-to-enable-faster-cheaper-web3-transactions-for-ethereum-rollups-via-eigenlayer/">EigenLayer-powered Fast Finality</a>.</li>



<li>Account aggregation on top of this to enable transacting on all chains using a single account</li>



<li>Data layer that supports everything from monolithic, integrated, modular, private and permissioned chains to query data in a <a href="https://docs.near.org/bos/queryapi/intro">predictable protocol</a>.</li>



<li>Intent relayers that can execute complex intents across chains using this infra.</li>



<li><a href="https://docs.near.org/bos/overview">Decentralized frontends</a> that provide discoverability and composability for multiple apps across chains into one experience.</li>



<li>Super (app) wallets that are user friendly and offer a way to navigate all of Web3 without having to switch networks or deal with gas tokens and bridges.</li>
</ul>



<p>Importantly, each of these layers supports builders from across Web3, including Ethereum, rollups &amp; L2s, and beyond––the multichain future is becoming the chain abstraction future.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Call to Action</strong></p>



<p>2024 is the year of hiding the complexity of multichain infrastructure to deliver the Web3 experiences we’re striving for. Improving usability and discoverability should be a priority for all Web3 builders, as well as solving for liquidity fragmentation and security tradeoffs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s make chain abstraction a movement. The NEAR ecosystem invites builders from across Web3 to take advantage of the solutions we’re offering and to collaborate with us to build more chain abstraction solutions together. Stay tuned for more news on collaborations as well as details on an exciting event that NEAR Foundation will co-host at ETHDenver 2024.<br><br><em>Special thanks to Zaki Manian for conversations that led to this post as well as for his review.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/why-chain-abstraction-is-the-next-frontier-for-web3/">Why Chain Abstraction Is the Next Frontier for Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21182</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Case Study: Indexer&#8217;s Mary Korch on Building a Multichain Indexing Platform</title>
		<link>/blog/case-study-indexers-mary-korch-on-building-a-multichain-indexing-platform/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2023 17:15:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[NEAR Foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indexer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Multichain]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=20804</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR is a home to a number of amazing apps and projects. These developers, founders, and entrepreneurs are using NEAR …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/case-study-indexers-mary-korch-on-building-a-multichain-indexing-platform/">Case Study: Indexer&#8217;s Mary Korch on Building a Multichain Indexing Platform</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>NEAR is a home to a number of amazing apps and projects. These developers, founders, and entrepreneurs are using NEAR to effortlessly create and distribute innovative decentralized apps, while helping build a more open web — free from centralized platforms. In these Case Study videos, NEAR Foundation showcases some of these projects.&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>In the latest NEAR Foundation Case Study video below, Mary Korch, Customer Success at <a href="https://indexer.xyz/">Indexer</a>, talks about how the project built its Multichain Indexing Platform on NEAR. As Korch notes in the case study, Indexer builds infrastructure to support developers, giving them the data they need to be successful on the NEAR Protocol.</p>



<p>“If you’re a Web2 company looking to build in Web3, and specifically in NEAR, we have done a lot of the hard work for you,” says Korch.&nbsp; “You’re going to need data from the blockchain but also some off-chain data like metadata and IPFS. We actually have that all at your disposal, and it makes it a lot easier to build your application and get to market a lot quicker.”&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Case Study: Indexer&#039;s Mary Korch on Building a Multichain Indexing Platform" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MDGVG0SuiLU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/case-study-indexers-mary-korch-on-building-a-multichain-indexing-platform/">Case Study: Indexer&#8217;s Mary Korch on Building a Multichain Indexing Platform</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">20804</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
