<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Chain Signatures Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tag/chain-signatures/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/tag/chain-signatures/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 13:18:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Chain Signatures Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/tag/chain-signatures/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">234542837</site>	<item>
		<title>Chain Signatures Mainnet Launches: Smart Contracts Can Sign Transactions on Any Blockchain</title>
		<link>/blog/chain-signatures-mainnet-launches/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 13:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chain Abstraction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chain Signatures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Multichain]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21478</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Today marks the official Mainnet release of Chain Signatures, a groundbreaking Chain Abstraction solution built on NEAR. With the testnet phase and security audit now complete, developers can fully leverage Chain Signatures’ unique omnichain capabilities for their dApps on Mainnet. Degens and end users can now enjoy a fully chain abstracted user experience (UX) on the first cohort of Chain Signatures products already live on mainnet.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/chain-signatures-mainnet-launches/">Chain Signatures Mainnet Launches: Smart Contracts Can Sign Transactions on Any Blockchain</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Today marks the official Mainnet release of Chain Signatures, a groundbreaking Chain Abstraction solution built on NEAR. With the testnet phase and security audit now complete, developers can fully leverage Chain Signatures’ unique omnichain capabilities for their dApps on Mainnet. Degens and end users can now enjoy a fully chain abstracted user experience (UX) on the first cohort of Chain Signatures products already live on mainnet.</p>



<p>Chain Signatures utilizes a decentralized multi-party computation (MPC) network enabling NEAR accounts to sign transactions on any blockchain protocol. Chain Signatures are the only MPC solution where smart contracts can sign transactions on any chain and for any number of accounts. This is because accounts are smart contracts by default in the unique NEAR account model.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Chain Signatures reduce the work of multichain dApp development to a single layer: a smart contract on NEAR that can talk to all other chains. In this way, Chain Signatures abstract away the complexity and hassle of multichain dApps, for developers and users alike, and open up an entirely new design space of applications and user interfaces for Web3. Additionally, while existing bridges or cross-chain messaging protocols cannot support all chains or scale at speed, Chain Signatures can support every blockchain without native integration, whether Ethereum, Bitcoin, the Cosmos ecosystem, or (soon) Solana.</p>



<p>Five applications with more than 6 million active users between them are already using Chain Signatures Mainnet as of launch, with more than fifteen projects actively building. Soon there will be a full ecosystem of Chain Signatures products across this new design space, ranging across wallets, DEXs, lending, trading bots, bridges, and more.&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><a href="https://sweateconomy.com/">Sweat Wallet</a>: 2.5 million active Sweat Wallet users (on NEAR) can bridge assets to and from any chain, starting with BNB and Base, while paying for gas in $SWEAT.</li>



<li><a href="https://allstake.org/">Allstake</a>: Allstake is now live at Phase 0 with mainnet launch on NEAR, Solana, and Ethereum, supporting top LST and LRT protocols such as LiNEAR Protocol, MetaPool, Marinade, Jito, Renzo, and EtherFi.</li>



<li><a href="https://www.herewallet.app/">HERE Wallet</a>: Mobile, Web, and Telegram wallet supporting transactions on any chain. Check out this Hot Protocol (by Here Wallet) <a href="https://youtu.be/8fkgr7avNZA">demo</a>.</li>



<li><a href="https://wallet.bitte.ai/">Bitte Wallet</a>: Passkey wallets for any chain, including Bitcoin. Connect to all Ethereum apps with Bitte Wallet using WalletConnect. Watch a demo of how Bitte Wallet is using Chain Signatures <a href="https://youtu.be/0IoMCmvcjNY?si=0NJtvYGem_1iEyiL">here</a>.</li>



<li><a href="http://defuse.org/">Defuse</a>: Truly multichain spot DEX. Trade between any assets on any chain in seconds. See how NEAR Chain Signatures are transforming DeFi in this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xERiqWPD6Gk&amp;feature=youtu.be">demo</a>.</li>
</ul>



<p>Kendall Cole of <a href="http://proximity.dev/">Proximity Labs</a> – a contributor to Chain Signatures – said, &#8220;Chain Signatures is pivotal to replacing the fragmented Web3 landscape with a single user and developer layer that addresses current interoperability challenges. This innovation simplifies the user experience, enables DeFi for blockchains like Bitcoin that do not traditionally support smart contracts, and empowers developers to support all chains seamlessly. By eliminating the need for bridges, Chain Signatures can significantly expand the liquidity and utility of assets across various blockchains. We&#8217;re excited to see Chain Abstraction in the wild, transforming how users and developers interact with decentralized finance and making it more accessible.&#8221;</p>



<p>Another key layer of the Chain Signatures stack is the Multichain Gas Relayer. Instead of forcing users to acquire a separate gas token every time they transact on a new chain, the Multichain Gas Relayer performs the gas payment on the destination chain, on the user’s behalf. The user only needs to pay the equivalent amount in an asset they already hold, whether that’s NEAR or other NEAR-native fungible tokens (such as USDC or USDT). The power of Chain Signatures, together with the gas abstraction of the Multichain Gas Relayer, offers a streamlined user experience as exemplified by top dApps like Sweat Wallet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Illia Polosukhin, Co-Founder of Near Protocol and CEO of NEAR Foundation, added, &#8220;Chain Signatures is a game-changing innovation that brings Chain Abstraction to life. Whereas before we had fragmented liquidity in DeFi, now there will be a single DeFi layer for all chains. There is no more need for dozens of wallets and addresses, manual bridging, and paying gas fees in every token. Instead, all of DeFi is accessible from wherever users already are. It’s all possible because smart contracts can now sign transactions for any blockchain, even Bitcoin. This opens up a whole new design space for financial apps in Web3, benefitting degens and also paving the way for new user bases.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>As of mainnet launch, Chain Signatures’ MPC network is secured by eight reputable validators: <a href="https://www.pagoda.co/">Pagoda</a>, <a href="https://www.luganodes.com/">Luganodes</a>, <a href="https://liftedinit.org/">The Lifted Initiative</a>, <a href="https://infstones.com/">InfStones</a>, <a href="https://www.staking4all.org/">Staking4All</a>, <a href="https://node.monster/">Node.Monster,</a> <a href="https://blacksand.xyz/">Black Sand Technologies</a>, and <a href="https://aurora.dev/">Aurora</a>. The initial audit for the Chain Signatures protocol has been conducted by <a href="https://kudelskisecurity.com/">Kudelski</a>, the final report of which will be published soon on the Chain Signatures GitHub.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Chain Signatures development roadmap includes adding EDDSA support before the end of the year, increasing throughput, and increasing the number of nodes. As of mainnet launch, Chain Signatures supports all blockchain protocols based on the ECDSA elliptic curve, which includes most chains such as Ethereum, Bitcoin, Dogecoin, and recently, NEAR. With the additional support for the EDDSA elliptic curve (e.g. Solana, TON), Chain Signatures will be able to sign transactions on every known blockchain by Q4 2024. By the end of the year, Chain Signatures will aim to increase throughput up to 300 transactions/second to match NEAR’s sharded capacity. Finally, the number of validators on the network will gradually increase over time with the aim of achieving 40+ highly independent nodes, which would require 27 for a single signature.</p>



<p>For all app builders in Web3 who want to build multichain experiences from day one, explore these resources and start building:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Chain Signatures: <a href="/blog/getting-started-with-chain-signatures/">Getting Started Guide</a></li>



<li>Multichain Gas Relayer: <a href="https://docs.near.org/build/chain-abstraction/multichain-gas-relayer/getting-started">Getting Started Guide</a></li>



<li><a href="https://form.jotform.com/240777569453167">Request support</a> for building with Chain Signatures</li>



<li>Join the Chain Abstraction Dev Group on <a href="https://t.me/+RXYjlPob_XM5N2Ex">Telegram</a></li>
</ul>



<p>All the above resources and more can be found on the Chain Signatures landing page: <a href="https://near.org/chain-abstraction">https://near.org/chain-abstraction</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/chain-signatures-mainnet-launches/">Chain Signatures Mainnet Launches: Smart Contracts Can Sign Transactions on Any Blockchain</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21478</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting Started with Chain Signatures</title>
		<link>/blog/getting-started-with-chain-signatures/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 22:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chain Abstraction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chain Signatures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Multichain]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21468</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What is Chain Signatures? Chain Signatures is a groundbreaking technology built on NEAR that enables NEAR accounts, including smart contracts, …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/getting-started-with-chain-signatures/">Getting Started with Chain Signatures</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is Chain Signatures?</h2>



<p>Chain Signatures is a groundbreaking technology built on NEAR that enables NEAR accounts, including smart contracts, to sign and execute transactions across multiple blockchains. This innovation leverages Multi-Party Computation (MPC) and a distributed network of node operators to create joint signatures from arbitrary payloads, allowing NEAR users to control external blockchain accounts. This technology enhances blockchain interoperability, giving ownership of diverse assets, cross-chain accounts, and data to a single NEAR account.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Does It Work?</h2>



<p>Chain Signatures operates through a series of steps to enable seamless cross-chain transactions:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Deriving Foreign Addresses:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Chain Signatures uses derivation paths to represent accounts on foreign blockchains.</li>



<li>The NEAR account’s name and the derivation path are used to mathematically <a href="https://docs.near.org/concepts/abstraction/chain-signatures#derivation-paths-one-account-multiple-chains">derive a unique address</a> for the user on the foreign blockchain.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Creating the Transaction:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>The client constructs the hash of the transaction to be signed, which varies by the target blockchain.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Requesting the Signature:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>A NEAR account or smart contract calls the sign method of the MPC smart contract (<a href="https://nearblocks.io/address/v1.signer">v1.signer</a>) to sign a payload.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Relaying the Signature:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>The client reconstructs the valid transaction using the signature and broadcasts it to the destination blockchain.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>



<p>This process eliminates the need for traditional bridges and enables developers to build innovative cross-chain DeFi applications with seamless user experiences.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Use Cases</h2>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>DeFi on Bitcoin (and other chain without smart contracts)</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Chain signatures allow NEAR smart contract to program assets on Bitcoin.</li>



<li>Build lending, swaps, runes launchpads, passkey-based Bitcoin wallets, and more.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Chain agnostic applications</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Since chain signatures can sign transactions for all blockchains, developers can support every single chain with just one smart contract.</li>



<li>Multichain DEXs, lending protocols, oracles, derivatives, and more.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Multichain account abstraction </strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Users can control assets on all chains with just their NEAR account, and can utilize account abstraction features on any chain including passkeys, key rotation, etc.</li>



<li>Using the multichain gas relayer, users can pay for gas fees on any chain using USDC.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Privacy</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Chain signatures can be used to encrypt and decrypt information in a programmatic way.</li>



<li>This enables privacy applications, and even decrypting information based on ownership of assets/NFTs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How to Get Started?</h2>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Familiarize Yourself with Chain Signatures:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Understand the <a href="https://docs.near.org/concepts/abstraction/chain-signatures">basics of Chain Signatures</a> and how they simplify blockchain interactions.</li>



<li>Review the technical <a href="https://near.org/blog/unlocking-web3-usability-with-account-aggregation">explainer</a>.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Explore the Use Cases:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Review <a href="/blog/unlocking-multichain-web3-with-near-chain-signatures/">examples of use cases for Chain Signatures</a>, such as Multichain DAO, Multichain NFT Minter, and Bitcoin Runes Airdrop.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Access Resources and Documentation:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Visit the <a href="https://docs.near.org/build/chain-abstraction/chain-signatures">Chain Signatures documentation</a> for detailed technical information and code snippets.</li>



<li>Check out the <a href="https://linktr.ee/chainsignatures">Linktree for Chain Signatures</a> for various resources, including demos and tutorials.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Try the Demos:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Use the <a href="https://github.com/near-examples/chainsig-script">command-line-based demo</a> to derive accounts and send transactions on Bitcoin, Ethereum, Doge, and Ripple.</li>



<li>Check out the <a href="https://github.com/near-examples/near-multichain/tree/main">web app demo</a>.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Engage with the Community:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Join the <a href="https://t.me/chain_abstraction">Chain Abstraction developers’ channel on Telegram</a> to connect with other developers and get support.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Where to Learn More?</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Technical Blogs and Deep Dives:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Read <a href="/blog/unlocking-multichain-web3-with-near-chain-signatures">high-level use cases</a> and technical <a href="https://near.org/blog/unlocking-web3-usability-with-account-aggregation">explainer</a> posts on the NEAR blog.</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li><strong>Community and Support:</strong>
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Engage with the NEAR community on <a href="http://x.com/nearprotocol">X</a> and participate in <a href="https://t.me/chain_abstraction">discussions</a> to stay updated on the latest developments.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/getting-started-with-chain-signatures/">Getting Started with Chain Signatures</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21468</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chain Signatures Launch to Enable Transactions on Any Blockchain from a NEAR Account</title>
		<link>/blog/chain-signatures-launch-to-enable-transactions-on-any-blockchain-from-a-near-account/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mally Anderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 02:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chain Signatures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Today at BUIDL Asia in Seoul, Korea, NEAR Co-Founder and NEAR Foundation CEO Illia Polosukhin announced the launch of Chain …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/chain-signatures-launch-to-enable-transactions-on-any-blockchain-from-a-near-account/">Chain Signatures Launch to Enable Transactions on Any Blockchain from a NEAR Account</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Today at BUIDL Asia in Seoul, Korea, NEAR Co-Founder and NEAR Foundation CEO Illia Polosukhin announced the launch of Chain Signatures on NEAR. Chain Signatures enable NEAR accounts, including smart contracts, to sign transactions for any blockchain. This is powered by a decentralized MPC network which uses NEAR staking and Eigenlayer ETH restakers for security. Chain Signatures currently supports Bitcoin, Ethereum, Cosmos chains, DogeCoin, and XRP Ledger and will soon support Solana, TON Network, Polkadot, and others. </p>



<p><strong>How Chain Signatures Work</strong></p>



<p>Chain signatures introduce threshold signatures for any blockchain, controlled by NEAR accounts &amp; smart contracts. A NEAR account, which can also be a smart contract thanks to the NEAR account model, can request that the NEAR validators or MPC nodes sign an arbitrary payload, which could be a transaction for some other blockchain, and get a signed payload back to then send to the destination chain. </p>



<p>This is made possible by building an account-based decentralized Multi-Party Computation (MPC) network, allowing NEAR accounts to control multiple addresses on various chains and ensuring that the users are the only ones who can request signatures for transactions. Chain Signatures uses an account-based pattern, as opposed to a deposit-based or bridge-based pattern, as most other MPC networks currently in production do. The Chain Signatures MPC network functions as a decentralized signer for NEAR accounts and smart contracts, managing requests to addresses on different blockchains while placing zero burden on the user to manage these.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1600" height="928" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image.png" alt="" class="wp-image-21297" style="width:707px;height:auto" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image.png 1600w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-300x174.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-1024x594.png 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-768x445.png 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-1536x891.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure>



<p>The first of its kind, Chain Signatures is a major advancement in DeFi adoption by enhancing cross chain interoperability and unlocking a new variety of use cases for mainstream users and Web3 builders. Chain signatures makes it easier to build DeFi products for particular chains and assets (while utilizing assets from other chains e.g. USDC/T, SOL, etc). For example, users can use XRP as collateral to borrow USDC, or trade DOGE for SOL. The launch of Chain Signatures delivers an elevated user experience that simplifies the transaction process while increasing accessibility to liquidity on non-smart contract chains such as Bitcoin, DogeCoin, XRP Ledger, and more. This also means that Chain Signatures let app developers serve all ecosystems at once from one interface rather than having to commit to a single chain or pool of liquidity.</p>



<p>The Chain Signatures MPC network is launching with Eigenlayer as a key partner and will be secured by Eigenlayer ETH restakers and NEAR stakers. The initial operator set is a trust-minimized network of ten node providers, which includes some top Eigen AVS infrastructure providers, using a Proof of Authority security model at launch. The future state is a permissionless network of node operators based on staking requirements and slashing conditions, planned to roll out in the coming months.  </p>



<p><strong>Multichain Gas Relayer</strong></p>



<p>Launching alongside Chain Signatures is the Multichain Gas Relayer, which removes the need to have the native gas token of another chain in order to transact. This is a big hurdle for users today, often requiring purchasing multiple tokens on exchanges and sending them to different accounts just to complete a single cross-chain action. Now, with the Multichain Gas Relayer, users can just use NEAR or NEP-141 tokens to cover gas on any chain, not just NEAR or EVM chains. </p>



<p>This unlocks true multichain account abstraction. Whereas cross-chain bridges vary significantly depending on which assets are bridging to which chains, chain signatures makes transacting on smart contract and non-smart contract chains possible from a single account or interface, while simultaneously unlocking liquidity that wouldn’t have been accessible before. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="1318" height="846" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-21298" style="width:623px;height:auto" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-1.png 1318w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-1-300x193.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-1-1024x657.png 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-1-768x493.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1318px) 100vw, 1318px" /></figure>



<p>For a longer technical deep dive on Chain Signatures and the Multichain Gas Relayer, see this <a href="/blog/unlocking-web3-usability-with-account-aggregation/">post from February 2024</a> about NEAR account aggregation technologies.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>New Web3 Design Patterns with Chain Signatures</strong></p>



<p>Chain Signatures unlocks a range of powerful new use cases for application builders and DeFi developers while also enabling much simpler user interfaces across different contexts. Smart contracts on NEAR will be able to custody assets on any chain (since they can sign transactions on any chain via chain signatures), and maintain user balances similar to how single chain lending protocols or DEXs do now. For example, a user will be able to atomically swap their BTC in a Bitcoin account for another user’s ETH in an Ethereum account. This works because they can first deposit into accounts on these respective chains that are fully controlled by a NEAR smart contract, which will then settle the trade and allow the user’s to withdraw their “new” assets post-trade.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>DeFi on non-smart contract chains: </strong>NEAR smart contracts can sign transactions for non-smart contract chains like Bitcoin, Celestia, Bittensor, XRP Ledger, and others. This enables DEXs, lending protocols, and other DeFi apps to be built using the native assets of these chains, unlocking previously inaccessible liquidity.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Bridgeless cross-chain DeFi: </strong>Since NEAR smart contracts can custody assets on any chain, users can build truly cross chain applications such as RFQs, orderbooks, AMMs, lending protocols, and more. It is also possible to build swaps and other apps without bridges and message passing layers, meaning that new chains and assets can be added at launch. Additionally, chain signatures can be used to build two-way bridges to non-smart contract chains, using NEAR as the intermediate chain.<br></li>



<li><strong>Multichain Account Abstraction: </strong>A single NEAR account can manage any number of accounts on any number of chains. This means users can get ERC 4337-like functionality (natively supported by NEAR) without deploying any new smart contracts (so they can use non-EVM and non-smart contract chains), or needing to update their accounts on each individual chain. Chain Signatures also enables users to pay for gas costs on various chains with USDC, including non-EVM chains.<br></li>



<li><strong>Instantly multichain apps at launch:</strong> Thanks to Chain Signatures and the Multichain Gas Relayer, app developers don’t need to commit to a single chain when they start building––now, they can make many chains accessible to their users immediately after launching and dramatically increase their addressable market of users.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Advancing the Chain Abstraction Vision</strong></p>



<p>Chain Signatures advances the NEAR ecosystem’s <a href="https://near.org/blog/why-chain-abstraction-is-the-next-frontier-for-web3">vision of Chain Abstraction</a>, or the idea that Web3 hurdles should be abstracted away from user interfaces for the sake of simplicity and accessibility. Many of these hurdles arise with multichain use cases as users need to deal with long lists of accounts on different chains, manually move assets between them, and manage all the related security. Now, with Chain Signatures, users can simply create and secure one account and then start transacting on any network in Web3. Chain Signatures also help dapp developers deliver better multichain experiences to their users and get access to all available liquidity across blockchains.</p>



<p>As Illia noted, &#8220;Since day one, the NEAR ecosystem has focused on simplifying access to Web3 for developers and mainstream users. Chain Signatures is the next step in that journey, making it significantly easier to transact on any blockchain while also defragmenting liquidity across the ecosystem. This will enable the next generation of truly decentralized apps to deliver much more powerful experiences and address the entire market of Web3 users.&#8221;   </p>



<p><strong>Live Use Cases In the Ecosystem</strong></p>



<p>Several projects in the NEAR ecosystem are already building with Chain Signatures to introduce new design patterns and experiences to users. More information on the node provider ecosystem as well as news about additional projects building with Chain Signatures across Web3 is coming in the next few weeks.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>SWEAT Economy, a <a href="https://dappradar.com/rankings">top ten</a> most used decentralized app (dApp), utilizes Multichain Gas Relayer to let users send transactions from NEAR to BNB chain and pay for the gas in SWEAT tokens earned in-app.</li>



<li>East Blue, a Bitcoin Layer 2, <a href="https://youtu.be/YpcCRglr6vc">uses NEAR Chain Signatures</a> to develop Bitcoin DeFi use cases that were not possible until now, providing a new way to extend Bitcoin with smart contract logic.&nbsp;</li>



<li><a href="https://linearprotocol.org/">LiNEAR</a> is building a multichain, multi-asset restaking framework on top of Eigenlayer, enabling non-ETH assets including NEAR to be restaked and used for securing applications.</li>



<li>Mintbase, an NFT infrastructure platform, enables NEAR-based Mintbase wallet holders to purchase <a href="https://x.com/mintbase/status/1769748329619992792?s=20">Ethereum NFTs directly</a>.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Start Building with Chain Signatures</strong></p>



<p>Chain Signatures makes possible a range of new use cases for Web3 developers and users alike, opening up an exciting new design space and expanding the landscape of multichain apps and experiences utilizing Chain Abstraction. </p>



<p>Builders and developers interested in getting started with Chain Signatures can visit the <a href="https://bit.ly/what-are-chain-signatures">documentation</a> or <a href="https://bit.ly/create-a-chain-signature">explore code examples</a> and begin building today. Projects looking for support implementing Chain Signatures can register their interest <a href="https://form.jotform.com/240777569453167">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/chain-signatures-launch-to-enable-transactions-on-any-blockchain-from-a-near-account/">Chain Signatures Launch to Enable Transactions on Any Blockchain from a NEAR Account</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21295</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
