<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Developers Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/category/developers/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/category/developers/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 13:47:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.5.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/cropped-favicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Developers Archives &#8211; NEAR Protocol</title>
	<link>/blog/category/developers/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">234542837</site>	<item>
		<title>Introducing *NEAR Name Tokens &#8211; Multichain, Cross-Platform Digital Identities In Web3</title>
		<link>/blog/introducing-near-name-tokens/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 13:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Following the recently announced partnership between NEAR Foundation and&#160;D3, we’re excited to introduce *NEAR Name Tokens; a multichain, cross-platform digital …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/introducing-near-name-tokens/">Introducing *NEAR Name Tokens &#8211; Multichain, Cross-Platform Digital Identities In Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Following the recently announced <a href="/blog/near-protocol-partners-with-d3-to-apply-for-near-top-level-domain/">partnership between NEAR Foundation and&nbsp;D3</a>, we’re excited to introduce *NEAR Name Tokens; a multichain, cross-platform digital identity for web3 and beyond.</p>



<p>NEAR Foundation is working with D3 to bridge the gap between traditional internet infrastructure and web3. *NEAR Name Tokens are an important step in developing the <a href="https://d3.inc/blog/educational/futureproof-your-digital-identity-how-d3-aims-to-revolutionize-your-online-persona/">futureproof, interoperable digital identities</a> that will be key to driving implementation of chain abstraction, and of developing web3 more broadly.</p>



<p><strong>Complementing the NEAR Ecosystem with *NEAR Name Tokens</strong></p>



<p>NEAR already offers a deeply integrated identity solution with named NEAR accounts. These NEAR accounts, however, are limited to use across the NEAR ecosystem.</p>



<p>*NEAR Name Tokens will offer users a comprehensive digital identity solution across the wider web3 ecosystem, while keeping NEAR front and center.</p>



<p>Users will be able to use these name tokens in a variety of ways, including:</p>



<ul>
<li>As a simplified wallet address across hundreds of different blockchain networks</li>



<li>As an infrastructure identifier across hundreds of different blockchain networks</li>



<li>As a cross-platform username across various different decentralized platforms, including DeFi, GameFi, SocialFi, SportFi and other related applications</li>



<li>As Verifiable Credentials (VCs) to platforms and services that you interact with</li>



<li>To gain access to unique benefits and rewards programs for participating in the D3 ecosystem</li>



<li>As expressions of interest for the eventual .NEAR equivalent domain on the internet</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Why *NEAR Instead of .NEAR</strong></p>



<p>*NEAR Name Tokens feature a star, or asterisk (*), between the name and extension—such as <em>you*near</em>—instead of a period (.). In part, this is because NEAR accounts already use a .NEAR extension, and we want to avoid confusion for users.</p>



<p>More importantly, however, we use *NEAR because Name Tokens are unique web3 identifiers, not real domains, and we want to avoid any confusion between these as well. For years, several naming systems across web3 have thrown around the word “domain” quite liberally, without offering any of the actual utility offered by real domains.</p>



<p>Real domains are fully integrated with the Domain Name System, the distributed service that allows users to access websites and email infrastructure with ease. Billions of internet-capable devices—such as computers, tablets, mobile phones, Internet of Things devices, and more—support the DNS and real domains without the need for specialized software or plugins.</p>



<p>Integrating web3 with DNS will be critical in bringing interoperable digital identities to web3. To that end, NEAR Foundation has partnered with D3 to apply for and obtain the .near top-level domain—like the “.org” in <em>near.org</em>—during the upcoming application period for new TLDs, the first in over a decade.</p>



<p><strong>Exclusive Early Access Period to *NEAR Name Tokens for NEAR Account Holders</strong></p>



<p>As part of our initial launch phase later this summer,, existing NEAR account holders will receive exclusive early access to their equivalent *NEAR Name Tokens. For instance, if you already have the <em>name.near</em> NEAR account registered prior to launch, you will receive exclusive access to register <em>name*near</em> for a period of 90 days before names are released for public availability.</p>



<p>Similarly, should a NEAR account be available for any new *NEAR Name Token registrations, D3 will claim it on behalf of users to ensure a uniform experience across the NEAR ecosystem. Users can <a href="https://d3.app/near">sign up for early access</a>, and you’ll be  notified you prior to the official launch of *NEAR Name Tokens later this summer</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/introducing-near-name-tokens/">Introducing *NEAR Name Tokens &#8211; Multichain, Cross-Platform Digital Identities In Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21393</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unlocking Multichain Web3 with NEAR Chain Signatures</title>
		<link>/blog/unlocking-multichain-web3-with-near-chain-signatures/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 13:59:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21369</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Written by: Matt Lockyer &#38; Proximity Labs TL;DR: Multichain Apps Before vs After Chain Signatures NEAR Chain Signatures introduces a …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/unlocking-multichain-web3-with-near-chain-signatures/">Unlocking Multichain Web3 with NEAR Chain Signatures</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Written by: Matt Lockyer &amp; Proximity Labs</p>



<p></p>



<p>TL;DR:</p>



<ul>
<li>Demystifies NEAR’s new protocol feature, Chain Signatures, both for developers and end users.</li>



<li>Compares how multichain Web3 apps work, before and after Chain Signatures.</li>



<li>Presents two multichain app examples in which Chain Signatures improves DevX and UX: a DAO and NFT minter.</li>



<li>Describes how Chain Signatures can add a layer of smart contract functionality to non-smart contract chains through a Bitcoin Runes airdrop example.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Multichain Apps Before vs After Chain Signatures</h2>



<p>NEAR Chain Signatures introduces a new approach to building multichain Web3 applications that provides a better experience for developers and users. Before, developers would write application layer smart contracts for each chain, possibly in different languages, requiring new smart contracts and audits every time. The re-implementation and re-deployment of application logic introduce several risks for users while switching networks and feature disparity among implementations creates poor user experience (UX). Additionally, users are often required to bridge assets or messages from chain to chain, introducing even more risk and even worse UX.</p>



<p>Developing multichain Web3 applications before Chain Signatures:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1600" height="914" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-2.png" alt="" class="wp-image-21375" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-2.png 1600w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-2-300x171.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-2-1024x585.png 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-2-768x439.png 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-2-1536x877.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure>



<p>Without Chain Signatures</p>



<p><em>For developers and users, each additional chain adds application, account, and contract complexity. In this model, bridges are necessary to migrate assets and perform transactions on a new chain. This forces both developers and users through several preparatory steps before they can experience apps on their chain of choice.</em></p>



<p>Now, Chain Signatures alleviates the burden of maintaining different contracts, deployments, and audits for each chain, by allowing developers to move a majority of the application logic to a single NEAR smart contract. Developers can focus on the UX of their application, instead of maintaining several different contracts on multiple chains. Users also benefit from not bridging assets. Instead, they deposit assets from the chain they wish to use into a Chain Signatures account the application can use. Users interact with the application using a single NEAR account and maintain full custody of their assets, even though they reside on another chain. Chain Signatures enables any NEAR account or smart contract to control and sign for an infinite number of accounts on any chain that exists today and chains that are yet to be launched! This is a major breakthrough for multichain Web3 application development, security, and UX.</p>



<p>Developing multichain Web3 applications with Chain Signatures:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" width="1600" height="914" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-4.png" alt="" class="wp-image-21377" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-4.png 1600w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-4-300x171.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-4-1024x585.png 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-4-768x439.png 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-4-1536x877.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure>



<p>Using Chain Signatures</p>



<p><em>Application logic is executed in NEAR smart contracts that produce signatures for accounts on any chain, executing transactions and moving assets. Shifting application logic upstream into a single layer of NEAR contracts reduces the developer’s burden of maintaining complex bespoke application smart contracts on each chain. Assets are still deployed as contracts on their respective chains, typically using standards and smart contract templates that are already audited, but application logic no longer needs to be.</em></p>



<p>With Chain Signatures, application logic can be in one place, one language, and on one layer; and hence only requires one smart contract audit. This facilitates a better developer experience, and in turn, a better and more secure user experience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s take a look at some examples of new and exciting applications that can be designed using Chain Signatures to better understand how this tech works.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Examples of Apps Unlocked by Chain Signatures</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Multichain DAO</h3>



<p>In crypto, users often want to pool funds and have an on-chain process for accepting proposals from the community and distributing those funds transparently. A decentralized autonomous organization (DAO) is generally the chosen approach for communities in Web3 today. Since Ethereum is the most widely accepted chain for popular stablecoins such as USDC, it makes sense to pool DAO funds there. However, running all of the DAO application logic using Ethereum smart contracts and transactions quickly becomes slow and cost-prohibitive, leading to voter apathy and disengagement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Using Chain Signatures, one can develop a design that provides a more immediate and better user experience, while lowering fees significantly. In addition, there can be a single DAO application layer that accepts proposals and handles voting that distributes funds on multiple chains!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" width="1600" height="914" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-3.png" alt="" class="wp-image-21376" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-3.png 1600w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-3-300x171.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-3-1024x585.png 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-3-768x439.png 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-3-1536x877.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure>



<p>A Chain Signatures-powered DAO (high-level)</p>



<p><em>The DAO application logic is executed in a NEAR smart contract. Features such as membership, proposals, and voting are handled in the DAO contract. When a proposal is accepted, the DAO contract automatically calls the NEAR Chain Signatures contract to generate a signature for the derived address and account. This account exists on the chain where the DAO members originally pooled their funds. In the case of Ethereum, or any EVM chain, this can simply be an externally owned account (EOA) and does not require an additional smart contract to be deployed.</em></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Multichain NFT Minter</h3>



<p>Let’s imagine there’s a new NFT collection where the total supply is capped at 10,000, with one difference from the typical model: the collection will be minted across multiple chains. Without Chain Signatures, there are a few different ways to go about this.</p>



<ol>
<li>You have the primary sales logic and NFT logic deployed to each chain. This forces you to predetermine the amounts you will allow on each chain.
<ol>
<li>This creates UX issues for users, who are forced to use a particular chain.</li>



<li>This also imposes limitations on how your collection is minted.</li>
</ol>
</li>



<li>You have the primary sales logic on one chain and allow users to mint NFTs through a message-passing bridge to the chain of their choice.
<ol>
<li>Introduces UX issues; multiple transactions and wallets for users.</li>



<li>Adds bridging risks to the application and for user error.</li>
</ol>
</li>



<li>Primary sales logic and NFT mints are done on one chain and the NFTs are bridged after the fact.
<ol>
<li>This introduces the above UX challenges and bridging risks.</li>



<li>Allowing bridging means less control over the supply of NFTs on any particular chain.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ol>



<p>The first approach is too rigid. The second and third require a minimum of 2 transactions from the user with all the complexity and security risks of bridging assets. Depending on your preference, you may or may not want users bridging your NFTs after the primary sale and initial mint. Let&#8217;s assume you don&#8217;t.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s also assume you want a seamless sale experience, where the user chooses the chain of mint, and the NFT is minted to an existing wallet on an arbitrary chain. Ideally, all of this should occur in a single transaction for the user. Note, the price of gas can be rolled into the primary sale via an oracle.</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s how this would work with Chain Signatures:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="914" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-21374" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-1.png 1600w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-1-300x171.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-1-1024x585.png 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-1-768x439.png 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-1-1536x877.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure>



<p>A Chain Signatures Multichain NFT Mint (high-level)</p>



<p><em>The NFT Sale contract takes payment. This can be in NEAR, USDC, or any other token on NEAR. The NFT Sale contract calls the Chain Signatures contract with a transaction&nbsp; payload that mints an NFT on the destination chain selected by the user, and with an account as owner supplied by the user. A signature for the mint is generated, passed back to the user client, and then broadcasted to the selected chain. The NFT is minted on the selected chain’s NFT contract and ownership is given to the user’s account specified in the sale transaction. In a single transaction, an NFT is bought and minted on another chain.</em></p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Bitcoin Runes Airdrop</h3>



<p><a href="https://cointelegraph.com/learn/bitcoin-runes">Bitcoin Runes</a> are a new fungible token protocol by Ordinals creator Casey Rodarmor. Improving on BRC-20, Runes aim to produce less clutter and improve the costs of issuing and trading fungible tokens on Bitcoin. One drawback to Bitcoin is restricted programmability, making something like a mass Runes airdrop difficult. With Chain Signatures, NEAR can function as a smart contract layer for Bitcoin through which a mass Bitcoin Runes airdrop could be executed.</p>



<p>One can use a NEAR contract to maintain an “allow list” for the airdrop, utilizing a BTC light client contract. Assuming all the Runes are premined and residing in the Chain Signatures address derived from the NEAR Airdrop smart contract, the first step for the user is to fund this BTC address with the necessary BTC transaction fees to transfer the Runes to themselves. Once this is done, they can submit this transaction hash and their BTC address to the NEAR Airdrop contract, which will call the Chain Signatures contract with a transaction payload that will transfer the Runes.</p>



<p>Here’s what this would look like:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="914" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image.png" alt="" class="wp-image-21373" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image.png 1600w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-300x171.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-1024x585.png 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-768x439.png 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-1536x877.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure>



<p>A Runes Airdrop using Chain Signatures (high-level)</p>



<p><em>The user funds the BTC address with the fees needed to transfer Runes to their account (1). They submit the transaction hash and their BTC address to the NEAR Airdrop contract (2). The NEAR Airdrop contract checks the user’s BTC address against the allow list. Then the contract calls the BTC Light Client to verify the fees have been paid (3). Finally, the NEAR Airdrop contract can generate a transaction to transfer the Runes to the user’s destination address. A cross-contract call is made to the Chain Signatures contract to sign the transaction. The signature is returned to the client and broadcasted to the Bitcoin network where the Runes are transferred (4).</em></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Summary</h2>



<p>NEAR Chain Signatures introduces a new way to design multichain Web3 applications for a range of use cases, such as DAOs, NFT minting, and airdrops. Chain Signatures brings rich smart contract functionality to non-smart contract chains like BTC and XRP. Building with Chain Signatures provides a better experience for developers and users. Developers have to write less smart contract code, submit fewer audits, and maintain fewer smart contract deployments across multiple chains. Users don’t have to bridge assets or perform several transactions in order to use the chains they feel most comfortable with. All in all, Chain Signatures is a massive step forward for multichain Web3 applications and towards mainstream adoption for new and existing crypto users.</p>



<p>NEAR Chain Signatures is live on testnet and will soon be available on mainnet. For further resources on Chain Signatures, see <a href="https://linktr.ee/chainsignatures">here</a>. To get support for building with Chain Signatures, for any of the examples above or another idea, reach us <a href="https://form.jotform.com/240777569453167">here</a>.</p>



<p></p>



<p><em>Disclosures: Proximity Labs holds $NEAR and other tokens or investments that may be associated with protocols or projects mentioned in this article.&nbsp; This article&#8217;s content does not constitute financial advice or a recommendation to buy, sell, or use any token or protocol. This article also contains forward-looking statements about third-party projects that the authors have no control over and, as such, actual future developments may be substantially different from the expectations described in the forward-looking statements for a number of reasons, including those that are not under the control of the authors. The content of this article reflects the opinions of its authors and is presented for informational purposes only. This is not and should not be construed to be investment advice.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/unlocking-multichain-web3-with-near-chain-signatures/">Unlocking Multichain Web3 with NEAR Chain Signatures</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21369</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Legends of NEAR: Expansion from 4 to 6 Shards</title>
		<link>/blog/legends-of-near-expansion-from-4-to-6-shards/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 16:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Core protocol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ecosystem]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21349</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>TLDR: NEAR is growing fast, leading to a need for more capacity, so it increased its shards from 4 to …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/legends-of-near-expansion-from-4-to-6-shards/">Legends of NEAR: Expansion from 4 to 6 Shards</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>TLDR: </strong>NEAR is growing fast, leading to a need for more capacity, so it increased its shards from 4 to 6 to handle more transactions smoothly. This upgrade boosts the network’s ability by 50% and was done without any disruption to the system, ensuring users continue to have a fast and stable experience.</p>



<p>Over the last six months, NEAR has experienced a significant increase in users and transactions. NEAR has 3 of the top ten <a href="https://dappradar.com/rankings">dapps</a> in Web3 by users with KAI-CHING and HOT Wallet both reaching millions of daily active users in April 2024.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-1024x683.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-21359" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-1024x683.jpeg 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-300x200.jpeg 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image-768x512.jpeg 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/image.jpeg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Chart from <a href="https://pikespeak.ai/near-world/overview">Pikespeak</a></p>



<ul>
<li>Total Transactions: 1.16B&nbsp;</li>



<li>Daily Unique Active Accounts: 1.3M</li>
</ul>



<p>NEAR has 3 of the top ten dapps in Web3 by users according to <a href="https://dappradar.com/rankings">dappradar</a> with KAI-CHING and HOT Wallet both reaching millions of daily active users in April 2024.</p>



<p>All of this demand led to some congestion on one of the shards, so Bowen Wang, Director of Protocol, and the Protocol team worked on further optimizations that rolled out within days to address it. Over the course of 2 weeks, they added 2 more shards to NEAR – for a total of 6 live shards. This increased the network’s capacity by 50%.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the end of Q2, stateless validation is expected to&nbsp; launch on Mainnet – this upgrade is projected to improve throughput for each shard by 5x and grow the total number of shards available for the network.</p>



<p>One of the most remarkable aspects of this upgrade is that it was implemented live—there was no need to take the blockchain offline. There was no break in user transactions.</p>



<p>What is sharding on a blockchain? Let&#8217;s simplify using an analogy.</p>



<p>Imagine you have a library that&#8217;s become too large and crowded. To manage this, you divide your books into several smaller sections and place them in different rooms. Each room now holds part of the entire collection, making finding and managing books easier. Most importantly, the separate collections will minimize congestion when the library is busy.</p>



<p>Now, think of the NEAR blockchain like that crowded library. Sharding is like dividing this big blockchain into smaller, manageable pieces called &#8220;shards.&#8221; Each shard is like one of those rooms, with only the contract interactions within that shard. When someone needs information, they go directly to the room (shard) where it&#8217;s stored instead of waiting for the whole chain. This way, sharding helps handle more data and serve more users efficiently without affecting users of the entire chain every time.</p>



<p>In NEAR&#8217;s case, the blockchain is split into multiple shards, akin to these rooms, where each shard processes transactions and maintains the state independently. This division allows for parallel processing, significantly boosting the network&#8217;s capacity and speed.</p>



<p>What sets NEAR apart is how these shards interact and synchronize. A developer doesn’t have to worry about which shard a specific contract might be on. This approach maintains high security and interconnectivity while allowing the network to scale effectively. As the network grows and demands increase, more shards can be added, like expanding the library with more rooms, to ensure that&nbsp; NEAR can adapt to increasing usage and more complex applications.</p>



<p>NEAR is focusing on future-proofing the protocol to handle even more growth and usage. This proactive approach aims to minimize disruptions and maintain a consistent developer and user experience, no matter how much the demand grows.</p>



<p>This further validates NEAR’s thesis that sharding is the best scaling approach given what is currently&nbsp; happening across the whole Web3 space. Many non-sharded chain/rollups are getting congested with transactions and have been forced to raise fees, while NEAR was able to expand capacity by adding more shards and keeping fees stable.</p>



<p>Homogeneous Sharding isn’t just a tech tweak; it’s a critical evolution in the blockchain that keeps transactions flowing. And it takes a team of superheroes for NEAR Protocol to be a top blockchain in Web3. The ultimate goal? To ensure that users never notice the complexity behind their seamless digital experience.</p>



<p>        <a href="https://shard.dog/legendsofnear-bowen">Claim your Proof of Legends of NEAR NFT</a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="724" height="1024" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/LoN-Bowen-Wang-Card-Final-724x1024.png" alt="" class="wp-image-21365" style="width:303px;height:auto" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/LoN-Bowen-Wang-Card-Final-724x1024.png 724w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/LoN-Bowen-Wang-Card-Final-212x300.png 212w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/LoN-Bowen-Wang-Card-Final-768x1086.png 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/LoN-Bowen-Wang-Card-Final-1086x1536.png 1086w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/LoN-Bowen-Wang-Card-Final-1448x2048.png 1448w" sizes="(max-width: 724px) 100vw, 724px" /></figure>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/legends-of-near-expansion-from-4-to-6-shards/">Legends of NEAR: Expansion from 4 to 6 Shards</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21349</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chain Signatures Launch to Enable Transactions on Any Blockchain from a NEAR Account</title>
		<link>/blog/chain-signatures-launch-to-enable-transactions-on-any-blockchain-from-a-near-account/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mally Anderson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 02:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chain Signatures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Today at BUIDL Asia in Seoul, Korea, NEAR Co-Founder and NEAR Foundation CEO Illia Polosukhin announced the launch of Chain …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/chain-signatures-launch-to-enable-transactions-on-any-blockchain-from-a-near-account/">Chain Signatures Launch to Enable Transactions on Any Blockchain from a NEAR Account</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Today at BUIDL Asia in Seoul, Korea, NEAR Co-Founder and NEAR Foundation CEO Illia Polosukhin announced the launch of Chain Signatures on NEAR. Chain Signatures enable NEAR accounts, including smart contracts, to sign transactions for any blockchain. This is powered by a decentralized MPC network which uses NEAR staking and Eigenlayer ETH restakers for security. Chain Signatures currently supports Bitcoin, Ethereum, Cosmos chains, DogeCoin, and XRP Ledger and will soon support Solana, TON Network, Polkadot, and others. </p>



<p><strong>How Chain Signatures Work</strong></p>



<p>Chain signatures introduce threshold signatures for any blockchain, controlled by NEAR accounts &amp; smart contracts. A NEAR account, which can also be a smart contract thanks to the NEAR account model, can request that the NEAR validators or MPC nodes sign an arbitrary payload, which could be a transaction for some other blockchain, and get a signed payload back to then send to the destination chain. </p>



<p>This is made possible by building an account-based decentralized Multi-Party Computation (MPC) network, allowing NEAR accounts to control multiple addresses on various chains and ensuring that the users are the only ones who can request signatures for transactions. Chain Signatures uses an account-based pattern, as opposed to a deposit-based or bridge-based pattern, as most other MPC networks currently in production do. The Chain Signatures MPC network functions as a decentralized signer for NEAR accounts and smart contracts, managing requests to addresses on different blockchains while placing zero burden on the user to manage these.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1600" height="928" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image.png" alt="" class="wp-image-21297" style="width:707px;height:auto" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image.png 1600w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-300x174.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-1024x594.png 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-768x445.png 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-1536x891.png 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure>



<p>The first of its kind, Chain Signatures is a major advancement in DeFi adoption by enhancing cross chain interoperability and unlocking a new variety of use cases for mainstream users and Web3 builders. Chain signatures makes it easier to build DeFi products for particular chains and assets (while utilizing assets from other chains e.g. USDC/T, SOL, etc). For example, users can use XRP as collateral to borrow USDC, or trade DOGE for SOL. The launch of Chain Signatures delivers an elevated user experience that simplifies the transaction process while increasing accessibility to liquidity on non-smart contract chains such as Bitcoin, DogeCoin, XRP Ledger, and more. This also means that Chain Signatures let app developers serve all ecosystems at once from one interface rather than having to commit to a single chain or pool of liquidity.</p>



<p>The Chain Signatures MPC network is launching with Eigenlayer as a key partner and will be secured by Eigenlayer ETH restakers and NEAR stakers. The initial operator set is a trust-minimized network of ten node providers, which includes some top Eigen AVS infrastructure providers, using a Proof of Authority security model at launch. The future state is a permissionless network of node operators based on staking requirements and slashing conditions, planned to roll out in the coming months.  </p>



<p><strong>Multichain Gas Relayer</strong></p>



<p>Launching alongside Chain Signatures is the Multichain Gas Relayer, which removes the need to have the native gas token of another chain in order to transact. This is a big hurdle for users today, often requiring purchasing multiple tokens on exchanges and sending them to different accounts just to complete a single cross-chain action. Now, with the Multichain Gas Relayer, users can just use NEAR or NEP-141 tokens to cover gas on any chain, not just NEAR or EVM chains. </p>



<p>This unlocks true multichain account abstraction. Whereas cross-chain bridges vary significantly depending on which assets are bridging to which chains, chain signatures makes transacting on smart contract and non-smart contract chains possible from a single account or interface, while simultaneously unlocking liquidity that wouldn’t have been accessible before. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1318" height="846" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-21298" style="width:623px;height:auto" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-1.png 1318w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-1-300x193.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-1-1024x657.png 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/image-1-768x493.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1318px) 100vw, 1318px" /></figure>



<p>For a longer technical deep dive on Chain Signatures and the Multichain Gas Relayer, see this <a href="/blog/unlocking-web3-usability-with-account-aggregation/">post from February 2024</a> about NEAR account aggregation technologies.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>New Web3 Design Patterns with Chain Signatures</strong></p>



<p>Chain Signatures unlocks a range of powerful new use cases for application builders and DeFi developers while also enabling much simpler user interfaces across different contexts. Smart contracts on NEAR will be able to custody assets on any chain (since they can sign transactions on any chain via chain signatures), and maintain user balances similar to how single chain lending protocols or DEXs do now. For example, a user will be able to atomically swap their BTC in a Bitcoin account for another user’s ETH in an Ethereum account. This works because they can first deposit into accounts on these respective chains that are fully controlled by a NEAR smart contract, which will then settle the trade and allow the user’s to withdraw their “new” assets post-trade.</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>DeFi on non-smart contract chains: </strong>NEAR smart contracts can sign transactions for non-smart contract chains like Bitcoin, Celestia, Bittensor, XRP Ledger, and others. This enables DEXs, lending protocols, and other DeFi apps to be built using the native assets of these chains, unlocking previously inaccessible liquidity.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li><strong>Bridgeless cross-chain DeFi: </strong>Since NEAR smart contracts can custody assets on any chain, users can build truly cross chain applications such as RFQs, orderbooks, AMMs, lending protocols, and more. It is also possible to build swaps and other apps without bridges and message passing layers, meaning that new chains and assets can be added at launch. Additionally, chain signatures can be used to build two-way bridges to non-smart contract chains, using NEAR as the intermediate chain.<br></li>



<li><strong>Multichain Account Abstraction: </strong>A single NEAR account can manage any number of accounts on any number of chains. This means users can get ERC 4337-like functionality (natively supported by NEAR) without deploying any new smart contracts (so they can use non-EVM and non-smart contract chains), or needing to update their accounts on each individual chain. Chain Signatures also enables users to pay for gas costs on various chains with USDC, including non-EVM chains.<br></li>



<li><strong>Instantly multichain apps at launch:</strong> Thanks to Chain Signatures and the Multichain Gas Relayer, app developers don’t need to commit to a single chain when they start building––now, they can make many chains accessible to their users immediately after launching and dramatically increase their addressable market of users.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Advancing the Chain Abstraction Vision</strong></p>



<p>Chain Signatures advances the NEAR ecosystem’s <a href="https://near.org/blog/why-chain-abstraction-is-the-next-frontier-for-web3">vision of Chain Abstraction</a>, or the idea that Web3 hurdles should be abstracted away from user interfaces for the sake of simplicity and accessibility. Many of these hurdles arise with multichain use cases as users need to deal with long lists of accounts on different chains, manually move assets between them, and manage all the related security. Now, with Chain Signatures, users can simply create and secure one account and then start transacting on any network in Web3. Chain Signatures also help dapp developers deliver better multichain experiences to their users and get access to all available liquidity across blockchains.</p>



<p>As Illia noted, &#8220;Since day one, the NEAR ecosystem has focused on simplifying access to Web3 for developers and mainstream users. Chain Signatures is the next step in that journey, making it significantly easier to transact on any blockchain while also defragmenting liquidity across the ecosystem. This will enable the next generation of truly decentralized apps to deliver much more powerful experiences and address the entire market of Web3 users.&#8221;   </p>



<p><strong>Live Use Cases In the Ecosystem</strong></p>



<p>Several projects in the NEAR ecosystem are already building with Chain Signatures to introduce new design patterns and experiences to users. More information on the node provider ecosystem as well as news about additional projects building with Chain Signatures across Web3 is coming in the next few weeks.</p>



<ul>
<li>SWEAT Economy, a <a href="https://dappradar.com/rankings">top ten</a> most used decentralized app (dApp), utilizes Multichain Gas Relayer to let users send transactions from NEAR to BNB chain and pay for the gas in SWEAT tokens earned in-app.</li>



<li>East Blue, a Bitcoin Layer 2, <a href="https://youtu.be/YpcCRglr6vc">uses NEAR Chain Signatures</a> to develop Bitcoin DeFi use cases that were not possible until now, providing a new way to extend Bitcoin with smart contract logic.&nbsp;</li>



<li><a href="https://linearprotocol.org/">LiNEAR</a> is building a multichain, multi-asset restaking framework on top of Eigenlayer, enabling non-ETH assets including NEAR to be restaked and used for securing applications.</li>



<li>Mintbase, an NFT infrastructure platform, enables NEAR-based Mintbase wallet holders to purchase <a href="https://x.com/mintbase/status/1769748329619992792?s=20">Ethereum NFTs directly</a>.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Start Building with Chain Signatures</strong></p>



<p>Chain Signatures makes possible a range of new use cases for Web3 developers and users alike, opening up an exciting new design space and expanding the landscape of multichain apps and experiences utilizing Chain Abstraction. </p>



<p>Builders and developers interested in getting started with Chain Signatures can visit the <a href="https://bit.ly/what-are-chain-signatures">documentation</a> or <a href="https://bit.ly/create-a-chain-signature">explore code examples</a> and begin building today. Projects looking for support implementing Chain Signatures can register their interest <a href="https://form.jotform.com/240777569453167">here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/chain-signatures-launch-to-enable-transactions-on-any-blockchain-from-a-near-account/">Chain Signatures Launch to Enable Transactions on Any Blockchain from a NEAR Account</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21295</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NEAR at NVIDIA GTC 2024: A Recap of Illia’s Appearance</title>
		<link>/blog/nvidia-gtc-2024/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 21:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21290</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At NVIDIA GTC 2024––the flagship conference of the AI hardware supercompany in San Jose, California––the spotlight was on the intersection …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nvidia-gtc-2024/">NEAR at NVIDIA GTC 2024: A Recap of Illia’s Appearance</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>At NVIDIA GTC 2024––the flagship conference of the AI hardware supercompany in San Jose, California––the spotlight was on the intersection of AI, blockchain, and the next era of open web innovation. Among the distinguished speakers was Illia Polosukhin, co-founder of NEAR Protocol, who contributed his insights into how AI models will evolve and how blockchain and token economies can play key roles. Polosukhin is the only blockchain industry founder to speak at the NVIDIA event.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The “Transforming AI” panel was hosted by Jensen Huang, CEO and co-founder of NVIDIA. Appearing on the panel were all but one of&nbsp; the co-authors of the landmark 2017 research paper “Attention is All You Need,” which introduced the Transformer architecture that revolutionized natural language processing. That lineup of coauthors has gone on to work on projects such as OpenAI, Inceptive, and Essential AI.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The group’s conversation explored the practical applications of blockchain technology, with Illia touching on programmable money and its impact on both the current and future states of digital economies. By addressing the challenges and opportunities presented by the convergence of AI and blockchain, Illia offered a grounded perspective on the potential for these technologies to facilitate a more decentralized and efficient open web.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Illia’s&nbsp; insights also highlighted NEAR&#8217;s commitment to leveraging Web3 technologies&nbsp; for broader adoption and innovation across a range of future tech use cases. Jensen himself noted that he thinks “NEAR is very cool.”&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-from-accelerated-computing-to-ai-and-the-blockchain">From Accelerated Computing to AI and the Blockchain</h2>



<p>Jensen kicked off the panel by providing context around the evolution of computing power and the potential of generative AI as the next industrial revolution. After a round of introductions, Illia dove into the beginnings of his research at Google and the unique challenges that brought AI to the forefront during that time.</p>



<p>&#8220;The team and I were working on simple question answering. You’d go to Google, you ask a question, and it should give you an answer,” Illia recounted. “But Google has very low latency requirements, so if you want to ship actual models that read search results, like tons of documents, you need something that can process that quickly. And models at the time just couldn’t do that.&#8221;</p>



<p>After publishing the paper and leaving Google to explore new opportunities, Illia first worked on NEAR as an AI startup, then pivoted when he and co-founder Alex Skidanov recognized an opportunity in the blockchain space they first encountered as users. They recognized a clear need in the space back in 2018: to make blockchain technology accessible and intuitive for everyday use. Illia discussed with the panel how that realization led him to the concept of programmable money, and subsequently built NEAR Protocol to address blockchain scalability and usability challenges, creating a shift towards a more user-friendly open web economy.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-genesis-of-near-and-programmable-money">The Genesis of NEAR and Programmable Money&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Illia further discussed how his shift from pure AI research to Web3 was driven by the concept of programmable money, not just for cross-border payments but for a range of powerful use cases. This was a direct response to the challenges of coordinating on complex networks and the increasing demand for scalable blockchain solutions. The result is a platform that can handle large transaction volumes without compromising speed or security.</p>



<p>“NEAR has the most users in the world in the blockchain space,” Illia explained. “We’re talking about multiple millions of daily users who don’t even know they’re using blockchain. But they’re actually interfacing with programmable money and programmable value. And now we’re bringing back some of those AI tools to generate more data.”</p>



<p>He then highlighted the need for a shift in how creators are rewarded in an emerging age of generative AI, suggesting that the century-old copyright system must evolve. With artists and creators now leveraging tools like Midjourney and OpenAI for everything from visual art to storytelling, the panel agreed that copyright laws will need an overhaul sooner than later.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-integrating-ai-for-fairer-user-and-creator-economies">Integrating AI for Fairer User and Creator Economies</h2>



<p>With the generative age already underway, Illia further unpacked how NEAR will be central to this new AI-enabled creator economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The way we’re rewarding creators right now is broken,” Illia continued. “And the only way to fix that is to leverage programmable money, programmable value, and blockchain. You need the basic primitive of programmable money because it’s what allows users and groups to coordinate people at scale.”</p>



<p>Illia&#8217;s vision extends to building a version of the open web where programmable value underpins a positive feedback loop, fostering a novel economy enriched by equitable participation. For example, he noted that NEAR is exploring ways for users to contribute their own data, which can help improve AI models. These initiatives demonstrate how tomorrow’s AI economy could benefit both creators and users by allowing more participation and collaboration underpinned by Web3 infrastructure and incentives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“I strongly believe that the way we&#8217;re going to make progress towards software eating the world to machine learning is eating software,” Illia argued. “And the most direct way is to teach machines to code, so you&#8217;re able to actually generate software and transform everyone&#8217;s access.”</p>



<p>Throughout his appearance at NVIDIA GTC 2024, Illia underscored NEAR’s pivotal role in bridging the gap between the open web, programmable money, and AI. By advocating for a reimagined copyright framework and more equitable creator compensation models, Illia presented an accessible and compelling vision for NEAR at the forefront of tomorrow’s user and creator centric AI economy. While this was just a brief glimpse of the emerging AI+Web3 ecosystem on NEAR, it was met with a wave of excitement from the NEAR community and served as a reminder for the whole Web3 space about Illia’s and NEAR’s early roots in the world of AI.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/nvidia-gtc-2024/">NEAR at NVIDIA GTC 2024: A Recap of Illia’s Appearance</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21290</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Graph Expands Subgraph Support to NEAR and 40+ Blockchains</title>
		<link>/blog/the-graph-expands-subgraph-support-to-near-and-40-blockchains/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 17:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21275</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Graph Foundation recently announced the inclusion of NEAR into its expansive subgraph support, now encompassing over 40 leading L1 …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/the-graph-expands-subgraph-support-to-near-and-40-blockchains/">The Graph Expands Subgraph Support to NEAR and 40+ Blockchains</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Graph Foundation recently announced the inclusion of NEAR into its expansive subgraph support, now encompassing over 40 leading L1 and L2 blockchains including Arbitrum, Base, Fantom, Celo, Optimism, Polygon Labs, and Scroll. By integrating with The Graph, NEAR developers gain access to a decentralized network for streamlined data querying, significantly reducing costs and improving synchronization speeds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The partnership highlights the NEAR Foundation&#8217;s ongoing commitment to enhancing developer resources and interoperability within open web ecosystems as part of advancing the Chain Abstraction vision. In 2021, NEAR became The Graph&#8217;s <a href="https://thegraph.com/blog/graph-near/">first non-EVM chain integration</a> for its hosted service, kickstarting the evolution towards a multichain open web ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Subgraph support will take things a step further, facilitating better multichain data accessibility for NEAR builders and increasing the reach and breadth of tools and technologies to support Chain Abstraction. This moment also marks NEAR as the first non-EVM chain to become available on The Graph Network.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-how-subgraph-support-empowers-near-developers">How Subgraph Support Empowers NEAR Developers</h2>



<p>Subgraphs on The Graph are transformative open APIs that efficiently organize and serve blockchain data, accelerating the development of decentralized applications (dApps) on the NEAR Protocol. This integration offers developers further support in efficient data querying, swift access to indexed blockchain data, and seamless interoperability across multiple chains.</p>



<p>By streamlining data retrieval, The Graph&#8217;s subgraph support eliminates the need for exhaustive blockchain scans, allowing for quick navigation, filtering, and location of specific data points. This advancement equips NEAR developers with tools similar to Web 2.0 search engine capabilities, tailored for the precision and complexity of blockchain data.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-graph-s-multichain-support-and-expansion-goals">The Graph&#8217;s Multichain Support and Expansion Goals&nbsp;</h2>



<p>The Graph&#8217;s integration with NEAR and over 40 additional blockchains is a step towards more rich multichain development. By extending beyond Ethereum, The Graph is facilitating a unified, accessible ecosystem for designing advanced, user-focused decentralized applications (dApps) across a diverse range of blockchains.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Enhancing interoperability among different blockchain networks also grants developers access to a broader spectrum of data, supporting the creation of dApps that are both feature-dense and user-friendly. These improvements also promote more unrestricted data exchange across chains for the purposes of dApp development.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-protocol-and-future-of-the-graph-network">NEAR Protocol and Future of The Graph Network</h2>



<p>Looking forward, The Graph Network is aiming to break the barriers of decentralized access to blockchain data, as it plans to introduce new data services to meet the growing needs of Web3. The Graph’s core devs are planning ahead on executing the “<a href="https://thegraph.com/blog/unveiling-updated-sunrise-decentralized-data/">Sunrise of decentralized data</a>” initiative, designed to improve tooling and developer experience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Soon, NEAR devs building on The Graph Network will be able to take advantage of a free query plan, an intuitive subgraph upgrade wizard, and more. The Graph-NEAR Foundation collaboration will further emphasize the shared mission of both teams for a more interconnected and inclusive Web3 ecosystem via Chain Abstraction, enhancing the value of indexing and querying blockchain data.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/the-graph-expands-subgraph-support-to-near-and-40-blockchains/">The Graph Expands Subgraph Support to NEAR and 40+ Blockchains</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21275</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FRAX Deploys Decentralized Stablecoin Infrastructure on NEAR Protocol</title>
		<link>/blog/frax-deploys-decentralized-stablecoin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Frax Finance announced the launch of FRAX stablecoin on NEAR via Ref Finance and Burrow through FraxFerry and the Rainbow …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/frax-deploys-decentralized-stablecoin/">FRAX Deploys Decentralized Stablecoin Infrastructure on NEAR Protocol</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Frax Finance announced the launch of FRAX stablecoin on NEAR via Ref Finance and Burrow through FraxFerry and the Rainbow Bridge. This marks a significant milestone for Frax as its first major venture into a non-Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM) ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Frax Finance is the second-largest issuer of decentralized dollar-pegged stablecoins and an industry leader for DeFi infrastructure.</p>



<p>The NEAR ecosystem and Frax contributors will now collaborate through ongoing in-depth research and protocol integrations. One of the biggest opportunities between the two teams will be the introduction of short-term treasury yields on NEAR using sFRAX, a yield-bearing asset that tracks the Federal Reserve&#8217;s Interest on Reserve Balance (IORB).</p>



<p>In the coming months, Frax will natively issue their suite of assets, FRAX, sFRAX, frxETH, and sfrxETH on NEAR and Fraxtal, along with exploring opportunities around NEAR LSTs. Other protocols on NEAR will also be able to explore these exciting frontiers with Frax. While NEAR supports various stablecoins, the decentralized Frax platform sets itself apart by offering additional features like yield and LSTs. These offerings can be utilized by NEAR&#8217;s DeFi protocols for novel ventures.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This deployment is led by Ref and Burrow and will soon expand to other protocols. <a href="https://www.ref.finance/">Ref Finance</a> is a decentralized finance (DeFi) platform built on NEAR Protocol, designed to facilitate the swapping, lending, and borrowing of digital assets. It is a multi-purpose DeFi platform that integrates various financial mechanisms, offering users a comprehensive suite of DeFi tools. <a href="https://burrow.finance/">Burrow</a> is a decentralized finance (DeFi) platform on the NEAR blockchain, offering non-custodial, pool-based lending and borrowing services.</p>



<p class="has-medium-font-size"><strong>Highlighting the Incentive Campaign</strong></p>



<p>To boost activity and foster growth of Frax on NEAR, Ref will introduce an incentive program offering rewards for Liquidity Providers (LPs) in the USDC/FRAX and NEAR/FRAX pools, as well as the Curve style stableswap pools.</p>



<p>The proliferation of native stablecoins is crucial to the growth of DeFi as it facilitates effortless access to liquidity between protocols for users across various types of exchanges. This allows for more seamless interactions with different projects across the Web3 ecosystem, effectively removing bottlenecks and promoting a smooth trading experience. This also advances the NEAR ecosystem vision of Chain Abstraction, streamlining usability and defragmenting liquidity and UX across all of Web3. Moreover, native stablecoins will significantly enhance the visibility of the NEAR Ecosystem&#8217;s Total Value Locked (TVL) within the market.</p>



<p>On Burrow, borrowers and lenders will earn incentives for using USDC, USDT, and FRAX. Additionally, Burrow will offer rewards for NEAR and liquid staked NEAR, with more details to be announced soon.</p>



<p>This incentive campaign will be expanded&nbsp; to other qualifying DeFi protocols and primitives after the initial rollout on Ref and Burrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you’re new to NEAR, you can find free resources for building apps, deploying smart contracts,creating blockchain operating system(BOS) components, and more on the <a href="https://docs.near.org/#">DevRel resources page.&nbsp;</a>Checkout the official documentation of <a href="https://docs.frax.finance/">Frax</a> to learn more about protocol and other technical specifications.&nbsp;</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/frax-deploys-decentralized-stablecoin/">FRAX Deploys Decentralized Stablecoin Infrastructure on NEAR Protocol</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21270</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unlocking Web3 Usability with Account Aggregation</title>
		<link>/blog/unlocking-web3-usability-with-account-aggregation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Illia Polosukhin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 14:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Account Aggregation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21229</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Since the start, the focus for the NEAR ecosystem has been on advancing Chain Abstraction, or hiding the elements of …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/unlocking-web3-usability-with-account-aggregation/">Unlocking Web3 Usability with Account Aggregation</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Since the start, the focus for the NEAR ecosystem has been on advancing <a href="/blog/why-chain-abstraction-is-the-next-frontier-for-web3/">Chain Abstraction</a>, or hiding the elements of the blockchain (“abstracting away”) from users so they are not barriers to entry or participation in the decentralized Web. In Web3, the data and assets belong to the user, tied to their on-chain, noncustodial account. Currently every user has separate (usually many) accounts on each blockchain and also needs separate wallet software to manage those accounts. This requires users to manage the security for each account and wallet individually, deal with complex recovery processes if they make a mistake, and go through a thorny series of manual steps to move any assets into their wallets or across different wallets and chains.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The current world, where every wallet is managing accounts on many chains, is untenable as each account slowly falls out of sync with the others. In order to provide a consistent, abstracted experience for users across all chains, we need to aggregate accounts across all chains within a single interface––account abstraction alone is not enough. Enter Account Aggregation.</p>



<p>Account Aggregation––the ability to transact on any blockchain through a single account and interface––is a critical pillar of advancing Chain Abstraction, defragmenting Web3 for app users and increasing their ability to move across networks or between applications with ease. Developers should not be building apps on single chains anymore in order to reach some specific market or pool of liquidity. Now dApps can truly become decentralized applications, yet still feel like the unified experience of using an app.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To enable an effective user experience for using all blockchains, without users needing to think about underlying infrastructure or switch networks, it’s important to have a single account from which they can navigate all of Web3. This means no manual bridging, no managing long lists of addresses on different networks, no gas tokens, and no more switching between wallets and networks. In the true spirit of Web3, this single account should be non-custodial and non-dependent on a specific wallet software or any other single service provider.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/_GsCWKS9_mqc-HYLf-kOPRH3R561qw7Y_a8y5jijWHHDzbktn3QYl2KLFd7HuCqWegaL9rpEHuPXVddEhXh4luFR7kwFcIU_OxaComsMZME0pbZcP3oKq7MZPDD-OjjezCaIGwG1wDSN0kEynQPLwg8" alt="" style="width:1050px;height:auto"/></figure>



<p>NEAR is enabling such an experience for all Web3 users with Account Aggregation, which consists of 3 core technologies.&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>NEAR Account</strong>: account abstraction for smooth onboarding and recovery of accounts.</li>



<li><strong>Chain Signatures</strong>: enabling NEAR network to have MPC nodes that are jointly signing transactions and messages.</li>



<li><strong>Intent Relayers</strong>: parties in the ecosystem that are able to execute the intent of the user on different chains.</li>
</ul>



<p>By adding Chain Signatures and Intent Relayers to the already robust NEAR account model, NEAR can become the home for multichain apps that abstract the pain points of switching networks and managing gas fees, bridging, and long lists of accounts away from end users.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This post details the 3 technical pillars of Account Aggregation and how they combine to deliver the next generation of usability for any decentralized application. Chain Signatures and Intent Relayers will be available on NEAR testnet by early March 2024.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-account">NEAR Account</h2>



<p>Account aggregation on NEAR begins with the innovative NEAR <a href="https://docs.near.org/concepts/basics/accounts/model">account model</a>. Incorporating native account abstraction since launch, NEAR’s account model offers a high degree of flexibility to developers and users alike. Ethereum introduced its version of account abstraction, EIP-4337, in March 2023.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Native account abstraction means that a given NEAR account maps to a human-readable account name instead of a public key hash, so accounts can have a large number of keys with different permissions for different functions. This means that NEAR account security is both stronger and easier to manage for users, while also allowing much broader functionality within a single account.<br></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="634" src="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Screenshot-2024-02-15-at-12.37.10 PM-1024x634.png" alt="" class="wp-image-21236" style="width:1102px;height:auto" srcset="https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Screenshot-2024-02-15-at-12.37.10 PM-1024x634.png 1024w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Screenshot-2024-02-15-at-12.37.10 PM-300x186.png 300w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Screenshot-2024-02-15-at-12.37.10 PM-768x475.png 768w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Screenshot-2024-02-15-at-12.37.10 PM-1536x951.png 1536w, https://pages.near.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/Screenshot-2024-02-15-at-12.37.10 PM-2048x1267.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><a href="https://docs.near.org/tools/fastauth-sdk">FastAuth</a>, the industry-leading account creation experience NEAR launched in 2023, offers a Web2-like onboarding flow: users can sign up with just an email, and they don’t need to save a seed phrase or password. Instead, their FastAuth account and keys are secured using “Passkeys,” a new technology that replaces passwords with biometrics such as fingerprints or FaceID linked to a device. Users can also recover access to their account at any time by using their email through the MPC recovery service.</p>



<p>Now, with added multichain functionality on the horizon, the power of the NEAR account can extend across all of Web3 and offer easier onboarding and security management to users of any decentralized application. By having passkey integration, revocation, and recovery in one place rather than scattered across every chain, users will have a significantly streamlined experience for managing their Web3 accounts.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-chain-signatures">Chain Signatures</h2>



<p>Chain signatures allow any NEAR account to have associated “remote” addresses on other chains and to sign transactions and messages from those addresses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Traditionally a user would have different private keys in different wallet providers to facilitate multichain interactions and would need to manage them manually. With Chain Signatures, the NEAR MPC network is the signer for these remote addresses, meaning there is no explicit private key.</p>



<p>MPC (multi-party computation) signing allows a number of independent nodes to sign a message with key shares separately generated by non-trusting parties without needing to assemble them anywhere. The challenge with the standard MPC signing approach is that if nodes are changed, a new public key needs to be generated. The introduction of a novel threshold signature protocol which has a procedure of key resharing allows the MPC signer to maintain the same aggregate public key even as key shares and nodes constantly change.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/rkoKA7u9NfTNCcGfc755qGg15lO539HM7CsFtf1Wg5HstDF_iTgVtg_9BlDx_Ta7BoJAsleLxdNzUwzeNKRBm4Z09DQlTMLW8FxuMoE3kd_wDvlh3qQTD1XkC3Tw4XDHidWDTJNqbo0KWyvXaI3iPNA" alt="" style="width:938px;height:auto"/></figure>



<p>Chain Signatures is the NEAR approach to make this model programmable. Making MPC signer nodes that are also nodes in the NEAR network allows for a smart contract call to instantiate a signature procedure for a given account. By using different derivations constructed from a chain ID, a NEAR account ID, and a provided path, each account receives an infinite number of remote addresses on every chain.&nbsp;<br></p>



<p>This amplifies the power and flexibility of NEAR accounts by allowing them to operate on any chain. Any NEAR smart contract can sign transactions and messages targeted for other chains––introducing another novel account programming primitive and extending the NEAR account model across all of Web3.</p>



<p>The MPC signer network will start as a subset of validators and partners of NEAR. Over time it is expected to be added to all NEAR validators on the protocol level to continue increasing the security of the system.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-intent-relayers">Intent Relayers</h2>



<p>We can’t expect app users to pay gas fees in various native tokens across different chains. We also should not require users to explicitly swap tokens on the destination chain in order to pay there. To achieve a smooth user experience, it should be easy for users to pay on the NEAR network and then be able to transact value on other chains, i.e. to relay their <em>intent</em> from NEAR to another chain.</p>



<p>With intent, a user can state what they want to achieve and leave out how it should be done. Users should be able to specify any action they want to take without having to navigate or understand the intricate complexities of multiple transactions on multiple chains they will be executed on, nor the swaps and funding required to achieve that action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Although Chain Signatures is a generic technology that can be used in many ways for the first iteration of Account Aggregation, the relayer smart contract will control the remote account for users. This means that instead of the user’s account mapping to an address, the <em>relayer.near</em> will have a derivation for each user, allowing this smart contract to initiate signing and offer other services (like trading derivations).</p>



<p>Let’s look at an example of how the first iteration of intent relayer will abstract away cross-chain gas and payments for a NEAR user:&nbsp;</p>



<ul>
<li>User has a root.near account that maps to the remote Ethereum address 0xabc via the relayer’s smart contract.</li>



<li>User initiates a transaction to buy a BAYC NFT on OpenSea using their NEAR account and pays in $NEAR by doing a transaction on the NEAR network to relayer smart contract with Ethereum transaction payload in arguments and attaching the required $NEAR amount.</li>



<li>The relayer smart contract will then forward the transaction bundle to the NEAR MPC signature contract. This bundle consists of (1) the transaction to fund the user’s 0xabc with $ETH required for gas and NFT payment and (2) user’s transaction to buy the BAYC NFT on OpenSea.</li>



<li>The Chain Signature contract will sign both transactions using different derivations respective to the relayer contract and originating user.</li>



<li>The relayer operator will observe the response from MPC service with signed transactions and submit them to the Ethereum network. This starts with initiating a fund transfer from a treasury paymaster account on Ethereum. This paymaster account will transfer ETH to the user’s 0xabc Ethereum address, equivalent to the NEAR that was originally sent by the user.&nbsp;</li>



<li>Then the relayer will submit the final transaction and the BAYC NFT will be purchased from the user&#8217;s 0xabc address using ETH to cover gas and payment.</li>
</ul>



<p>The above example showcases how an intent relayer reduces complexity for a user to complete a cross-chain transaction. This is an <em>intent</em>-based architecture, and this is only a brief initial example of what will be possible in the future to provide a seamless user experience and abstract blockchains for users.</p>



<p>The intent relayers approach allows users to pay with any assets they own, not just $NEAR, opening up wallet and application developers to offer a variety of options: using application tokens for paying for multichain transactions, offering a subscription model by charging a flat fee, or offering extra discounts to incentivize specific behaviors.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-use-cases">Use Cases</h2>



<p>One account for using apps on all chains unlocks a range of previously difficult use cases for founders and developers. Here are some examples for founders and developers to consider as the possibilities for excellent multichain user experiences expand with Account Aggregation.</p>



<p><strong>Expanding user base for existing applications.</strong> Currently applications are only targeting the user base of the single chain they have launched on. With Account Aggregation, users can log into applications from every chain as an alternative wallet option. Application developers will simply need to add “Connect with NEAR” to their wallet selector.</p>



<p>Wallet developers can also leverage NEAR’s decentralized and composable interfaces together with Account Aggregation to surface applications across all chains directly within their wallet experience.</p>



<p><strong>Bridgeless DeFi</strong>. The first example is bridgeless, cross-chain DeFi where a NEAR account can be a gateway to multiple chains through a unified app experience. This is especially useful for apps like <a href="https://dapdap.tech/">DapDap</a>, built on NEAR, which lets users discover DeFi apps and experiences from a range of L2s and start using them within a single interface.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Multichain DEX.</strong> One of the most desired but also complex-to-build use cases is a decentralized exchange (DEX) that works across most if not all chains. Currently users must default to centralized exchanges for such a multichain experience due to the complexity of bridging, gas, and handling separate wallets. With Account Aggregation, DEX smart contracts can live on NEAR while having deposit addresses across all chains. This means there is no need to bridge assets to a single chain to swap or for the user to bridge to the chain where assets have liquidity. Instead they can easily swap $BTC on the Bitcoin network for $OP on Optimism using such a NEAR smart contract.</p>



<p><strong>Bridging Assets.</strong> Although the Account Aggregation approach really focuses on using canonical assets on where they are issued, sometimes there is value in having wrapped assets. For example, in cases like Bitcoin or Ethereum where the canonical assets are too expensive and slow to move, wrapping becomes quite useful. To build a specific token bridge using Account Aggregation is just to make a NEAR smart contract that keeps an account of deposits of a given token and issues that respective token balance.</p>



<p><strong>Trading multichain asset bundles. </strong>Beyond simple trading, Account Aggregation allows users to make a NEAR account into a bundle of multichain assets. NEAR accounts themselves are tradeable (see <a href="https://namesky.app/">NEAR account marketplace NameSky</a>), which also allows the trading of everything that is deposited to such an account across all chains. For example, say the account <em>xyz.near</em> has 2 BTC, some BRC-20, a BAYC NFT on Ethereum, and some veCRV. By trading this entire account, there is no need to move each of the underlying assets on the other chains.&nbsp; Instead, the new owner comes into possession of the whole bundle when the keys are rotated to them on the account.<br></p>



<p>There is also an interesting potential approach to implement a multichain exchange of assets via a smart contract that internally maintains a mapping from an owner account to a given path derivation (which is what determines remote addresses on other chains). One can trade the derivation paths inside this smart contract, trading everything deposited on a remote account without trading the entire account. For example:</p>



<ul>
<li>Smart contract <em>dex.near </em>internally maintains:&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li>derivation=/0/0/1 → root.near</li>



<li>derivation=/0/0/2 → alice.near which maps to 0xabc on Ethereum</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li>alice.near can sell root.near the derivation inside this smart contract for some amount on NEAR and now it will be inside dex.near. Then root.near can request to draw Ethereum assets from it later.&nbsp;</li>
</ul>



<ul>
<li>derivation=/0/0/1 → root.near</li>



<li>derivation=/0/0/2 → root.near</li>
</ul>



<p>This approach means users can trade assets across all chains at the speed (1s block time) and cost (below $0.01) of using NEAR.</p>



<p><strong>Delegated Smart Contract Permissions on NEAR.</strong> Another use case for Chain Signatures is the ability for a NEAR smart contract to execute something on behalf of other users––for example, to recover keys for an app user.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s say there is a <em>social_recovery.near</em> contract that keeps track of a mapping of friends for a given account root.near. This root.near account at some point added a public key that the social_recovery.near account can sign via Chain Signatures. Friends can initiate a recovery flow, where they send a new public key given to them by the user to social_recovery.near. If enough friends do this, the social_recovery.near requests to sign a NEAR transaction that adds a new key on behalf of its own remote key with signer root.near. When executed, this transaction adds a new key to root.near, allowing the user to recover their account via a social recovery process they can set up in case they need it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Similarly, smart contracts can execute rebalancing of pools on behalf of the user based on some condition and any other logic that the user decides to “install” on their account by adding a remote key from that account.</p>



<p><strong>DeFi on Bitcoin (and other non-smart contract chains). </strong>Using chain signatures, smart contracts on NEAR can control externally-owned accounts on non-smart contract chains like Bitcoin, Dogecoin, Ripple, Bittensor, Cosmos Hub, etc. This enables developers to use NEAR as a smart contract “layer” for chains that do not support this functionality natively.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, a developer can build a decentralized exchange for Bitcoin Ordinals, using a smart contract on NEAR to manage deposits (into Bitcoin addresses controlled by the contract) and to verify and execute swaps when two users agree to trade BTC for an Ordinal or BRC20 token.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-coming-soon-to-near-testnet">Coming Soon to NEAR Testnet</h3>



<p>Excited to build with Account Aggregation? Keep an eye on NEAR’s <a href="https://docs.near.org/">docs</a>: Chain Signatures and Intent Relayers are expected to be available on testnet by March 1, 2024. And join members of the NEAR ecosystem at the <a href="https://lu.ma/ChADay">Chain Abstraction Summit</a>, co-sponsored by NEAR Foundation during ETHDenver, to learn more about Account Aggregation and exciting innovations from all the projects contributing to Chain Abstraction.</p>



<p><em>–Illia Polosukhin, David Millar-Durrant, Gautham Ravi, Dio Ortega, Mally Anderson</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/unlocking-web3-usability-with-account-aggregation/">Unlocking Web3 Usability with Account Aggregation</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21229</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Inaugural AI x Web3 Hackathon and Decentralized AI Summit to Debut at ETH Denver 2024</title>
		<link>/blog/inaugural-ai-x-web3-hackathon-and-decentralized-ai-summit-to-debut-at-eth-denver-2024/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 18:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI is NEAR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hackathon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partnerships]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21226</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In collaboration with Edge and Polygon Labs, the NEAR Foundation will co-sponsor a Decentralized AI Summit and “Autonomous Agent,” an …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/inaugural-ai-x-web3-hackathon-and-decentralized-ai-summit-to-debut-at-eth-denver-2024/">Inaugural AI x Web3 Hackathon and Decentralized AI Summit to Debut at ETH Denver 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In collaboration with Edge and Polygon Labs, the NEAR Foundation will co-sponsor a Decentralized AI <a href="https://lu.ma/fvoeazk8">Summit</a> and “Autonomous Agent,” an AI x Web3 <a href="https://edgeintelligence.xyz/autonomous-agent-hackathon">Hackathon</a>, at ETHDenver on February 26 and 27. The events will bring together visionaries, developers, and enthusiasts working at the intersection of AI and Web3 along with a hackathon for builders and researchers to dive into the buzziest tech topic of today. Speakers at the Summit will include Vitalik Buterin of the Ethereum Foundation, Illia Polosukhin of NEAR Foundation, Sandeep Nailwal of Polygon Labs, and Sreeram Kannan of EigenLayer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Autonomous Agent” is the first event in the &#8220;{Chain}-of-Thought&#8221; series from <a href="https://edgeintelligence.xyz/">Edge</a>, which will explore and harness the potential of Web3 and open source AI. Edge is a research and development organization dedicated to democratizing access to open intelligence and advancing the evolution of next-generation web architecture. Hackers can expect hands-on hacking sessions, workshops, and mentorship opportunities with a chance to learn from those at the cutting edge of decentralized AI development. </p>



<p>The intersection of Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Web3 technology is poised to revolutionize industries, with many Web3 projects now incorporating AI into decentralized applications and developer tools. Ethereum Co-Founder Vitalik Buterin recently shared his <a href="https://vitalik.eth.limo/general/2024/01/30/cryptoai.html">observations</a> about the intersection, and NEAR Co-Founder Illia Polosukhin shared how AI fits into the vision for the NEAR ecosystem in a recent <a href="/blog/self-sovereignty-is-near-a-vision-for-our-ecosystem/">post</a>. </p>



<p>As the risks from centralized AI controlled primarily by major corporations become more apparent, investing in open source, transparent AI development will become increasingly important––along with community building, governance experiments, and advocacy. “{Chain} of Thought” will lead the way in bringing members of the AI and Web3 ecosystems together to advance these initiatives and make concrete progress.</p>



<p>In addition to the premier sponsors, the “Autonomous Agent” hackathon is co-sponsored by <a href="https://www.eigenlayer.xyz/">EigenLayer</a>, <a href="https://www.gensyn.ai/">Gensyn</a>, and <a href="https://www.hyperoracle.io/">Hyper Oracle</a>, with co-hosting participation from Sentient, Lightspeed, and Symbolic Capital. Benefits of participation include:</p>



<ul>
<li><strong>Cutting-Edge Workshops:</strong> Engage with industry experts and thought leaders through immersive workshops exploring the latest trends and technologies in AI x Web3.</li>



<li><strong>Hackathon Challenges:</strong> Tackle real-world challenges and showcase your creativity by developing innovative solutions at the forefront of AI and Web3 integration.</li>



<li><strong>Networking Opportunities:</strong> Connect with like-minded individuals, potential collaborators, and industry professionals to expand your network and exchange ideas.</li>



<li><strong>Prizes and Recognition:</strong> Compete for exciting prizes and gain recognition for your contributions to the advancement of AI x Web3 technology.</li>
</ul>



<p>Join NEAR Foundation, Polygon Labs, and Edge in Denver and be a part of the next great tech revolution. Those interested in attending the Decentralized AI Summit can register <a href="https://lu.ma/fvoeazk8">here</a>. Researchers, developers, and hackers interested in participating in the <a href="https://edgeintelligence.xyz/autonomous-agent-hackathon">hackathon</a> can apply <a href="https://lu.ma/k6dw9jk2">here</a>.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/inaugural-ai-x-web3-hackathon-and-decentralized-ai-summit-to-debut-at-eth-denver-2024/">Inaugural AI x Web3 Hackathon and Decentralized AI Summit to Debut at ETH Denver 2024</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21226</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why NEAR Data Availability?</title>
		<link>/blog/why-near-data-availability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[NEAR Team]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 16:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Developers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chain Abstraction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethereum Rollups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Modularity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NEAR Data Availability Layer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=21194</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>NEAR Protocol is built to onboard 1B+ users to Web3. Since its mainnet launch in October 2020, NEAR Protocol has …</p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/why-near-data-availability/">Why NEAR Data Availability?</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>NEAR Protocol is built to onboard 1B+ users to Web3. Since its mainnet launch in October 2020, NEAR Protocol has achieved 100% uptime with 4 shards and has onboarded 35M accounts, of which 16M are monthly active accounts.</p>



<p>Supporting the most users of any network in Web3 requires a scalable blockchain that is capable of having both high data availability and low-cost data posting in order for applications to scale to the level of mainstream global adoption. This post will explain NEAR’s technical approach to data availability and how <a href="http://near.org/da">NEAR DA</a>, a solution designed for Ethereum rollups, will scale the modular ecosystem and defragment all of Web3.</p>



<p>The modular Ethereum ecosystem seeks to scale the network by separating the functions of a blockchain––settlement, execution, and data availability––into separate layers. The Ethereum layer-one simply could not scale to accommodate the level of demand it reached, particularly during bull markets, without prohibitively high transaction fees. This demand becomes even more problematic when users want to do swaps on Ethereum or post transaction data for layer-twos to the layer-one network.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NEAR DA offers a solution to this scalability roadblock. With a simple architecture that is easy to implement and constantly improving efficiency, and thanks to NEAR having the cheapest transaction fees of any network in Web3, NEAR DA is an incredibly fast and cost-effective data availability option. Depending on the gas fees, NEAR DA is up to 85,000x cheaper than posting blob submissions on Ethereum and 30x cheaper than doing the same on Celestia.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-eu.googleusercontent.com/Vw1qZ6OUS85XzYhXKYqIS3uHxSQ14GrzJDd4kh8eJRjFuggXqaYKAx_zWxgLsGWEMEEqUb6WjXu6lmQe0Hhkgm49HRz-OnQi_aMSZkxvAUuJ6XM4534EQ7x5bR1c8rAeaMjx14bnBC1Sv47T1LyngJw" alt=""/></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-near-da-and-the-chain-abstraction-vision">NEAR DA and the Chain Abstraction Vision</h3>



<p>The NEAR ecosystem’s focus for 2024 is expanding <a href="/blog/why-chain-abstraction-is-the-next-frontier-for-web3">chain abstraction</a> across more chains &amp; ecosystems, with the goal of abstracting the blockchain away from the user &amp; developer experience. While the modular Ethereum ecosystem has made Ethereum more scalable in some ways, it’s also resulted in a lot of incompatible infrastructure and fractured liquidity that places a huge burden on app builders and end users to manage. The chain abstraction vision is that apps should just work with all chains, onboarding should be seamless, and things like gas fees and bridging should become invisible to end users.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Data availability and NEAR DA play an important role in chain abstraction. As zero-knowledge technology enables unification of security across chains via state proofs, as described in the chain abstraction deep dive post linked above, settlement data will be easier to fetch from different networks. As dapps become truly multichain thanks to account aggregation and decentralized frontends, they can query data from multiple chains more easily when data is all posted in one place. Doing so on NEAR will be much cheaper for rollups.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-how-is-near-da-implemented">How is NEAR DA Implemented?</h3>



<p>NEAR DA leverages an important part of NEAR’s consensus mechanism, known as Nightshade, which parallelizes the network into multiple shards (essentially, multiple parallel blockchains). Each shard on NEAR produces a small portion of a block, which is called a chunk. These chunks are aggregated to produce blocks. All of this happens entirely at the protocol level and so is invisible to users and developers.</p>



<p>NEAR DA uses this infrastructure to an ETH rollup’s benefit. When a chunk producer processes a receipt, there is consensus around the receipt. However, once the chunk has been processed and included in the block, the receipt is no longer required for consensus and can be pruned from the blockchain’s state. The pruning time is at least 3 NEAR epochs, where each epoch is 12 hours. In practice, this is usually around 5 NEAR epochs, so data is available in the network for around 60 hours. Once the receipt is pruned, it is the responsibility of archival nodes to retain the transaction data.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This means that NEAR doesn’t slow down its consensus with more data than it requires, yet any user of NEAR DA would have ample time to query transaction data. The advantage this architecture provides to rollups is cost-effective data availability, especially to those with high transaction volume, such as gaming chains.&nbsp;</p>



<p>NEAR DA provides an out-of-the-box solution for developers, making it easy for rollup builders to make the most of NEAR’s infrastructure––which has 3+ years of proven reliability behind it. The Pagoda engineering team has already built three important components that are open-source and ready to be integrated into any OP Stack, Polygon CDK, or Arbitrum Nitro rollups:</p>



<ul>
<li>The Blob Store Contract: A contract that stores arbitrary data.</li>



<li>Light Client: A trustless off-chain client that provides easy access to transaction and receipt data.</li>



<li>RPC Client: A client to publish data blobs to the NEAR Protocol.</li>
</ul>



<p>Rollup builders looking to work with a cloud-like service could also leverage NEAR DA’s rollup-as-a-service (RaaS) providers (list provided <a href="https://near.org/data-availability">here</a>), in order to utilize these three components all in one place in a more abstracted manner.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-s-next-the-future-of-near-da-and-data-availability-sharding">What’s next? The Future of NEAR DA and Data Availability Sharding</h3>



<p>Another advantage NEAR’s sharding approach offers to users of NEAR DA is the future scaling roadmap. The NEAR Protocol Engineering team recently announced the move towards stateless validation, the next phase of sharding. This will further decrease the hardware requirements of certain types of validators (chunk validators) and move the state into memory, which will allow for more shards and increase the decentralization in the system by lowering the requirements to become a validator in the system. </p>



<p>This means that the number of shards will increase, greatly increasing the overall throughput of the NEAR Protocol. While NEAR is already fast, with 4 MB/s per shard with 4 shards, scaling towards <em>n</em> shards means that rollups, applications, and any other project or developer using NEAR will not have to compete for blockspace. This is a major contrast to the scaling limits of both monolithic systems as well as the modular ETH ecosystem and offers a substantial future-proof for anyone building on NEAR, including users of NEAR DA.</p>



<p>As the NEAR Protocol starts increasing the number of shards to n, the amount of data that has to be stored for a single shard decreases. Eventually, in theory every account on NEAR Protocol could potentially become its own shard. This allows running very light RPC nodes that would only track the shard that a given user is interested in. </p>



<p>For L2s that use NEAR DA, this would mean running an in-memory RPC client that would only track the shard that your data blob contract is in for your retention period (for fraud proofs), or for a given interval of time (retention is configurable on the RPC nodes). Instead of relying on data availability sampling (DAS), a rollup can rely on its own shard by running a lightweight RPC through Data Availability with Sharding. The additional benefit here is that the RPC is also applying the chunks they are tracking, essentially acting as a validator without participating in the consensus, as opposed to statistical confidence with DAS. </p>



<p>While Data Availability Sharding remains in the research phase of development, it shows the major advantages the NEAR Protocol design offers to many kinds of builders and ecosystems. As the Web3 space pursues mainstream adoption, the scalability hurdles of the first ten years of Ethereum will seem minor, and it is not clear that modularity alone will solve the problem. The NEAR ecosystem’s goal of mainstream adoption of Web3 means the network is available for all builders to use for creating great applications and delivering the next generation of the internet.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-fast-cost-effective-da-is-near">Fast, Cost-Effective DA is NEAR</h3>



<p>As Web3 adoption grows and as the number of rollups continues to climb, the need to scale the modular scalability solutions becomes greater. NEAR offers its innovative, reliable technology as a data availability solution for rollups that can save time and money while future-proofing projects for an increasingly multichain (and cross-chain) future. The bleeding-edge research driving the future development of NEAR DA will provide rollups with even more advantages over time. Interconnecting and defragmenting Web3 via chain abstraction will be a major theme of 2024 and utilizing NEAR DA puts rollups at the forefront of this evolution.</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a href="/blog/why-near-data-availability/">Why NEAR Data Availability?</a> appeared first on <a href="/">NEAR Protocol</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">21194</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
